<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iran on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/iran/</link><description>Recent content in iran on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/iran/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Propaganda Blitz</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/propaganda-blitz/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/propaganda-blitz/</guid><description>For years I’ve wanted a successor to [[books/manufacturing consent|Manufacturing Consent]] that is a bit more current and accessible — this might not exactly fill those shoes, but it comes pretty damn close.
See the helpful excerpt here: [[notes/anatomy of a propaganda blitz|anatomy of a propaganda blitz]]</description></item><item><title>Dirty Wars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/dirty-wars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/dirty-wars/</guid><description>[Insert string of obscenities] at the things the United States has done. The best thing this book does is make it perfectly clear there isn’t right-wing or left-wing. It spans two crucial presidencies (Bush II and Obama), and the substantive difference is that the former worried how far they could push things and the latter did not care.</description></item><item><title>Manufacturing Consent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/manufacturing-consent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/manufacturing-consent/</guid><description>Infuriatingly and terrifyingly relevant. Like, up to this very day, where you couldn’t even update the book with current examples because there are too many to choose from. Venezuela, Syria, Iran. Ad infinitum. It’s all following the same script. Where you could argue the book is dated, that actually further proves its point, such as the west’s support and glorification of Putin thirty years ago when he fit their needs in a different way.</description></item><item><title>I’ll Have What He’s Having</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</guid><description>I’m glad the term tonic masculinity has been making the rounds, because this feels like tonic masculinity of the highest order. David Curtis, sommelier, mistakes Farzan Alavi for a food critic, and what blooms in the wake of this mixup is a tender, sexy, heartfelt romance between two grown adults who have to deal with the obstacles that a grown-ass relationship entails.</description></item></channel></rss>