<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>grief on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/grief/</link><description>Recent content in grief on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/grief/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When Things Fall Apart</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/when-things-fall-apart/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/when-things-fall-apart/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Forest of Noise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</guid><description>How do you write the unimaginable? How do you craft art from the horror? How do you count your loved ones, now dead, in lines of poems?
I read this twice, once fast, once slow, and let it break me. 50 years of occupation and apartheid.</description></item><item><title>The Spring Before Obergefell</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spring-before-obergefell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spring-before-obergefell/</guid><description>It’s strange how a book like this—small-town rural Ohio circa 2015—can feel like an artifact of the past and yet an ongoing present. Mike is middle-aged, gay, single, and lost, with no cultural script for how someone like him can find connection and happiness. He believes the best he can hope for is hookup apps and casual flings, until he meets the capricious Matteo and the enigmatic Dave, who each challenge him in different ways.</description></item><item><title>In Perpetuity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/in-perpetuity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/in-perpetuity/</guid><description>Melancholy little novella about vampires stuck out of time in our modern world, besieged by the violent noises and smells as civilization encroaches upon them. The author has written other autistic characters; it seems like he has first hand experience of the nerve-wracking world of sensory overload to render it so accurately.</description></item><item><title>You Made a Fool of Death with Your Beauty</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/you-made-a-fool-of-death-with-your-beauty/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/you-made-a-fool-of-death-with-your-beauty/</guid><description>Re-read. The widowed Feyi hooks up with a stranger, then dates his best friend Nasir, then falls in love with Nasir’s father, and none of that sentence captures the raw transcendence of this novel. It makes me not just cry, but weep, multiple times—not (only) because of the grief but because of the way it vibrates with life, with pain, with joy, with every raw emotion.</description></item><item><title>I’m Sorry for My Loss</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/im-sorry-for-my-loss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/im-sorry-for-my-loss/</guid><description>I know a book is going to be good when it starts off with the way language limits or distorts our understanding of a subject. Recommended to absolutely anyone, with or without a uterus, with or without the intention to procreate. It’s ostensibly about pregnancy loss and miscarriage/stillbirth awareness, but that overlaps with many things—abortion, grief, medical misogyny, racial injustice, human rights.</description></item></channel></rss>