<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>anachronistic on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/anachronistic/</link><description>Recent content in anachronistic on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/anachronistic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Something Fabulous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</guid><description>So far the theme of the year is romances that I read and then re-read right away and install on my best-of-year list (best-of-ever list too, in the case of Something Fabulous, which more than lives up to its name).
A few notes:
We’re starting to see the books written during the pandemic where authors are writing what they WANT, not what they SHOULD.</description></item><item><title>Something Spectacular</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</guid><description>You couldn’t write your own story in the margins of someone else’s.
I want to write something long and complex about the concept of family in this book (the Tarletons enfolding Valentine and Sir Horley and Periwinkle and practically every other stray into their own little world; the stitched-together warmth of the Delanceys’ parenting, wrapped around Peggy like a quilt; that spectacular ending of creating a new family when convention says it’s impossible).</description></item><item><title>Something Extraordinary</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</guid><description>The high-strung Belle has left behind her heroine era, and the drama-prone Rufus has left behind his Sir Horley Comewithers era. Together they embark on the worst elopement kidnapping elopement in history (per Belle, it’s not vainglorious to claim that when it’s true), and what ensues is a meditation on friendship, love, sexuality, identity, self-discovery, society, and home in a way that only Alexis Hall can do it.</description></item><item><title>Gwen &amp; Art Are Not in Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</guid><description>I think it wobbled a smiiiidge on the landing, a few things felt abrupt and/or undercooked, not to mention the jarring tonal shift into violence, but the ride to get there was super fun. There’s some fade-to-black, hand-wavey, don’t-think-too-hard-about-this energy re: the whole premature-inheritance, fix-a-broken-system-from-the-inside plan, but it is YA, and I wasn’t expecting an [[books/bitter|Akwaeke Emezi-level thesis]] on the subject of institutional power.</description></item><item><title>Hot Earl Summer</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hot-earl-summer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hot-earl-summer/</guid><description>A goofy, over-the-top farce with the volume dialed up to 11. Which seems absurd to complain about, given how I just read and loved [[books/something extraordinary|Something Extraordinary]]—surely if anything is dialed up to 11 it’s the Tarletons. But [[authors/alexis hall|Alexis Hall]] grounds his farce with deep emotion and intimacy, using it to scratch away at the actual farce of a society that dictates such rigid, preposterous roles.</description></item><item><title>Infamous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</guid><description>This ending was the EXACT ENDING I’ve wanted to see for SO LONG. (Unapologetic all caps.) It took us ages to get there (more on that in a sec) but once we did? CHEF’S KISS.
Spoilery: %%it’s an f/f romance, and one half of the pair is affianced, to an amazing man, who’s gay, and they are going to use their marriage to give themselves and their true partners a safe harbor from society, and they go through with their marriage, and it’s just beautifully done, and… sniff I have a lot of feelings about friendships and healthy communication and unconventional choices and that kind of love.</description></item><item><title>Reputation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</guid><description>Lex Croucher’s lols-per-page cannot be beat.
Weirdly, the only character I was meh on was the love interest, just because he’s too perfect. (My notes say “Col Brandon in a Henry Tilney body???”) I also would have been fine if this had swung more towards a coming-of-age instead of HEA romance, but I won’t hold that against it.</description></item><item><title>Trouble</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/trouble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/trouble/</guid><description>Perfection. I knew Lex Croucher could do it. Each standalone entry in this not-quite-series has been good, better, best. This one is THE BEST. In Emily, Croucher has written the prickly heroine of my dreams, who isn’t required to sand down any sharp edges for plot or relationship reasons.</description></item></channel></rss>