<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>race-politics on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/race-politics/</link><description>Recent content in race-politics on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/race-politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deviant Matter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/deviant-matter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/deviant-matter/</guid><description>It’s a bummer that I am so very interested in the premise of this, but the dense academic writing, chock full of jargon, makes it nearly inaccessible. It’s especially a bummer that for someone purporting to “queer the narrative,” it’s impenetrable to those without the author’s credentials.</description></item><item><title>Jane Austen, the Secret Radical</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jane-austen-the-secret-radical/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jane-austen-the-secret-radical/</guid><description>Superb and long-overdue reevaluation of Jane Austen and the context in which she wrote her beloved novels. For many people, I imagine “radical” is the word in the title that lifts eyebrows; for me, it’s the word “secret.” Austen’s politics have always felt clear on the page, and this is how I’ve read her, even lacking some of the well-researched context Helena Kelly provides here.</description></item><item><title>Abolish Rent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</guid><description>An enthusiastic and persuasive manifesto on housing rights as human rights. It’s encouraging to see such robust organizing among tenants across the country, and the practical template for how to expand it. The authors rightly quote [[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula Le Guin]]: our housing system is a human power—produced by people, not God or nature.</description></item><item><title>Mansfield Park</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mansfield-park/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mansfield-park/</guid><description>Mansfield Park in context Since this was a re-read after [[books/jane austen the secret radical|Jane Austen, The Secret Radical]], I’m going to put my relevant highlights from that book here.</description></item><item><title>Sister Outsider</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sister-outsider/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sister-outsider/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Yellowface</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</guid><description>After witnessing the accidental death of her frenemy Athena Liu, failed author June Hayward refashions herself as Juniper Song and steals Athena’s posthumous masterpiece to pass it off as her own. Cue white woman tears, as she’s victimized and vilified by the consequences of her own egregious actions.</description></item><item><title>Giovanni’s Room</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</guid><description>Not everyone in book club was a fan, but I loved it, but it was brutal, but I’m glad I read it, but I’m glad I won’t be in a rush to read it again.
“Somebody,” said Jacques, “your father or mine, should have told us that not many people have ever died of love.</description></item></channel></rss>