<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>censorship on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/censorship/</link><description>Recent content in censorship on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/censorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Censorship does not make the ideas we disagree with go away</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/censorship-does-not-make-the-ideas-we-disagree-with-go-away/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/censorship-does-not-make-the-ideas-we-disagree-with-go-away/</guid><description>It strikes me how much facing bad things we disagree with is like facing the “bad” emotions we refuse to acknowledge. What we can’t face doesn’t go away—it festers and comes out in much worse ways.
Curiosity is always the answer. Curiosity and addressing the root cause in a meaningful way.</description></item><item><title>Self-censorship is primarily state censorship</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-censorship-is-primarily-state-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-censorship-is-primarily-state-censorship/</guid><description>State censorship shapes and causes self-censorship, directly and intentionally. To act like it’s primarily a civilian phenomenon is to perpetuate the illusion and miss the point entirely.
Hence, my biggest conclusion, the majority of real censorship is self-censorship, but the majority of self-censorship is intentionally cultivated by an outside power trying to cause that self-censorship to occur.</description></item><item><title>Tools for thinking about censorship</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/</guid><description>[[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]] has an excellent essay in Reactor Mag (formerly Tor) about the psychological and manipulative tactics of preventing free speech, and thus tools for thinking about free speech: https://reactormag.com/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/
The whole thing is excellent and worth a read, but I wanted to copy down her five takeaways below:</description></item><item><title>We discount censorship when its motives are “good”</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-discount-censorship-when-its-motives-are-good/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-discount-censorship-when-its-motives-are-good/</guid><description>It doesn’t take much to persuade us that censorship is good, when it aligns with what we fear or who we want to protect from harm.
We tend instinctively to call things censorship primarily when we perceive those involved to have bad intentions. But we tend to excuse or discount censorious actions when we perceive the motives to be good.</description></item><item><title>Censorship is often plural, private, and popular</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/real-censorship-is-often-plural-private-and-popular/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/real-censorship-is-often-plural-private-and-popular/</guid><description>When we only have one template for what censorship looks like—state-driven, authoritarian, Orwellian—we fail to see the myriad kinds of censorship that don’t resemble it.
Alarm bells go off the instant people see censorship which resembles Orwell, which creates a corresponding weakness or failure to observe when censorship begins that does not resemble Orwell.</description></item></channel></rss>