<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fanfic-positive on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/fanfic-positive/</link><description>Recent content in fanfic-positive on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/fanfic-positive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Bang a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-bang-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-bang-a-billionaire/</guid><description>Ugh, billionaires! I love Arden as much as I ugh Caspian. Which I think is the point at this point. Fifty Shades of Gray fanfic at its finest.</description></item><item><title>Iron &amp; Velvet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</guid><description>I have now done each of these in print (well, ebook, as print is sadly out of print) and each of these in audio, and all other vampire books can check themselves at the door. All other PI noirs too, for that matter.
“Yes, I was a faery-blooded, thirty-something PI with trust issues and a drinking problem, and she was a bloodthirsty undead nun with a pudding fixation, but I honestly thought we were in with a chance.</description></item><item><title>Mortal Follies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Prosperity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/prosperity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/prosperity/</guid><description>Adore it truly, deeply.</description></item><item><title>Rosaline Palmer Takes the Cake</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rosaline-palmer-takes-the-cake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rosaline-palmer-takes-the-cake/</guid><description>I laughed. I cried. I have a therapist now. How many books can do that, AND homage the hell out of the Great British Bake Off?
Rosaline Palmer does take the cake.</description></item><item><title>10 Things That Never Happened</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</guid><description>It’s about grief and melancholy and connection and hope; it hit me so hard in the feels I cried through the last chapters. Outstanding use of the cheesy amnesia trope, a worthy homage to While You Were Sleeping. (Sam is absolutely the British Sandra Bullock.)</description></item><item><title>Inferno</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</guid><description>So good to read this while steeped in Florentine history. These are real people and real places, not just an abstract Lewis-esque allegory. Now I wish I knew Italian to read his terza rima original, especially since I’ve had to dig through the Longfellow to see what’s underneath.</description></item><item><title>Something Fabulous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</guid><description>So far the theme of the year is romances that I read and then re-read right away and install on my best-of-year list (best-of-ever list too, in the case of Something Fabulous, which more than lives up to its name).
A few notes:
We’re starting to see the books written during the pandemic where authors are writing what they WANT, not what they SHOULD.</description></item><item><title>Boyfriend Material</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/boyfriend-material/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/boyfriend-material/</guid><description>I’m doing a reading challenge for the local library and need “a book that became a movie” for bingo, and how I wish this book qualified because, if Hollywood knew what they were doing, it should be optioned and filmed before I finish this sentence.</description></item><item><title>A Lady’s Guide to Fortune-Hunting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-fortune-hunting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-fortune-hunting/</guid><description>I didn’t love this quite as much as [[books/a lady&amp;rsquo;s guide to scandal|book two]]. (Read them out of order, oops!) Lots of promise, but I think the difference in POV—floating omniscient instead of tight third—didn’t work quite as well for me, possibly because it’s such a high bar of difficulty, possibly because it’s much closer to Jane Austen’s voice, which means the differences in quality are glaring.</description></item><item><title>Gideon the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</guid><description>WOULD HAVE HARROWHARK’S BABIES.
I mean, it’s a good thing I like nice people in real life, because in fiction, Harrowhark is 10000% my type.
And just, 10/10 on working through your Catholic upbringing by writing meme-filled fic about blood sacrifice and redemption and necromancy and lesbian saints and cavaliers.</description></item><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>Confounding Oaths</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/confounding-oaths/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/confounding-oaths/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How to Blow It with a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-blow-it-with-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-blow-it-with-a-billionaire/</guid><description>It’s a testament to Hall’s writing that I’m still enjoying a series where my primary thought is: Arden! Ditch Caspian!</description></item><item><title>Liberty &amp; Other Stories</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liberty-and-other-stories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liberty-and-other-stories/</guid><description>I did not think I could love the [[series/prosperityverse|Prosperityverse]] more, BUT I DO.</description></item><item><title>Paris Daillencourt is About to Crumble</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</guid><description>Once again Alexis Hall takes away the book I thought I wanted and replaces it with the book I actually need.
Reading this at the same time as [[books/the body keeps the score|The Body Keeps the Score]], though, just means I’m peeking between the lines of all the parental neglect and trauma and thinking, dearest Paris, get thee to some somatic therapy, medication is just a start.</description></item><item><title>Shadows &amp; Dreams</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</guid><description>I’m almost sad I did this in audio because there are SO MANY lines I would have copy-pasted. Except the audio is SO GOOD I am not sad. I will just read it again in words-on-page form to copy-paste lines, and it will be no trial.</description></item><item><title>Purgatorio</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</guid><description>Reading this alongside Guido Ruggiero’s [[books/the renaissance in italy|The Renaissance in Italy]] is A+ recommended. Once again, vastly more interesting than my first exposure, where school curriculum wanted it read like it was Pilgrim’s Progress. I needed the Bondanella introduction back then to dispense with the nonsense: “Such allegorical abstractions are simply not what Dante’s great poem is all about.</description></item><item><title>Husband Material</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/husband-material/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/husband-material/</guid><description>Choosing to interrogate the state of matrimony, I should have expected nothing less from Alexis Hall. I had to read this twice to really like it, because I am so urgggggh about weddings, and I needed the ending spoiled to get fully on board:
%%THEY DITCHED THEIR OWN WEDDING AT THE ALTAR WOOHOOO%%</description></item><item><title>A Lady’s Guide to Scandal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</guid><description>Aah, this was so fun! It righted some wrongs from Persuasion (I’m not a Wentworth fan, okay—don’t @ me), and threw in enough hijinks that it didn’t have to be a faithful retelling. The only character I adore more than Melville is Margaret; I’m in love with them both.</description></item><item><title>Harrow the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</guid><description>Amount of times this book made me cry: [redacted]. It is a sum equal to or only slightly less than the amount of times it made me cackle, gasp, and yelp.
“I cannot behold that apocalypse, Harrow. I think you are one of the only Lyctors who can really and truly understand apocalypse… It is not a death of fire.</description></item><item><title>Fire &amp; Water</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How to Belong with a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-belong-with-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-belong-with-a-billionaire/</guid><description>If there’s an author who could get me to love books with billionaire in the title, it’s Alexis Hall. Just like if there’s an author who could get me to love books with duke in the title, it’s going to be Alexis Hall’s [[books/a lady for a duke|upcoming historical romance]].</description></item><item><title>Paradiso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</guid><description>My dilemma since the early years of Sunday school: hell is more interesting than paradise. Thus, true to form, though I wanted to be contrary, [[books/inferno|Inferno]] is more interesting than any amount of heavenly light (so bright! so much dancing!), but get to that last line and you can’t help but feel the awe and poetry of it:</description></item><item><title>Nona the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</guid><description>Verdict still stands after book three: would have Harrowhark’s babies.
The end of [[books/gideon the ninth|Gideon]] had some pacing things, the start of [[books/harrow the ninth|Harrow]] had some pacing things; Nona was the one I barreled through in 1.5 days because I could not put the book down.</description></item><item><title>Smoke &amp; Ashes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lessons from Cruising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</guid><description>Joke’s on me, because I picked up this ARC for the last story, a retelling of Billy Budd from Captain Vere’s point of view. I figured I’d sample the rest; instead I went down the buffet line and inhaled them all. Rarely do I like every story in a short story collection, but that’s what Goodman’s done to me.</description></item><item><title>Looking for Group</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/looking-for-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/looking-for-group/</guid><description>Very nearly chaste because there’s a different love language, and that makes it one of the most romantic books I’ve read.</description></item><item><title>Murder Most Actual</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/murder-most-actual/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/murder-most-actual/</guid><description>Speaking of [[books/proper english|sapphic murder house mysteries]], Alexis Hall has the contemporary version on lock.
There are few things I like more than an established relationship romance—so very difficult to do well—and here it’s a marriage very naturally on the rocks for very relatable, natural reasons, just the living of life and complexities that ensue.</description></item><item><title>Spokes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spokes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spokes/</guid><description>Nooooo. I thought I had finally found the holy grail, cycling fiction (nay, romance!) that gets the cycling facts correct. The dedication is to Wouter Weylandt(!), there’s a glossary of French terms and race classifications, and four pages in she’s name-dropping Garmin-Sharp and Fausto Coppi. My expectations, below sea level, started to gain elevation.</description></item><item><title>The Affair of the Mysterious Letter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</guid><description>The only thing I’ve had brain space for this week is Alexis Hall, and I say that as the highest compliment. He brings so much heart, joy, and snark even when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery. Or should I say, especially when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery.</description></item><item><title>The Mask of Apollo</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-mask-of-apollo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-mask-of-apollo/</guid><description>I’m reserving five stars because Alexander shows up at the end and whoa, I want to see what she does with his books. But it’s a marvel. The best of Renault’s I’ve read yet? Thettalos is my fave.</description></item><item><title>Emma of 83rd Street</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:43:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</guid><description>[[books/emma|Emma]] is my favorite [[authors/jane austen|Austen]], and arguably the most difficult to modernize without losing the spirit of the story.1 I don’t envy any author who attempts it, but this one lost me in the weeds, with pacing that seems twice the length of Austen with half the page count.</description></item><item><title>A Sorceress Comes to Call</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</guid><description>I’m here all day long for T. Kingfisher’s aging, aching protagonists, with bad knees and big hearts and a well-honed sense of doom. The plot is a very loose retelling of The Goose Girl, minus princesses and kings and plus a conniving, murderous, sorceress mother. Evangeline, aka Doom, is determined to marry herself and her trapped, obedient daughter to the highest bidders in proper Regency-esque fashion, plans thwarted when she encounters a squire’s spinster sister who sees her for exactly who she is.</description></item><item><title>The Emperor and the Endless Palace</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-emperor-and-the-endless-palace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-emperor-and-the-endless-palace/</guid><description>I kept my expectations low, and the writing shows promise on the sentence level—but on the plot/structure/worldbuilding/thematic level, it falls apart. There are plot twists that change the entire point of the story, but Huang doesn’t write like he knows that. (If there’s a second book, perhaps he plans to explore that further, but it doesn’t come together in this book.</description></item><item><title>The Palace of Eros</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</guid><description>My adjectives for the prose: purple, dense, florid, bloated. It sounds like I’m describing a corpse. DNF @ 15% because none of it is connecting with me, not the first-person Psyche nor the third-person Eros, nor the prose that’s turgid to the point of hyperbole. (Did I just want the chance to deploy the word turgid?</description></item><item><title>The Spirit Ring</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</guid><description>Sometimes when things connect, they really connect. I picked this up because I was ready for another Bujold, and this is what the library had, and what is right there when I open it up? Renaissance Italy! Borgias, Florentines; Sforzas, Medicis; Guelphs and Ghibellines.
Three true things: it’s a gem in the rough; Thur is my boy; every Bujold, even vintage Bujold, is the best Bujold.</description></item><item><title>Starlings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starlings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starlings/</guid><description>My favorite stories are clustered right in the middle: “What A Piece of Work,” “Parable Lost,” “What Would Sam Spade Do?” But the first story is where the heroine has the line that makes me laugh, clap, and cheer:
“Love? Well now. You feel what you feel, and I feel what I feel, but that doesn’t mean you have to fit us into a story and wreck both our lives.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</guid><description>A note on translation: I used Reynolds to compare, contrast, and fill in the gaps with the [[books/orlando furioso a new verse translation|Slavitt translation]]. Slavitt takes liberties, and Reynolds has merit, but I’ve got to say, for compulsive readability, and cheeky irreverence that feels like it honors the spirit of the original, Slavitt it is.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso: A New Verse Translation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</guid><description>Ariosto writing like AO3 was a thing in the sixteenth century. I love it. Fiendishly clever layers of satire; a story where anything goes.</description></item><item><title>Spear</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item><item><title>Racing to You</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</guid><description>“Has someone written a romance about pro cycling?” was something I wondered last week. And voila, this book.
It actually:
Has some legit knowledge of cycling! Addresses doping as a plot point Addresses the extremely monastic and high-pressure lifestyle Gets the team dynamic! Has real races like Paris-Nice!</description></item><item><title>The Black Jersey</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</guid><description>It takes until page 280 for the main character to say, “I am an imbecile,” which is the truest thing in the book.
Oh boy. So many feelings. That are conflicted. Is this a book about cycling? Yes. Do I love cycling? Yes. Do I love books about cycling?</description></item><item><title>On the Fox Roads</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</guid><description>Nghi Vo can write [[books/the chosen and the beautiful|queer Jazz Age fanfic]] for me all day any day. (Also excellent: the Venn diagram of her Chinese and Vietnamese characters, the overlapping similarities and the differences.)</description></item><item><title>Infamous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</guid><description>This ending was the EXACT ENDING I’ve wanted to see for SO LONG. (Unapologetic all caps.) It took us ages to get there (more on that in a sec) but once we did? CHEF’S KISS.
Spoilery: %%it’s an f/f romance, and one half of the pair is affianced, to an amazing man, who’s gay, and they are going to use their marriage to give themselves and their true partners a safe harbor from society, and they go through with their marriage, and it’s just beautifully done, and… sniff I have a lot of feelings about friendships and healthy communication and unconventional choices and that kind of love.</description></item><item><title>The Chosen and the Beautiful</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</guid><description>As someone who has long loved [[authors/f scott fitzgerald|F. Scott Fitzgerald]]’s writing, despite his depressing and often problematic deal, this [[books/the great gatsby|Gatsby]] retelling vis-à-vis a Vietnamese Jordan Baker is exquisite. Absolutely true to the spirit of the original, while absolutely its own fantastical, queer, eerie, spectacular thing.</description></item><item><title>Gwen &amp; Art Are Not in Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</guid><description>I think it wobbled a smiiiidge on the landing, a few things felt abrupt and/or undercooked, not to mention the jarring tonal shift into violence, but the ride to get there was super fun. There’s some fade-to-black, hand-wavey, don’t-think-too-hard-about-this energy re: the whole premature-inheritance, fix-a-broken-system-from-the-inside plan, but it is YA, and I wasn’t expecting an [[books/bitter|Akwaeke Emezi-level thesis]] on the subject of institutional power.</description></item><item><title>Reputation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</guid><description>Lex Croucher’s lols-per-page cannot be beat.
Weirdly, the only character I was meh on was the love interest, just because he’s too perfect. (My notes say “Col Brandon in a Henry Tilney body???”) I also would have been fine if this had swung more towards a coming-of-age instead of HEA romance, but I won’t hold that against it.</description></item><item><title>Kiss Her Once for Me</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</guid><description>Tried this one again, hoping I had one more festive read in me for the year, but there are just sooo many things that bug me right away. It’s gonna be one of those books where shitty systemic poverty gets magically fixed for one [pretty young white] woman by the power of romance with a [manipulative gaslighting] millionaire, isn’t it?</description></item><item><title>The Dragon Waiting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dragon-waiting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dragon-waiting/</guid><description>“The Velvet Underground of novels,” as Scott Lynch says in the introduction. This book is a masterwork. If I ever mix up my history on the Medicis, the War of the Roses, and the Byzantine Empire, it’s probably because I’ve misremembered this fiction as fact. It’s a fascinating thought experiment, imagining how the trajectory of history would look different (or not) if Julian the Apostate had had a long, successful rule.</description></item><item><title>The Price of Meat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</guid><description>Maybe don’t read this over lunch like I did? By which I mean, it’s fanfic of Sweeney Todd, it’s grisly horror, and it’s very good and effective, because KJ Charles. She can write anything from [[books/band sinister|Georgette Heyer homages]] to penny dreadfuls and it’s worth the ink.</description></item><item><title>Wanted, A Gentleman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</guid><description>She had me at “gothic novelist” and “lonely hearts columnist.” This is wonderful. I love it when Charles just unleashes her id.
Note: I’m including the epilogue Wanted, an Author, in which Corvin from [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] makes a cameo and Theo’s gay gothic erotica novel Jonathan: or The Struggles of Virtue is at the top of my list for books-within-a-book that I most need to read.</description></item><item><title>Band Sinister</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</guid><description>If this isn’t everything that’s wholesome and good in the world, I don’t know what is. A tribute to Heyer indeed; it just includes those who paint with oils outside conventional lines. It cranked my heart open without being saccharine or heavy. One of those books where I have to be careful what I read next because it might not measure up.</description></item><item><title>Songs of Innocence and Experience</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/songs-of-innocence-and-experience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/songs-of-innocence-and-experience/</guid><description/></item><item><title>William Blake: The Complete Illuminated Books</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/william-blake-the-complete-illuminated-books/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/william-blake-the-complete-illuminated-books/</guid><description>Reading Blake, I always get the sense he’s working in a fever, trying to translate an ecstatic vision for us mortals. I saw someone call him the original troll—that too, the radical printmaker in the time when printmaking was a real threat to the established order.</description></item></channel></rss>