<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>here-be-dragons on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/here-be-dragons/</link><description>Recent content in here-be-dragons on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/here-be-dragons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Wizard of Earthsea</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-wizard-of-earthsea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-wizard-of-earthsea/</guid><description>This felt like something between prologue and parable, and yet I’m still into it. More Earthsea, here I come.</description></item><item><title>Shadow &amp; Claw</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadow-claw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadow-claw/</guid><description>I think a series that has its own [[books/lexicon urthus|lexicon]] counts for the ultimate feat of [[notes/puzzle-book worldbuilding|puzzle-book worldbuilding]].</description></item><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>Sword &amp; Citadel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sword-citadel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sword-citadel/</guid><description>Ugh, my [[notes/puzzle-book worldbuilding|puzzle-loving brain]] absolutely loved this. Even all the places where it was like, Gene, your Roman Catholicism is showing. And when apparently such brilliant flights of imagination can’t imagine a different role for women in the universe.
But the brilliant ideas were brilliant, and the execution thereof.</description></item><item><title>The Red Threads of Fortune</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</guid><description>This should have been book 1! Or I should have done my typical thing of reading out of order and started here! The one time I try to be responsible and read a series in order, this is what happens.
Technically, these are “twin novellas,” but IMO, Mokoya is the emotional core of the story, followed by Rider, and Akeha in [[books/the black tides of heaven|Black Tides]] is an interesting prequel.</description></item><item><title>The Tombs of Atuan</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-tombs-of-atuan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-tombs-of-atuan/</guid><description>The funny thing is, I sometimes resist reading Ursula K. Le Guin. Because I know I’ll have to stop, and do nothing else, and absorb through my pores, and not read any of the other ten or twelve things I might have read that week, and just camp out in her world as long as I can.</description></item><item><title>The Descent of Monsters</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</guid><description>So we’re completely changing protagonists AND writing style AND partially the genre too? Hell yes! Basically it’s the official report on the fallout of the [[books/the red threads of fortune|second book]], done epistolary style (with redactions!), introducing major revelations of its own.
Loved it. Definitely doesn’t stand on its own—don’t start here.</description></item><item><title>Lunar New Year Love Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lunar-new-year-love-story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lunar-new-year-love-story/</guid><description>What I loved: the cultural stuff, especially lion dancing, and the nuance about the Asian diaspora (Vietnamese, Chinese, and Korean all represented).
What I wasn’t expecting: Lunar New Year actually plays a small part in the story; it’s much more focused on Valentine’s Day and Catholicism.</description></item><item><title>The Dragon Waiting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dragon-waiting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dragon-waiting/</guid><description>“The Velvet Underground of novels,” as Scott Lynch says in the introduction. This book is a masterwork. If I ever mix up my history on the Medicis, the War of the Roses, and the Byzantine Empire, it’s probably because I’ve misremembered this fiction as fact. It’s a fascinating thought experiment, imagining how the trajectory of history would look different (or not) if Julian the Apostate had had a long, successful rule.</description></item></channel></rss>