<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Digests on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/</link><description>Recent content in Digests on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Books of November ’24</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-november-24/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-november-24/</guid><description>My reading mood took a nonfiction, political, anarchic bent this month. (Gee, I wonder why?)
[[books/deviant matter|Deviant Matter: Ferment, Intoxicants, Jelly, Rot]] — [[authors/kyla wazana tompkins|Kyla Wazana Tompkins]] (2024) It’s a bummer that I am so very interested in the premise of this, but the dense academic writing, chock full of jargon, makes it nearly inaccessible.</description></item><item><title>Books of October ’24</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-october-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-october-24/</guid><description>New Nghi Vo! New Nghi Vo! New Vajra Chandrasekera too, although that came out in June, but I’ve been saving it for October. Sometimes I just know which books are gonna be bangers, and I want to save them for my birthday month. And of course, a few horror reads too.</description></item><item><title>Books of September ’24</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-september-24/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-september-24/</guid><description>A whopping 20 books this month, including the start of a spontaneous re-read of Jane Austen. (Oops!) A few other re-reads for September too, comfort and otherwise. The unintended theme of the month is a bit political, from Austen to de Sade, from housing rights to reproductive rights.</description></item><item><title>Books of August ’24</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-august-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-august-24/</guid><description>A pretty even mix of great and not-great this month. The highs were high (Gathered Heat! Adib Khorram’s romcom! Kingfisher and Borges!) but the lows were low with a streak of disappointing historical romances. I’m almost ready for a solid three-star mediocre read to decompress. A lucky number 13 once again, but that’s with stranding four (excellent) books that I’m within a couple chapters of finishing—stay tuned for September.</description></item><item><title>Books of July ’24</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-july-24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 22:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-july-24/</guid><description>July was a hellacious month, both work-wise and heat-wise, but I finished (a lucky number) 13 books. ARCs aplenty, plus some anticipated new releases, plus clearing out the TBR means I mostly read books published in the last 24 months. Gasp! I’m gonna need some dusty, mothballed books soon.</description></item><item><title>Books of June ’24</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-june-24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/digest/books-of-june-24/</guid><description>I finished around fifteen books in June, even though the weather got too hot, too fast, for hammock time. Rufi Thorpe swooped in hot with one of my favorite books for the month (and year), but she was far from the only highlight. Let’s give this digest idea a whirl.</description></item></channel></rss>