<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>new-york on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/new-york/</link><description>Recent content in new-york on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/new-york/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iris Kelly Doesn’t Date</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</guid><description>Yes to the gender-bending production of Much Ado About Nothing; yes to practice dating and sex lessons. Beyond that, the plot was a hot mess for me, trying to both validate Iris’s singledom yet ultimately get her in a relationship. I appreciate that Blake acknowledged the difficulty of walking that tightrope, and it is a rom-com—of course it’s gonna be an HEA.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>The Believers</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-believers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-believers/</guid><description>“The Believers”—as in, the first of the eight stories, from which this collection takes its title—is a barnburner. A houseburner? That’s what literally happens in the end, when a couple from Jamaica try to disentangle themselves from the creepy church who sponsors them in Brooklyn and wants to marry off their daughter.</description></item><item><title>The Good Life</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-good-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-good-life/</guid><description>Man takes [[books/the great gatsby|The Great Gatsby]] as a how-to manual, right down to the narcissism and body count, just with more explicit gay sex. (As in, Gatsby the way the good lord intended.) It’s unpleasant to read in the way obscene wealth always is, but it’s beautifully structured and compellingly written, an interesting artifact of both the era in which it’s set and when it’s written.</description></item><item><title>You Made a Fool of Death with Your Beauty</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/you-made-a-fool-of-death-with-your-beauty/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/you-made-a-fool-of-death-with-your-beauty/</guid><description>Re-read. The widowed Feyi hooks up with a stranger, then dates his best friend Nasir, then falls in love with Nasir’s father, and none of that sentence captures the raw transcendence of this novel. It makes me not just cry, but weep, multiple times—not (only) because of the grief but because of the way it vibrates with life, with pain, with joy, with every raw emotion.</description></item><item><title>Emma of 83rd Street</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:43:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</guid><description>[[books/emma|Emma]] is my favorite [[authors/jane austen|Austen]], and arguably the most difficult to modernize without losing the spirit of the story.1 I don’t envy any author who attempts it, but this one lost me in the weeds, with pacing that seems twice the length of Austen with half the page count.</description></item><item><title>A Woman Is No Man</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</guid><description>We need more books by Palestinian and Arab authors. I intend to read more by Etaf Rum. But it pains me to say… I think this could have been a (powerful) short story. The structure and even dialogue is very repetitive, in a way that I’m sure is meant to illustrate the cyclical and generational cycle of abuse, but instead means you could skim chapters and not miss anything.</description></item></channel></rss>