<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>new-york on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/new-york/</link><description>Recent content in new-york on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/new-york/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iris Kelly Doesn’t Date</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</guid><description>Yes to the gender-bending production of Much Ado About Nothing; yes to practice dating and sex lessons. Beyond that, the plot was a hot mess for me, trying to both validate Iris’s singledom yet ultimately get her in a relationship. I appreciate that Blake acknowledged the difficulty of walking that tightrope, and it is a rom-com—of course it’s gonna be an HEA.</description></item><item><title>A Woman Is No Man</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</guid><description>We need more books by Palestinian and Arab authors. I intend to read more by Etaf Rum. But it pains me to say… I think this could have been a (powerful) short story. The structure and even dialogue is very repetitive, in a way that I’m sure is meant to illustrate the cyclical and generational cycle of abuse, but instead means you could skim chapters and not miss anything.</description></item><item><title>Emma of 83rd Street</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</guid><description>Emma is my favorite Austen, and arguably the most difficult to modernize without losing the spirit of the story.1 I don’t envy any author who attempts it, but this one lost me in the weeds, with pacing that seems twice the length of Austen with half the page count.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item></channel></rss>