<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gothic on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/gothic/</link><description>Recent content in gothic on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/gothic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Something Fabulous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</guid><description>So far the theme of the year is romances that I read and then re-read right away and install on my best-of-year list (best-of-ever list too, in the case of Something Fabulous, which more than lives up to its name).
A few notes:
We’re starting to see the books written during the pandemic where authors are writing what they WANT, not what they SHOULD.</description></item><item><title>Jane Eyre</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jane-eyre/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jane-eyre/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Carmilla</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:13:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</guid><description>I suppose I should be talking about the book, but Megan Follows does the audio, so my actual takeaway is: my Megan Follows crush has not abated after 25 years. The absolute perfect choice of narrator for a gothic, queer, melodramatic, erotically-charged tale.
![[images/megan-follows-aogg.gif]]
Note: I borrowed the audiobook from the library, but I’ve marked this Lanternfish Press edition because I also sought it out solely for the Carmen Maria Machado foreword, which is excellent and should not be missed.</description></item><item><title>Northanger Abbey</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/northanger-abbey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/northanger-abbey/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gothic Tales</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Green Equinox</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-green-equinox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-green-equinox/</guid><description>Sometimes you’re just in the mood for moody, queer af British novels with all the fraught gender politics and literary melodrama of the 1970’s. What can I say! So odd and compelling, like a fever dream. (Often literally, as there is an outbreak of typhoid that infects the course of the story.</description></item><item><title>Infamous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</guid><description>This ending was the EXACT ENDING I’ve wanted to see for SO LONG. (Unapologetic all caps.) It took us ages to get there (more on that in a sec) but once we did? CHEF’S KISS.
Spoilery: %%it’s an f/f romance, and one half of the pair is affianced, to an amazing man, who’s gay, and they are going to use their marriage to give themselves and their true partners a safe harbor from society, and they go through with their marriage, and it’s just beautifully done, and… sniff I have a lot of feelings about friendships and healthy communication and unconventional choices and that kind of love.</description></item><item><title>Starling House</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</guid><description>After burning out on southern gothic, it delights me when there are authors that make it fresh again, doing something fun in the genre.
Here’s how you write horror in Kentucky. All of the elements, from the book-within-a-book to the lingering satanic panic to the generational trauma to the historical footnotes to the ecological elegy to the snarky wit, worked for me.</description></item><item><title>The Henchmen of Zenda</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-henchmen-of-zenda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-henchmen-of-zenda/</guid><description>When KJ Charles is on, she’s on. This book is all the things: fun, ridiculous, hilarious, swashbuckling, hot, FUN. The high pulp style suits her so well because she can pack the book full of joy and all the sneering and sniding she likes to write works because it’s comic and joyful.</description></item><item><title>Wanted, A Gentleman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</guid><description>She had me at “gothic novelist” and “lonely hearts columnist.” This is wonderful. I love it when Charles just unleashes her id.
Note: I’m including the epilogue Wanted, an Author, in which Corvin from [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] makes a cameo and Theo’s gay gothic erotica novel Jonathan: or The Struggles of Virtue is at the top of my list for books-within-a-book that I most need to read.</description></item></channel></rss>