<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>propaganda on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/propaganda/</link><description>Recent content in propaganda on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/propaganda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mute the narrative soundtrack for global politics</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mute-the-narrative-soundtrack-for-global-politics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mute-the-narrative-soundtrack-for-global-politics/</guid><description>Much like mindfulness helps cut through the internal noise, muting the narrative helps cut through the external noise.
Learn the art of perceiving life without the perceptual filter of narrative. Mentally “mute” the narrative soundtrack and watch where all the resources are going, where the weapons are moving to and coming from, who’s being killed and imprisoned etc, to get a clear picture of what’s going on in the world.</description></item><item><title>The three stages of gaslighting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-stages-of-gaslighting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-stages-of-gaslighting/</guid><description>Gaslighting is basically a step-by-step psychological process to manipulate and destabilize you. It’s repetitive information force-fed to you that builds up over time, undermining your faith in your own logic, reason, and judgement. It’s super hard to detect because it’s encoded on the subconscious “hard disk,” which isn’t overridden by the conscious “floppy disk.</description></item><item><title>US exceptionalism is abusive narcissism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/us-exceptionalism-is-abusive-narcissism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/us-exceptionalism-is-abusive-narcissism/</guid><description>Exceptionalism has come to represent superiority in the minds and hearts of Americans, and belief in their economic, military and ideological supremacy is what has motivated successive US governments to shape the world in their “superior” image with no regard for the destruction left in the wake of their exceptional hegemony.</description></item></channel></rss>