<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dirty-south on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/dirty-south/</link><description>Recent content in dirty-south on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/dirty-south/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>Country Queers</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/country-queers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/country-queers/</guid><description>A book after my little southern queer heart. Garringer crisscrosses the Bible Belt, collecting a scrapbook and oral history of various LGBTQ+ people living in the rural margins. The older interviewees—the elders who survived the AIDS crisis and more—are the best and most emotional part. It’s easy to get miffed when people act like the Brooklyn or San Francisco subcultures are the only ones that matter, or like gay and trans people don’t exist in the south except to be persecuted.</description></item><item><title>Evil Eye</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</guid><description>This is why I wanted to read more Etaf Rum. This is the book I knew she had in her. It’s just as brilliant and damning a portrait of a toxic marriage as [[books/liars|Liars]] was, with the added generational trauma and displacement of a Palestinian family.</description></item><item><title>Starling House</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</guid><description>After burning out on southern gothic, it delights me when there are authors that make it fresh again, doing something fun in the genre.
Here’s how you write horror in Kentucky. All of the elements, from the book-within-a-book to the lingering satanic panic to the generational trauma to the historical footnotes to the ecological elegy to the snarky wit, worked for me.</description></item></channel></rss>