<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>americana on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/americana/</link><description>Recent content in americana on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:23:02 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/americana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Parable of the Sower</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-sower/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-sower/</guid><description>I loved the Earthseed parts of this (God is Change), but the dystopia parts went the way of most dystopias for me, almost too limited in its imagination? It also feels like only half of a whole, so I think that’s part of it too. Will revisit these feelings after [[books/parable of the talents|Parable of the Talents]].</description></item><item><title>Pet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pet/</guid><description>A YA book that discusses [[authors/hannah arendt|Hannah Arendt]] and [[books/the origins of totalitarianism|the banality of evil]] in the introduction, then goes on to drop some biblically accurate angels? YES PLEASE.</description></item><item><title>A Restless Truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</guid><description>This was so close to being great. SO CLOSE. But overall, the book felt kind of like the menagerie on board the ship, let loose in all directions, refusing to be corralled. There were some structure/plot/writing choices that left me more stumped than dazzled. Maud’s and Violet’s POV seemed really interchangeable for the first half, which is&amp;hellip; not great when one is a supposedly scandalous, sardonic, shrewd actress and one is a sheltered, capricious, stubborn young girl.</description></item><item><title>Parable of the Talents</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-talents/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-talents/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bitter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</guid><description>Is this even better than [[books/pet|Pet]]? Holy crap, I think so. The struggle. The hope. The tenderness. It knocked me sideways. I love it.
Bitter had learned it was better to be stoic, to be a blank and unfeeling wall, because if you were entirely armor and no underbelly, then they couldn’t stab you in the soft places.</description></item><item><title>We the Gathered Heat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:23:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</guid><description>Superb. This is how to do an anthology, where the disparate voices are the point—how do we even define AAPI except as “the other,” non-white? Who is the “we” in question? To whom is that category useful? The poems are sorted into themes of “mourn,” “pronounce,” “fight,” “love,” each as powerful as the last.</description></item><item><title>A Woman Is No Man</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</guid><description>We need more books by Palestinian and Arab authors. I intend to read more by Etaf Rum. But it pains me to say… I think this could have been a (powerful) short story. The structure and even dialogue is very repetitive, in a way that I’m sure is meant to illustrate the cyclical and generational cycle of abuse, but instead means you could skim chapters and not miss anything.</description></item><item><title>Evil Eye</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</guid><description>This is why I wanted to read more Etaf Rum. This is the book I knew she had in her. It’s just as brilliant and damning a portrait of a toxic marriage as [[books/liars|Liars]] was, with the added generational trauma and displacement of a Palestinian family.</description></item><item><title>Lessons from Cruising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</guid><description>Joke’s on me, because I picked up this ARC for the last story, a retelling of Billy Budd from Captain Vere’s point of view. I figured I’d sample the rest; instead I went down the buffet line and inhaled them all. Rarely do I like every story in a short story collection, but that’s what Goodman’s done to me.</description></item><item><title>Blackouts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</guid><description>All the different layers of meaning to the title—the blackouts our narrator experiences due to PTSD, the blackouts of Juan and his fading memory, the failure of institutional memory, the queer erasure from history, the literal blackouts of the pages of the book. It feels like a work of art, not just a novel.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>Our History Is the Future</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/our-history-is-the-future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/our-history-is-the-future/</guid><description>An excellent re-issue of a book that&amp;rsquo;s been on my to-read list since it first published in 2019. I&amp;rsquo;m glad it finally prompted me to get to it. It’s the history of two centuries of indigenous activism in the context of even broader indigenous exploitation and resistance, and it needs to be more widely known.</description></item><item><title>Yellowface</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</guid><description>After witnessing the accidental death of her frenemy Athena Liu, failed author June Hayward refashions herself as Juniper Song and steals Athena’s posthumous masterpiece to pass it off as her own. Cue white woman tears, as she’s victimized and vilified by the consequences of her own egregious actions.</description></item><item><title>On the Fox Roads</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</guid><description>Nghi Vo can write [[books/the chosen and the beautiful|queer Jazz Age fanfic]] for me all day any day. (Also excellent: the Venn diagram of her Chinese and Vietnamese characters, the overlapping similarities and the differences.)</description></item><item><title>Siren Queen</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/siren-queen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/siren-queen/</guid><description>I’ve been saving this one to be my birthday book because I knew Nghi Vo would deliver. Hoo boy, did she ever. Fav of the year? What she does with queerness, horror, and myth is just chef’s kiss.</description></item><item><title>The Chosen and the Beautiful</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</guid><description>As someone who has long loved [[authors/f scott fitzgerald|F. Scott Fitzgerald]]’s writing, despite his depressing and often problematic deal, this [[books/the great gatsby|Gatsby]] retelling vis-à-vis a Vietnamese Jordan Baker is exquisite. Absolutely true to the spirit of the original, while absolutely its own fantastical, queer, eerie, spectacular thing.</description></item><item><title>Starling House</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</guid><description>After burning out on southern gothic, it delights me when there are authors that make it fresh again, doing something fun in the genre.
Here’s how you write horror in Kentucky. All of the elements, from the book-within-a-book to the lingering satanic panic to the generational trauma to the historical footnotes to the ecological elegy to the snarky wit, worked for me.</description></item><item><title>Kiss Her Once for Me</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</guid><description>Tried this one again, hoping I had one more festive read in me for the year, but there are just sooo many things that bug me right away. It’s gonna be one of those books where shitty systemic poverty gets magically fixed for one [pretty young white] woman by the power of romance with a [manipulative gaslighting] millionaire, isn’t it?</description></item><item><title>Exodus 20</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:55:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</guid><description>If you’re gonna write monster kink, make it a biblically accurate angel. And throw in some searing social/political/theological commentary. This was excellent.</description></item><item><title>Cat’s Cradle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/cats-cradle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/cats-cradle/</guid><description/></item><item><title>China Mountain Zhang</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fledgling</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fledgling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fledgling/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Following the Water</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/following-the-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/following-the-water/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Leaves of Grass</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/leaves-of-grass/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/leaves-of-grass/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Great Gatsby</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-great-gatsby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-great-gatsby/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Lathe Of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</guid><description>I can’t remember the last time I read a book with a truly passive protagonist, where his qualities are not his weakness, but his strength. He doesn’t change who he is. There is no lesson needed. He is the virtue, not the flaw. Le Guin stacks George Orr up against the passionate Huber who wants to save the world, and carefully and thoroughly makes the case for the former.</description></item><item><title>Braiding Sweetgrass</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Annals of the Former World</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/annals-of-the-former-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/annals-of-the-former-world/</guid><description>I’m glad I’m not beyond the age where books I read can change the way I see the world. If that is an age you can reach, I don’t want to. I can’t even drive down the highway now without seeing something as simple as roadcuts in a whole different light.</description></item><item><title>Giovanni’s Room</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</guid><description>Not everyone in book club was a fan, but I loved it, but it was brutal, but I’m glad I read it, but I’m glad I won’t be in a rush to read it again.
“Somebody,” said Jacques, “your father or mine, should have told us that not many people have ever died of love.</description></item><item><title>I’ll Have What He’s Having</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</guid><description>I’m glad the term tonic masculinity has been making the rounds, because this feels like tonic masculinity of the highest order. David Curtis, sommelier, mistakes Farzan Alavi for a food critic, and what blooms in the wake of this mixup is a tender, sexy, heartfelt romance between two grown adults who have to deal with the obstacles that a grown-ass relationship entails.</description></item><item><title>One Day I’ll Grow Up and Be a Beautiful Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</guid><description>Nonfiction memoir about a mother raising her autistic, transgender daughter and the New Hampshire town that puts their family through hell. A harrowing and heartbreaking survival guide (barely? hopefully?) about weathering the eye of the current political storm. I’m always looking for books I can recommend to well-meaning people who want to see past the transphobic headlines, and this one goes on the list.</description></item></channel></rss>