<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>power on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/power/</link><description>Recent content in power on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Abandon the ancient impulse to control</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abandon-the-ancient-impulse-to-control/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abandon-the-ancient-impulse-to-control/</guid><description>If humanity is to survive into the future and move out of its psychopathy-enabling competition-based models into a collaborative relationship with all of humankind and with its entire ecosystem, that future will necessarily come with an abandonment of our ancient impulse to control. Our impulse to control nations, to control each other, to control life itself.</description></item><item><title>Ideology cloaks power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ideology-cloaks-power/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ideology-cloaks-power/</guid><description>Superficially, the means by which power conceals itself is through stories. Its needs narratives — mainly about those who appear powerful — to create political and social dramas that distract us from thinking about deep power. But more fundamentally still, power depends on ideology. Ideology cloaks power – in a real sense, it is power — because it is the source of power’s invisibility.</description></item><item><title>Power exists only so long as we consent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-exists-only-so-long-as-we-consent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-exists-only-so-long-as-we-consent/</guid><description>Power is the structure of the thoughts we think we control, a framework for the ideologies we think we voted for, the values we think we choose to treasure, the horizon of imaginations we think we created. Power exists only so long as we consent to it through our blind obedience.</description></item><item><title>Power is both structural and ideological</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-is-both-structural-and-ideological/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-is-both-structural-and-ideological/</guid><description>Power always has an ideological shape and physical structures. It has both faces. It existed before capitalism, and will exist after it (if capitalism doesn’t kill us first). Human history has consisted of power consolidating and regenerating itself in new form over and over again — like the eponymous hero of the long-running British TV sci-fi series Doctor Who — as different groups have learnt how to harness it, usurp it and put it to self-interested use.</description></item><item><title>Transparency should be directly proportionate to power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/transparency-should-be-directly-proportionate-to-power/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/transparency-should-be-directly-proportionate-to-power/</guid><description>Western liberal democracy is when corporations and bankers place all blame on the government, the government places all blame on the electorate, and the electorate absorbs all the consequences of the corporations, bankers and government without ever even getting a vote on any of the major decisions those entities make.</description></item><item><title>Any human power can be changed by human beings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/any-human-power-can-be-changed-by-human-beings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/any-human-power-can-be-changed-by-human-beings/</guid><description> We live in capitalism. Its power seems inescapable. So did the divine right of kings.
Any human power can be resisted and changed by human beings. —[[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula K. Le Guin]], National Book Awards Speech
see also: [[notes/the only thing keeping a crown on a king’s head is narrative|the only thing keeping a crown on a king’s head is narrative]], and [[notes/since it’s all narrative, anything is possible|since it’s all narrative, anything is possible]] see also: [[notes/we are making ourselves up as we go|we are making ourselves up as we go]] future: link to how we stay blind to the story of power</description></item><item><title>US exceptionalism is abusive narcissism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/us-exceptionalism-is-abusive-narcissism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/us-exceptionalism-is-abusive-narcissism/</guid><description>Exceptionalism has come to represent superiority in the minds and hearts of Americans, and belief in their economic, military and ideological supremacy is what has motivated successive US governments to shape the world in their “superior” image with no regard for the destruction left in the wake of their exceptional hegemony.</description></item><item><title>All relationships involve power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-relationships-involve-power/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-relationships-involve-power/</guid><description>Every relationship involves a power exchange, and learning the dynamics of power exchanges can be key to navigating relationships in general—and I’d argue life in general. It gets a hell of a lot easier to spot abuse and control.
Just as all power relationships are relationships, all relationships also involve power.</description></item><item><title>Self-censorship is primarily state censorship</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-censorship-is-primarily-state-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-censorship-is-primarily-state-censorship/</guid><description>State censorship shapes and causes self-censorship, directly and intentionally. To act like it’s primarily a civilian phenomenon is to perpetuate the illusion and miss the point entirely.
Hence, my biggest conclusion, the majority of real censorship is self-censorship, but the majority of self-censorship is intentionally cultivated by an outside power trying to cause that self-censorship to occur.</description></item><item><title>The three lies of power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</guid><description>For all the aspiring authoritarians wanting to “do the right thing” and force their good ideas on everyone, [[authors/adam mastroianni|Adam Mastroianni]] outlines the wildly delusional three lies of power:
The good guys will always have more power than the bad guys (ed note: I’d argue, the fact we even believe good guys vs.</description></item><item><title>To dominate is to destroy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/to-dominate-is-to-destroy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/to-dominate-is-to-destroy/</guid><description>The Taoists are saying, then, that seen as a whole the universe is a harmony or symbiosis of patterns which cannot exist without each other. However, when it is looked at section by section we find conflict. The biological world is a mutual eating society in which every species is the prey of another.</description></item><item><title>Tools for thinking about censorship</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/</guid><description>[[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]] has an excellent essay in Reactor Mag (formerly Tor) about the psychological and manipulative tactics of preventing free speech, and thus tools for thinking about free speech: https://reactormag.com/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/
The whole thing is excellent and worth a read, but I wanted to copy down her five takeaways below:</description></item><item><title>Institutional betrayal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</guid><description>Institutional betrayal is when an institution causes harm (by action or inaction) to anyone who trusts or depends on them. Red flags include strict membership requirements (the military, elite sports), prestige or power differentials (caregivers v. patients, clergy v. parishioners), and rigid priorities, like extreme efforts to protect the reputation of the organization.</description></item><item><title>Abuse isn’t just pathological, it’s political</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-isnt-just-pathological-its-political/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-isnt-just-pathological-its-political/</guid><description>Red flag for anything rationalizing “this is just the way things are,” or framing a problem as an individual one instead of a collective one. (Or worse, putting the onus on the victim instead of the offender.)
Feminists know about power. Specifically, they know a lot about unequal power relationships; how they are systematically used, and how they are rationalised or explained away as ‘just the way things are’.</description></item><item><title>Power doesn’t need facts or evidence, just narrative and ideology</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-doesnt-need-facts-or-evidence-just-narrative-and-ideology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-doesnt-need-facts-or-evidence-just-narrative-and-ideology/</guid><description>Power doesn’t need facts or evidence, even when its claims are self-evidently disruptive to the democratic process. It exists chiefly in the realm of narrative and ideology. This is a story, just like Corbyn’s “antisemitism crisis”, that is made true simply through repetition.
Because power is power, its narratives can defy the most elementary rules of logic.</description></item><item><title>The only thing keeping a crown on a king’s head is narrative</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-only-thing-keeping-a-crown-on-a-kings-head-is-narrative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-only-thing-keeping-a-crown-on-a-kings-head-is-narrative/</guid><description>This is why there have been book burnings, heretic burnings, and executions for mocking the emperor throughout history: ==ideas which differ from the dominant narratives about what power is, how money works, who should be in charge and so on are threatening to a ruler’s power in the exact same way that an assassin’s dagger is.</description></item><item><title>You’re only powerless if you stand alone</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/youre-only-powerless-if-you-stand-alone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/youre-only-powerless-if-you-stand-alone/</guid><description>We’ve all got a grain of sand’s worth of influence over our world. The historically unprecedented democratization of information and our ability to network and communicate like never before has given us all a grain of sand’s worth of power to open eyes and win hearts and minds over to a more revolutionary worldview.</description></item></channel></rss>