<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>power on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/power/</link><description>Recent content in power on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>All relationships involve power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-relationships-involve-power/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-relationships-involve-power/</guid><description>Every relationship involves a power exchange, and learning the dynamics of power exchanges can be key to navigating relationships in general—and I’d argue life in general. It gets a hell of a lot easier to spot abuse and control.
Just as all power relationships are relationships, all relationships also involve power.</description></item><item><title>Self-censorship is primarily state censorship</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-censorship-is-primarily-state-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-censorship-is-primarily-state-censorship/</guid><description>State censorship shapes and causes self-censorship, directly and intentionally. To act like it’s primarily a civilian phenomenon is to perpetuate the illusion and miss the point entirely.
Hence, my biggest conclusion, the majority of real censorship is self-censorship, but the majority of self-censorship is intentionally cultivated by an outside power trying to cause that self-censorship to occur.</description></item><item><title>The three lies of power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</guid><description>For all the aspiring authoritarians wanting to “do the right thing” and force their good ideas on everyone, [[authors/adam mastroianni|Adam Mastroianni]] outlines the wildly delusional three lies of power:
The good guys will always have more power than the bad guys (ed note: I’d argue, the fact we even believe good guys vs.</description></item><item><title>To dominate is to destroy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/to-dominate-is-to-destroy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/to-dominate-is-to-destroy/</guid><description>The Taoists are saying, then, that seen as a whole the universe is a harmony or symbiosis of patterns which cannot exist without each other. However, when it is looked at section by section we find conflict. The biological world is a mutual eating society in which every species is the prey of another.</description></item><item><title>Tools for thinking about censorship</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/</guid><description>[[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]] has an excellent essay in Reactor Mag (formerly Tor) about the psychological and manipulative tactics of preventing free speech, and thus tools for thinking about free speech: https://reactormag.com/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/
The whole thing is excellent and worth a read, but I wanted to copy down her five takeaways below:</description></item><item><title>Institutional betrayal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</guid><description>Institutional betrayal is when an institution causes harm (by action or inaction) to anyone who trusts or depends on them. Red flags include strict membership requirements (the military, elite sports), prestige or power differentials (caregivers v. patients, clergy v. parishioners), and rigid priorities, like extreme efforts to protect the reputation of the organization.</description></item><item><title>Abuse isn’t just pathological, it’s political</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-isnt-just-pathological-its-political/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-isnt-just-pathological-its-political/</guid><description>Red flag for anything rationalizing “this is just the way things are,” or framing a problem as an individual one instead of a collective one. (Or worse, putting the onus on the victim instead of the offender.)
Feminists know about power. Specifically, they know a lot about unequal power relationships; how they are systematically used, and how they are rationalised or explained away as ‘just the way things are’.</description></item></channel></rss>