<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>road-trip on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/road-trip/</link><description>Recent content in road-trip on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/road-trip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Something Fabulous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</guid><description>So far the theme of the year is romances that I read and then re-read right away and install on my best-of-year list (best-of-ever list too, in the case of Something Fabulous, which more than lives up to its name).
A few notes:
We’re starting to see the books written during the pandemic where authors are writing what they WANT, not what they SHOULD.</description></item><item><title>Paladin of Souls</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</guid><description>Magnificent. I didn’t think Bujold could top Cazaril as a character, and she does. Illvin and beloved Ista. Such a rich, full, scarred world she’s created. It spoke to me deeply, even more than the first. I cried. I felt joy-struck. Cursed, bitter Ista is also blessed, beloved Ista.</description></item><item><title>Something Extraordinary</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</guid><description>The high-strung Belle has left behind her heroine era, and the drama-prone Rufus has left behind his Sir Horley Comewithers era. Together they embark on the worst elopement kidnapping elopement in history (per Belle, it’s not vainglorious to claim that when it’s true), and what ensues is a meditation on friendship, love, sexuality, identity, self-discovery, society, and home in a way that only Alexis Hall can do it.</description></item><item><title>The Duke at Hazard</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</guid><description>I have a few auto-buy (auto-preorder) authors, but KJ Charles is the only one where I drop everything to start reading the day a new book comes out. Here, that impatience is rewarded with a tender, slow-blooming romance-on-the-run between Daizell, a disgraced non-scoundrel scoundrel (he’s paying for the sins of his father), and Cassian, aka The Duke, aka Vernon Fortescue Cassian George de Vere Crosse, the fourth Duke of Severn, the Earl of Harmsford, Baron Crosse of Wotton, and Baron Vere, who’s incognito for a month to hunt down a thief and win a wager (he’s burdened with the premature inheritance of his father’s title).</description></item><item><title>Into the Riverlands</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/into-the-riverlands/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/into-the-riverlands/</guid><description>Our traveling cleric Chih wanders into a wuxia novel, crossing paths with a pair of martial sisters and a polyamorous triad of rogue cultivators (MORE FANFIC ON THAT PLS!). It’s a road trip novella, replete with multiple stories within a story, rumination on reality vs. myth, and Almost Brilliant being brilliant.</description></item><item><title>On the Fox Roads</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</guid><description>Nghi Vo can write [[books/the chosen and the beautiful|queer Jazz Age fanfic]] for me all day any day. (Also excellent: the Venn diagram of her Chinese and Vietnamese characters, the overlapping similarities and the differences.)</description></item></channel></rss>