<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cover-love on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/cover-love/</link><description>Recent content in cover-love on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/cover-love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mortal Follies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Black Tides of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</guid><description>Note from my future self: this makes an excellent prequel, I should have started with [[books/the red threads of fortune|book 2]]!</description></item><item><title>The Empress of Salt and Fortune</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-empress-of-salt-and-fortune/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-empress-of-salt-and-fortune/</guid><description>If you’re partial to storytelling as lush as this cover art, do not miss Nghi Vo. WOW.</description></item><item><title>A Marvellous Light</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</guid><description>Fun Edwardian murder mystery. Fun world building. God save Edwin from the idiotic flower of English manhood.</description></item><item><title>Parable of the Sower</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-sower/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-sower/</guid><description>I loved the Earthseed parts of this (God is Change), but the dystopia parts went the way of most dystopias for me, almost too limited in its imagination? It also feels like only half of a whole, so I think that’s part of it too. Will revisit these feelings after [[books/parable of the talents|Parable of the Talents]].</description></item><item><title>Shadow &amp; Claw</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadow-claw/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadow-claw/</guid><description>I think a series that has its own [[books/lexicon urthus|lexicon]] counts for the ultimate feat of [[notes/puzzle-book worldbuilding|puzzle-book worldbuilding]].</description></item><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>The Secret Lives of Country Gentlemen</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</guid><description>Update: Yep. [[books/a noblemans guide to seducing a scoundrel|Second book]] delivers the very necessary half of the whole. I adored it, and now I adore this one on re-read. Everything that just felt a slight step off pace the first time was solved with a deeper, closer read, and the addition of Luke’s story.</description></item><item><title>Slippery Creatures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</guid><description>My favorite KJ Charles yet.
I should probably wait till the end of the trilogy to make declarative statements, but there’s WWI spies and bookshops and gentle friendship despite odds and this is as far into my wheelhouse as you can get until, like, sheep herding or Belgium is involved.</description></item><item><title>The Red Threads of Fortune</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</guid><description>This should have been book 1! Or I should have done my typical thing of reading out of order and started here! The one time I try to be responsible and read a series in order, this is what happens.
Technically, these are “twin novellas,” but IMO, Mokoya is the emotional core of the story, followed by Rider, and Akeha in [[books/the black tides of heaven|Black Tides]] is an interesting prequel.</description></item><item><title>When the Tiger Came Down the Mountain</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/when-the-tiger-came-down-the-mountain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/when-the-tiger-came-down-the-mountain/</guid><description>Just as lush and complex as the [[books/the empress of salt and fortune|first one]], and given the smaller scope of the story, arguably my favorite of the two.</description></item><item><title>A Restless Truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</guid><description>This was so close to being great. SO CLOSE. But overall, the book felt kind of like the menagerie on board the ship, let loose in all directions, refusing to be corralled. There were some structure/plot/writing choices that left me more stumped than dazzled. Maud’s and Violet’s POV seemed really interchangeable for the first half, which is&amp;hellip; not great when one is a supposedly scandalous, sardonic, shrewd actress and one is a sheltered, capricious, stubborn young girl.</description></item><item><title>Parable of the Talents</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-talents/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-talents/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sword &amp; Citadel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sword-citadel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sword-citadel/</guid><description>Ugh, my [[notes/puzzle-book worldbuilding|puzzle-loving brain]] absolutely loved this. Even all the places where it was like, Gene, your Roman Catholicism is showing. And when apparently such brilliant flights of imagination can’t imagine a different role for women in the universe.
But the brilliant ideas were brilliant, and the execution thereof.</description></item><item><title>The Sugared Game</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</guid><description>The reason it takes me a week to read a book that I literally can’t put down is because I read it twice.
When I read [[books/slippery creatures|Slippery Creatures]], I wanted to say, this is what it looks like when an author levels up. I refrained, but I’m not going to wait til book three to say it: this is what it looks like when an author levels up.</description></item><item><title>A Power Unbound</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</guid><description>Here is my theory from [[books/a restless truth|book 2]]: the Blyths suit me best in small doses. Robin and Maud, respectively, were the most difficult parts of their own books for me. They’re just so young, energetic, athletic, upstanding, so shiny, so beautiful, so aggressively… “normal,” for lack of a better word, when I prefer crankiness and weariness and a bit of tarnish on the bronze these days.</description></item><item><title>Into the Riverlands</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/into-the-riverlands/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/into-the-riverlands/</guid><description>Our traveling cleric Chih wanders into a wuxia novel, crossing paths with a pair of martial sisters and a polyamorous triad of rogue cultivators (MORE FANFIC ON THAT PLS!). It’s a road trip novella, replete with multiple stories within a story, rumination on reality vs. myth, and Almost Brilliant being brilliant.</description></item><item><title>The Descent of Monsters</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</guid><description>So we’re completely changing protagonists AND writing style AND partially the genre too? Hell yes! Basically it’s the official report on the fallout of the [[books/the red threads of fortune|second book]], done epistolary style (with redactions!), introducing major revelations of its own.
Loved it. Definitely doesn’t stand on its own—don’t start here.</description></item><item><title>Subtle Blood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</guid><description>I might have accidentally read Subtle Blood again, since I might have accidentally experienced a vivid dream of Will, Kim, Phoebe, and Maisie on a Parisian adventure (cameo by Teddy Molyneaux, of course), and upon waking, might have accidentally been distraught that that book wasn’t going to exist.</description></item><item><title>Mammoths at the Gates</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mammoths-at-the-gates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:35:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mammoths-at-the-gates/</guid><description>Our beloved cleric Chih returns home to the Singing Hills monastery, only to find (spoiler alert) mammoths at the gates, an imperial delegation come to collect one of their own. A lovely mediation on grief, change, and love, through a plot revealed as always in the layers and sediment of myth.</description></item><item><title>The Brides of High Hill</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-brides-of-high-hill/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-brides-of-high-hill/</guid><description>Cleric Chih accompanies the bridal party of Pham Nhung to the estate of her potential husband, a man with monstrous secrets. For the first two acts, there are no stories-within-a-story, and no Almost Brilliant, in a way that indicates they’re connected—Chih keeps requesting to hear stories, but people refuse or prevaricate, until we miss the niexin as keenly as Chih does.</description></item><item><title>A Vindication of the Rights of Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-vindication-of-the-rights-of-woman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-vindication-of-the-rights-of-woman/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gender and Our Brains</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gender-and-our-brains/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gender-and-our-brains/</guid><description>The takeaway: 19th century biological essentialism is bunk (duh), and the majority of crappy research in neurology and biology has been undertaken to prove that women are inferior (yay!). We don’t even know what we don’t know, because the pseudoscience myths we’ve inherited will NOT die; but it’s a gendered world that produces a gendered brain, not our biology.</description></item><item><title>Perv</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perv/</guid><description>For the longest time, to be a pervert wasn’t to be a sex deviant; it was to be an atheist Almost overnight, “pervert” goes from “immoral religious heretic” to “immoral sexual deviant” because Havelock Ellis The [[notes/naturalistic fallacy|naturalistic fallacy]] of polyamory, homosexuality, etc. (a rebuttal to [[books/sex at dawn|Sex at Dawn]]) Instead of “natural” or “unnatural”: Is it harmful?</description></item><item><title>Carmilla</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:13:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</guid><description>I suppose I should be talking about the book, but Megan Follows does the audio, so my actual takeaway is: my Megan Follows crush has not abated after 25 years. The absolute perfect choice of narrator for a gothic, queer, melodramatic, erotically-charged tale.
![[images/megan-follows-aogg.gif]]
Note: I borrowed the audiobook from the library, but I’ve marked this Lanternfish Press edition because I also sought it out solely for the Carmen Maria Machado foreword, which is excellent and should not be missed.</description></item><item><title>We the Gathered Heat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:23:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</guid><description>Superb. This is how to do an anthology, where the disparate voices are the point—how do we even define AAPI except as “the other,” non-white? Who is the “we” in question? To whom is that category useful? The poems are sorted into themes of “mourn,” “pronounce,” “fight,” “love,” each as powerful as the last.</description></item><item><title>Emma of 83rd Street</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:43:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</guid><description>[[books/emma|Emma]] is my favorite [[authors/jane austen|Austen]], and arguably the most difficult to modernize without losing the spirit of the story.1 I don’t envy any author who attempts it, but this one lost me in the weeds, with pacing that seems twice the length of Austen with half the page count.</description></item><item><title>A Sorceress Comes to Call</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</guid><description>I’m here all day long for T. Kingfisher’s aging, aching protagonists, with bad knees and big hearts and a well-honed sense of doom. The plot is a very loose retelling of The Goose Girl, minus princesses and kings and plus a conniving, murderous, sorceress mother. Evangeline, aka Doom, is determined to marry herself and her trapped, obedient daughter to the highest bidders in proper Regency-esque fashion, plans thwarted when she encounters a squire’s spinster sister who sees her for exactly who she is.</description></item><item><title>The Emperor and the Endless Palace</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-emperor-and-the-endless-palace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-emperor-and-the-endless-palace/</guid><description>I kept my expectations low, and the writing shows promise on the sentence level—but on the plot/structure/worldbuilding/thematic level, it falls apart. There are plot twists that change the entire point of the story, but Huang doesn’t write like he knows that. (If there’s a second book, perhaps he plans to explore that further, but it doesn’t come together in this book.</description></item><item><title>The Palace of Eros</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</guid><description>My adjectives for the prose: purple, dense, florid, bloated. It sounds like I’m describing a corpse. DNF @ 15% because none of it is connecting with me, not the first-person Psyche nor the third-person Eros, nor the prose that’s turgid to the point of hyperbole. (Did I just want the chance to deploy the word turgid?</description></item><item><title>Gothic Tales</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Invisible Cities</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/invisible-cities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/invisible-cities/</guid><description>Still my least favorite Calvino, strange as that may seem when many people rank it his best. Let’s take it for granted that I’m weird and they’re right. It suffers more this time from [[books/kalpa imperial|Kalpa Imperial]], which has much the same vision but with people included.</description></item><item><title>Mr Palomar</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mr-palomar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mr-palomar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Six Memos for the Next Millennium</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/six-memos-for-the-next-millennium/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/six-memos-for-the-next-millennium/</guid><description>At this rate, this is the year of [[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula]] and Italo rearranging my thoughts, not to mention my reading and writing.</description></item><item><title>The Baron in the Trees</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-baron-in-the-trees/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-baron-in-the-trees/</guid><description>Calvinooooo. I don’t usually like parables unless they’re by Calvino, then they’re brilliant.</description></item><item><title>The Castle of Crossed Destinies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-castle-of-crossed-destinies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-castle-of-crossed-destinies/</guid><description>A lot of [[authors/ludovico ariosto|Ariosto]], a little of [[authors/giovanni boccaccio|Boccaccio]], a lot of Homer, Sophocles, and Shakespeare and a little of [[authors/dante alighieri|Dante]] too. Had I not been recently indulging in all of those authors, the story might have lost me, but now it’s just in good company.</description></item><item><title>The Cloven Viscount</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cloven-viscount/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cloven-viscount/</guid><description>Now this is how you do a fable. What a joy the language is, even in translation. Not to mention each character, good and bad alike, equal parts lovable and bizarre. [[books/the complete cosmicomics|Once again]], the only reason I’d want to have kids is to read them Calvino.</description></item><item><title>The Complete Cosmicomics</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-complete-cosmicomics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-complete-cosmicomics/</guid><description>I kind of want to make some babies right now, just so I can curl them up and read them the history of the universe according to Calvino.</description></item><item><title>The Road to San Giovanni</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-road-to-san-giovanni/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-road-to-san-giovanni/</guid><description>I have missed Calvino.</description></item><item><title>Blackouts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</guid><description>All the different layers of meaning to the title—the blackouts our narrator experiences due to PTSD, the blackouts of Juan and his fading memory, the failure of institutional memory, the queer erasure from history, the literal blackouts of the pages of the book. It feels like a work of art, not just a novel.</description></item><item><title>Liars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liars/</guid><description>Brilliant, merciless, couldn’t put it down. Jane marries John (Bridges, but might as well be Doe, for all the universality implied), and misery ensues as John exploits his masculine privilege and his own insecurities to make Jane’s life hell.
Written as autofiction with a dash of crime fiction, it’s an autopsy of a 21st century marriage between two (eventually wealthy) white straight people, who are best placed to reap the benefits of modern feminism and equality, and instead expose the grotesque flaws and inequalities.</description></item><item><title>A Green Equinox</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-green-equinox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-green-equinox/</guid><description>Sometimes you’re just in the mood for moody, queer af British novels with all the fraught gender politics and literary melodrama of the 1970’s. What can I say! So odd and compelling, like a fever dream. (Often literally, as there is an outbreak of typhoid that infects the course of the story.</description></item><item><title>Margo’s Got Money Troubles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</guid><description>20-year-old Margo sleeps with her professor, gets pregnant, keeps the baby, and discovers what a capitalist hellscape the U.S. is for mothers of all stripes, but particularly the unwed. Creating porn online becomes the only ethical way to survive, and this searing social commentary is wrapped up with so much humor and heart the book practically explodes with it.</description></item><item><title>Wintering</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</guid><description>DNF due to the health scare(s) both May and her husband experience at the beginning of the book. Even though I knew they were okay, it was too much to relive in the moment, my own recent family health scares too fresh. I skimmed ahead to see if I could just skip that part, but multiple other chapters failed to grab me.</description></item><item><title>Everyone Knows Your Mother Is a Witch</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</guid><description>Historical (fan)fiction of Katarina Kepler, Johannes Kepler’s mother, famously tried as a witch. It’s fantastic, the character work, the structure, the narrative voice(s), the exuberant black humor that becomes blacker and blacker as it follows the warp of history. An impressive example of what the genre can do, no boring litfic pretentiousness here.</description></item><item><title>Gwen &amp; Art Are Not in Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</guid><description>I think it wobbled a smiiiidge on the landing, a few things felt abrupt and/or undercooked, not to mention the jarring tonal shift into violence, but the ride to get there was super fun. There’s some fade-to-black, hand-wavey, don’t-think-too-hard-about-this energy re: the whole premature-inheritance, fix-a-broken-system-from-the-inside plan, but it is YA, and I wasn’t expecting an [[books/bitter|Akwaeke Emezi-level thesis]] on the subject of institutional power.</description></item><item><title>The Found and the Lost</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-found-and-the-lost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-found-and-the-lost/</guid><description>Le Guin is the master of the novella. Each of these stories contains a universe; even the stories meant to expand the worlds she’s created in her [[series/hainish cycle|Hainish]] and [[series/earthsea cycle|Earthsea]] cycles, they feel complete unto themselves.
And the shape of each story—it’s her [[notes/the carrier bag theory of fiction|carrier bag theory of fiction]] in practice.</description></item><item><title>The Unreal and the Real</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-unreal-and-the-real/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-unreal-and-the-real/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Three Kings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</guid><description>Another for my collection of killer opening lines:
Ethan Shaw carried two knives, one for lilies, the other for veins.
And the book just gets better and better from there. It counters all my usual problems with cozy witchy books, and sometimes cozy fantasy in general, not to mention the fraught subject of fertility.</description></item><item><title>Exodus 20</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:55:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</guid><description>If you’re gonna write monster kink, make it a biblically accurate angel. And throw in some searing social/political/theological commentary. This was excellent.</description></item><item><title>Aspects</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/aspects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/aspects/</guid><description>The poignancy of having this one cut off, incomplete. What a feat it would have been. What a feat it still is. The [[notes/puzzle-book worldbuilding|worldbuilding]] is out of this world.</description></item><item><title>Fledgling</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fledgling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fledgling/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Lathe Of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</guid><description>I can’t remember the last time I read a book with a truly passive protagonist, where his qualities are not his weakness, but his strength. He doesn’t change who he is. There is no lesson needed. He is the virtue, not the flaw. Le Guin stacks George Orr up against the passionate Huber who wants to save the world, and carefully and thoroughly makes the case for the former.</description></item><item><title>What My Bones Know</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-my-bones-know/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-my-bones-know/</guid><description>Incredible memoir. One of the best books I’ve read about healing from abuse, dysfunction, and trauma. So much to relate to on every page (and not just because she had the same Jimmy Eat World song as a lifeline in the early aughts).
It’s heartbreaking and eye-opening that her upbringing (Asian, middle-class, immigrant; raised in what she correctly calls the wreckage of America’s brutal proxy wars against communism) is almost a 1:1 overlap with what was going on behind the scenes for almost everyone I knew growing up (white, middle-class, evangelical; basically the inheritors of the “American dream”).</description></item><item><title>Unreal Sex</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unreal-sex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unreal-sex/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Band Sinister</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</guid><description>If this isn’t everything that’s wholesome and good in the world, I don’t know what is. A tribute to Heyer indeed; it just includes those who paint with oils outside conventional lines. It cranked my heart open without being saccharine or heavy. One of those books where I have to be careful what I read next because it might not measure up.</description></item><item><title>Annals of the Former World</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/annals-of-the-former-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/annals-of-the-former-world/</guid><description>I’m glad I’m not beyond the age where books I read can change the way I see the world. If that is an age you can reach, I don’t want to. I can’t even drive down the highway now without seeing something as simple as roadcuts in a whole different light.</description></item><item><title>If On A Winter’s Night A Traveler</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/if-on-a-winters-night-a-traveler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/if-on-a-winters-night-a-traveler/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>