<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wholesome-af on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/wholesome-af/</link><description>Recent content in wholesome-af on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/wholesome-af/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Rat-Catcher’s Daughter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</guid><description>Very sweet and dare I say necessary before [[books/gilded cage|Gilded Cage]]. It has some pretty key context. And come on—that title.</description></item><item><title>The Duke at Hazard</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</guid><description>I have a few auto-buy (auto-preorder) authors, but KJ Charles is the only one where I drop everything to start reading the day a new book comes out. Here, that impatience is rewarded with a tender, slow-blooming romance-on-the-run between Daizell, a disgraced non-scoundrel scoundrel (he’s paying for the sins of his father), and Cassian, aka The Duke, aka Vernon Fortescue Cassian George de Vere Crosse, the fourth Duke of Severn, the Earl of Harmsford, Baron Crosse of Wotton, and Baron Vere, who’s incognito for a month to hunt down a thief and win a wager (he’s burdened with the premature inheritance of his father’s title).</description></item><item><title>There Will Be Phlogiston</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/there-will-be-phlogiston/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/there-will-be-phlogiston/</guid><description>Well fuck, now [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] has competition for most wholesome ever. So short, and so tender, so full of power and beauty.</description></item><item><title>Band Sinister</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</guid><description>If this isn’t everything that’s wholesome and good in the world, I don’t know what is. A tribute to Heyer indeed; it just includes those who paint with oils outside conventional lines. It cranked my heart open without being saccharine or heavy. One of those books where I have to be careful what I read next because it might not measure up.</description></item><item><title>Experienced</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</guid><description>Bette gets dumped-but-not-dumped in truly shitty fashion by her girlfriend, who suggests she just needs more experience since she’s newly out as a lesbian. Commence a sex odyssey through the wilds of Bristol, aided by her first failed date of the odyssey, the kind and thoughtful Ruth.</description></item><item><title>Margo’s Got Money Troubles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</guid><description>20-year-old Margo sleeps with her professor, gets pregnant, keeps the baby, and discovers what a capitalist hellscape the U.S. is for mothers of all stripes, but particularly the unwed. Creating porn online becomes the only ethical way to survive, and this searing social commentary is wrapped up with so much humor and heart the book practically explodes with it.</description></item></channel></rss>