<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>horror on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/horror/</link><description>Recent content in horror on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/horror/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beneath the Rising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/beneath-the-rising/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/beneath-the-rising/</guid><description>The coincidence of snagging this series on sale1 the night before I finished [[books/rakesfall|Rakesfall]], where [[authors/vajra chandrasekera|Vajra Chandrasekera]] names Premee Mohamed in his acknowledgments.
Indeed, it plays on similar themes, albeit in an entirely different style. Here we’ve got an action-adventure race across the continents when Johnny, young super-genius inventor/do-gooder in a kind of Greta Thurnberg mold, accidentally creates such a powerful clean energy reactor that it warps space and time and calls up eldritch gods from the deep… which she knows full well because she’s made a deal with those same gods to exchange her mortality for the fame and brains to save the world.</description></item><item><title>What Moves the Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</guid><description>Just what I wanted for October: brilliant gothic fanfiction of The Fall of the House of Usher with even more fungi than Poe. Creepy and exquisite, and that’s not just the cover art.
(With a bonus Beatrix Potter relative, clever worldbuilding linguistics w/r/t gender, and a hat tip to Prisoner of Zenda!</description></item><item><title>What Feasts at Night</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-feasts-at-night/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-feasts-at-night/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Frankenstein; or, the Modern Prometheus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/frankenstein/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/frankenstein/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Someone You Can Build a Nest In</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/someone-you-can-build-a-nest-in/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/someone-you-can-build-a-nest-in/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Never Whistle at Night</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/never-whistle-at-night/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/never-whistle-at-night/</guid><description>As awesome as the cover. I agree with Stephen Graham Jones, who writes the foreword, that the cream of the current horror crop is written by indigenous authors.
“But what feels like an even better explanation for why we tend to like our stories to end like that, with bleeding over, bleeding across, haunting us, it’s that it feels kind of fake and wrong and all too American to throw up walls between what’s real and what’s maybe not real.</description></item><item><title>The Salt Grows Heavy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</guid><description>Truly grisly horror with a truly touching love story. Most fairytale retellings (here, The Little Mermaid) course-correct from the Disney versions back to Hans Christian Andersen territory. This overshoots Andersen by quite some distance, landing in the realm of rapacious colonizers and ghoulish Mengele-style war crimes.</description></item><item><title>A House With Good Bones</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-house-with-good-bones/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-house-with-good-bones/</guid><description>Yay, vultures save the day! A horror novel where racist grandmothers and roses are the problem, not the bugs and the vultures. That, along with the fantastic characters and very specific (and accurate!) North Carolina setting, makes this spooky book a treat.
(Out of 247 pages, I have 152 highlights—mostly lols, entomologist rants, and perfect encapsulations of NC life.</description></item><item><title>Carmilla</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:13:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</guid><description>I suppose I should be talking about the book, but Megan Follows does the audio, so my actual takeaway is: my Megan Follows crush has not abated after 25 years. The absolute perfect choice of narrator for a gothic, queer, melodramatic, erotically-charged tale.
![[images/megan-follows-aogg.gif]]
Note: I borrowed the audiobook from the library, but I’ve marked this Lanternfish Press edition because I also sought it out solely for the Carmen Maria Machado foreword, which is excellent and should not be missed.</description></item><item><title>Come Out, Come Out</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</guid><description>In the same niche as [[books/camp damascus|Camp Damascus]], the conversion-therapy-as-horror genre. Similarities abound, even down to the senior class quarry jumps, which doesn’t indicate any co-opting of plot points but simply how ubiquitous this experience is, the same script across rural America, where any deviation from the script means there will be Consequences.</description></item><item><title>Earthlings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earthlings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earthlings/</guid><description>You could put trigger warnings on this book for child abuse, incest, and cannibalism(!!), and still the anguish of being forced to conform to society—“The Factory”—at the expense of all well-being forms the core of the horror. Particularly how women are reduced to wombs like mechanical components.</description></item><item><title>Camp Damascus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</guid><description>I had to wait until I was in a good headspace to handle this. Ruth, an autistic devout Christian on the cusp of adulthood, begins to realize everything in her life is not as it seems, not even herself. Cue the horror of religious trauma and conversion therapy camps, right at home with the traditional trappings of the horror genre.</description></item><item><title>The Price of Meat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</guid><description>Maybe don’t read this over lunch like I did? By which I mean, it’s fanfic of Sweeney Todd, it’s grisly horror, and it’s very good and effective, because KJ Charles. She can write anything from [[books/band sinister|Georgette Heyer homages]] to penny dreadfuls and it’s worth the ink.</description></item></channel></rss>