<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>neurodivergent on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/neurodivergent/</link><description>Recent content in neurodivergent on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/neurodivergent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Marvellous Light</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</guid><description>Fun Edwardian murder mystery. Fun world building. God save Edwin from the idiotic flower of English manhood.</description></item><item><title>Iris Kelly Doesn’t Date</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</guid><description>Yes to the gender-bending production of Much Ado About Nothing; yes to practice dating and sex lessons. Beyond that, the plot was a hot mess for me, trying to both validate Iris’s singledom yet ultimately get her in a relationship. I appreciate that Blake acknowledged the difficulty of walking that tightrope, and it is a rom-com—of course it’s gonna be an HEA.</description></item><item><title>Untypical</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/untypical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/untypical/</guid><description>Part memoir of a late-diagnosed autistic person (straight white British male version); part comprehensive outline of accommodations that would make the world a safer, more autistic-friendly place. Some are so laughably trivial that it’s shameful they even have to be requested in the first place—but alas, that’s the world we live in.</description></item><item><title>Is This Autism?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/is-this-autism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/is-this-autism/</guid><description>Once again I have read my way up from beginner to clinical level on a subject in the space of a year. I’m going to make a declarative statement that this is currently the best resource out there, full stop, on ASD and the myriad of ways it presents.</description></item><item><title>The Autistic Survival Guide to Therapy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autistic-survival-guide-to-therapy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autistic-survival-guide-to-therapy/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wintering</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</guid><description>DNF due to the health scare(s) both May and her husband experience at the beginning of the book. Even though I knew they were okay, it was too much to relive in the moment, my own recent family health scares too fresh. I skimmed ahead to see if I could just skip that part, but multiple other chapters failed to grab me.</description></item><item><title>Gwen &amp; Art Are Not in Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</guid><description>I think it wobbled a smiiiidge on the landing, a few things felt abrupt and/or undercooked, not to mention the jarring tonal shift into violence, but the ride to get there was super fun. There’s some fade-to-black, hand-wavey, don’t-think-too-hard-about-this energy re: the whole premature-inheritance, fix-a-broken-system-from-the-inside plan, but it is YA, and I wasn’t expecting an [[books/bitter|Akwaeke Emezi-level thesis]] on the subject of institutional power.</description></item><item><title>Everyone in This Room Will Someday Be Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:21:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</guid><description>This is the most strongly coded [[notes/autism|autistic]] protagonist I’ve read. Especially of the female, high-masking, chronic burnout variety, and undiagnosed. (Or rather, insufficiently diagnosed with anxiety and depression.) The unconscious stimming! Chronic sensory overload! The shutdowns! The meltdowns! The masking!
I feel like I am operating my body like it’s a vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Interesting Facts about Space</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</guid><description>Me [page 1]: I’m worried I read too much about [[notes/autism|ASD]] into [[books/everyone in this room will someday be dead|Everyone in This Room Will Someday be Dead]]. This time I’m gonna look for all the ways it’s not autism. I will counteract my bias.
Me [page 20]: This is autism.</description></item><item><title>Camp Damascus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</guid><description>I had to wait until I was in a good headspace to handle this. Ruth, an autistic devout Christian on the cusp of adulthood, begins to realize everything in her life is not as it seems, not even herself. Cue the horror of religious trauma and conversion therapy camps, right at home with the traditional trappings of the horror genre.</description></item><item><title>One Day I’ll Grow Up and Be a Beautiful Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</guid><description>Nonfiction memoir about a mother raising her autistic, transgender daughter and the New Hampshire town that puts their family through hell. A harrowing and heartbreaking survival guide (barely? hopefully?) about weathering the eye of the current political storm. I’m always looking for books I can recommend to well-meaning people who want to see past the transphobic headlines, and this one goes on the list.</description></item></channel></rss>