<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sexuality on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/sexuality/</link><description>Recent content in sexuality on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/sexuality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bisexuality might be erotic plasticity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bisexuality-might-be-erotic-plasticity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bisexuality-might-be-erotic-plasticity/</guid><description>More women tend to be bisexual, or fluid with how they label their sexuality. Some of the conflict between saying sexuality is a choice might be this erotic plasticity.
In fact, women in general are far more likely than men to report being bisexual. Tellingly, they’re also more likely to change their self-identification as straight or gay during their adult lives.</description></item><item><title>Kink is the new vanilla</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/kink-is-the-new-vanilla/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/kink-is-the-new-vanilla/</guid><description>It’s funny, I’ve seen scattered comments lately, mostly on the r/romancelandia and r/ao3 subreddits, of people saying they prefer vanilla/chaste/closed door stories now because kink is basically the norm, so therefore predictable and boring.
Just like any sex scene, kink alone does not make it interesting or good—I’ve read absolutely dire representations of kink.</description></item><item><title>Our sense of the erotic is more plastic than we think</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-sense-of-the-erotic-is-more-plastic-than-we-think/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-sense-of-the-erotic-is-more-plastic-than-we-think/</guid><description>How fluid is our sense of the erotic? Like neurological plasticity, probably a lot more fluid than we think.
Whether it involves livestock or people, this sexual-imprinting process (in which a highly circumscribed set of erotic targets is stamped early into the individual’s brain) appears to be a decidedly male characteristic.</description></item></channel></rss>