<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>activism-and-resistence on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/activism-and-resistence/</link><description>Recent content in activism-and-resistence on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/activism-and-resistence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Black Tides of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</guid><description>Note from my future self: this makes an excellent prequel, I should have started with [[books/the red threads of fortune|book 2]]!</description></item><item><title>Parable of the Sower</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-sower/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/parable-of-the-sower/</guid><description>I loved the Earthseed parts of this (God is Change), but the dystopia parts went the way of most dystopias for me, almost too limited in its imagination? It also feels like only half of a whole, so I think that’s part of it too. Will revisit these feelings after [[books/parable of the talents|Parable of the Talents]].</description></item><item><title>Seven Surrenders</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</guid><description>There’s no way I can talk comprehensively about this series, so for now I’m just going to keep a running list of different things I notice each time I read them. This time (2/2023), it was how the many names for JEDD Mason echoes the [[notes/apophatic naming|apophatic naming]] of God, a classical theological strategy of the “negative” naming, an effort to call God by every time, thereby acknowledging and preserving God’s transcendence of all of them.</description></item><item><title>The Will to Battle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</guid><description>Reader, I cried like Mycroft Canner. It’s very much the first half of a whole (third quarter of four?), and it needs [[books/perhaps the stars|the last book]] to be complete, but what a feat it is on its own.</description></item><item><title>A Seditious Affair</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</guid><description>This was my first KJ Charles, purchased and read—I just looked it up—March 2017. I then read the whole series (out of order, of course), re-read this one in 2018, again in 2019, and somehow reviewed nary a one before 2020.
I feel so sentimental.</description></item><item><title>Perhaps the Stars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</guid><description>I still haven’t found the words to talk about this one. Maybe next year I will. It should be in the Smithsonian, or win the Nobel prize, or something, as one of humanity’s greatest achievements.</description></item><item><title>A Gentleman’s Position</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-gentlemans-position/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-gentlemans-position/</guid><description>It’s the favorite recurring KJ Charles theme: sometimes you just need a villain instead of a hero. See [[books/wanted a gentleman|Wanted, A Gentleman]] or [[books/the henchmen of zenda|Henchmen of Zenda]], et. al. My love language is elaborate schemes by crafty bastards, so you can guess how happy I was by the end.</description></item><item><title>The Dispossessed</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dispossessed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dispossessed/</guid><description>Sublime. Carefully constructed, nuanced, warmly empathetic, passionately human, complex. If you want a rose-colored ideologue that purports to fix problems with simplistic utopias, look elsewhere. If you want an accounting of our society’s ills, and alternatives that are just as complicated and imperfect, you’re in the right place.</description></item><item><title>A Natural History of Homosexuality</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-natural-history-of-homosexuality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-natural-history-of-homosexuality/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Forest of Noise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</guid><description>How do you write the unimaginable? How do you craft art from the horror? How do you count your loved ones, now dead, in lines of poems?
I read this twice, once fast, once slow, and let it break me. 50 years of occupation and apartheid.</description></item><item><title>On Genocide</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-genocide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-genocide/</guid><description>Sartre in 1967:
When a peasant falls in his rice paddy, mowed down by a machine gun, every one of us is hit. The Vietnamese fight for all men and the American forces against all. Neither figuratively nor abstractly. And not only because genocide would be a crime universally condemned by international law, but because little by little the whole human race is being subjected to this genocidal blackmail piled on top of atomic blackmail, that is, to absolute, total war.</description></item><item><title>On Palestine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</guid><description>Many of the world’s problems are so intractable that it’s hard to think of ways even to take steps toward mitigating them.
The Israel-Palestine conflict is not one of these.
I admit I’ve fallen prey to the line, re: the occupation of Palestine, “it’s too complex to understand.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>The Saint of Bright Doors</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</guid><description>Gobsmacked at how good this is, without even the caveat of “for a first novel.” Fetter, the feral only child of a messiah, trained by his mother as assassin, destined to commit matricide and fratricide, navigates a dystopian Sri Lanka far too recognizable in the present.</description></item><item><title>Abolish Rent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</guid><description>An enthusiastic and persuasive manifesto on housing rights as human rights. It’s encouraging to see such robust organizing among tenants across the country, and the practical template for how to expand it. The authors rightly quote [[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula Le Guin]]: our housing system is a human power—produced by people, not God or nature.</description></item><item><title>Sister Outsider</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sister-outsider/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sister-outsider/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Vindication of the Rights of Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-vindication-of-the-rights-of-woman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-vindication-of-the-rights-of-woman/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mutual Aid</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mutual-aid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mutual-aid/</guid><description>In an explicit riposte to social Darwinists, Kropotkin argues against the theories that emphasize competition and survival of the fittest, and against the romantic depictions by writers such as [[authors/jean-jacques rousseau|Jean-Jacques Rousseau]], who thought that cooperation was motivated by universal love. Instead, he spoke for an alternative school of Darwinism that emerged in Russia, emphasizing cooperation, not competition, as the driver of evolutionary change.</description></item><item><title>We the Gathered Heat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:23:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</guid><description>Superb. This is how to do an anthology, where the disparate voices are the point—how do we even define AAPI except as “the other,” non-white? Who is the “we” in question? To whom is that category useful? The poems are sorted into themes of “mourn,” “pronounce,” “fight,” “love,” each as powerful as the last.</description></item><item><title>Our History Is the Future</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/our-history-is-the-future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/our-history-is-the-future/</guid><description>An excellent re-issue of a book that&amp;rsquo;s been on my to-read list since it first published in 2019. I&amp;rsquo;m glad it finally prompted me to get to it. It’s the history of two centuries of indigenous activism in the context of even broader indigenous exploitation and resistance, and it needs to be more widely known.</description></item><item><title>Freak Pleasures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/freak-pleasures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/freak-pleasures/</guid><description>Now this is protest art. Specifically, the protest of SESTA/FOSTA and the censorship it entails, not to mention the way it endangers those it purports to protect.
Available here: https://claystorks.itch.io/freak-pleasures</description></item><item><title>The Chosen and the Beautiful</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</guid><description>As someone who has long loved [[authors/f scott fitzgerald|F. Scott Fitzgerald]]’s writing, despite his depressing and often problematic deal, this [[books/the great gatsby|Gatsby]] retelling vis-à-vis a Vietnamese Jordan Baker is exquisite. Absolutely true to the spirit of the original, while absolutely its own fantastical, queer, eerie, spectacular thing.</description></item><item><title>China Mountain Zhang</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Emergent Strategy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emergent-strategy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emergent-strategy/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Octavia’s Brood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/octavias-brood/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/octavias-brood/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pleasure Activism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pleasure-activism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pleasure-activism/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Lathe Of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</guid><description>I can’t remember the last time I read a book with a truly passive protagonist, where his qualities are not his weakness, but his strength. He doesn’t change who he is. There is no lesson needed. He is the virtue, not the flaw. Le Guin stacks George Orr up against the passionate Huber who wants to save the world, and carefully and thoroughly makes the case for the former.</description></item><item><title>The Right to Maim</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-right-to-maim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 14:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-right-to-maim/</guid><description>In The Right to Maim Jasbir K. Puar brings her pathbreaking work on the liberal state, sexuality, and biopolitics to bear on our understanding of disability. Drawing on a stunning array of theoretical and methodological frameworks, Puar uses the concept of “debility”—bodily injury and social exclusion brought on by economic and political factors—to disrupt the category of disability.</description></item><item><title>The Origins of Totalitarianism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-origins-of-totalitarianism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-origins-of-totalitarianism/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wanted, A Gentleman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</guid><description>She had me at “gothic novelist” and “lonely hearts columnist.” This is wonderful. I love it when Charles just unleashes her id.
Note: I’m including the epilogue Wanted, an Author, in which Corvin from [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] makes a cameo and Theo’s gay gothic erotica novel Jonathan: or The Struggles of Virtue is at the top of my list for books-within-a-book that I most need to read.</description></item><item><title>William Blake: The Complete Illuminated Books</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/william-blake-the-complete-illuminated-books/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/william-blake-the-complete-illuminated-books/</guid><description>Reading Blake, I always get the sense he’s working in a fever, trying to translate an ecstatic vision for us mortals. I saw someone call him the original troll—that too, the radical printmaker in the time when printmaking was a real threat to the established order.</description></item><item><title>Unfit to Print</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unfit-to-print/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unfit-to-print/</guid><description>Print shop feels! Plus the Victorian porn trade! And yes to showing this side of British colonialism, even if that could stand to be fleshed out a bit.</description></item><item><title>Health Communism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/health-communism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/health-communism/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Duchess War</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duchess-war/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 22:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duchess-war/</guid><description>Finally I didn’t bounce off a Courtney Milan! Granted, the Norfolk Southern disaster had me in the mood to read about labor organizing, and that part worked for me better than the romance.
(In theory, I liked Minnie and Robert together, but they didn’t make me feel it, you know.</description></item><item><title>I’m Sorry for My Loss</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/im-sorry-for-my-loss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/im-sorry-for-my-loss/</guid><description>I know a book is going to be good when it starts off with the way language limits or distorts our understanding of a subject. Recommended to absolutely anyone, with or without a uterus, with or without the intention to procreate. It’s ostensibly about pregnancy loss and miscarriage/stillbirth awareness, but that overlaps with many things—abortion, grief, medical misogyny, racial injustice, human rights.</description></item><item><title>One Day I’ll Grow Up and Be a Beautiful Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</guid><description>Nonfiction memoir about a mother raising her autistic, transgender daughter and the New Hampshire town that puts their family through hell. It’s harrowing and heartbreaking, a survival guide (barely? hopefully?) about weathering the eye of the current political storm.a I’m always looking for books I can recommend to well-meaning people who want to see past the transphobic headlines, and this one goes on the list.</description></item></channel></rss>