<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cptsd on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/cptsd/</link><description>Recent content in cptsd on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 23:57:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/cptsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Paris Daillencourt is About to Crumble</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</guid><description>Once again Alexis Hall takes away the book I thought I wanted and replaces it with the book I actually need.
Reading this at the same time as [[books/the body keeps the score|The Body Keeps the Score]], though, just means I’m peeking between the lines of all the parental neglect and trauma and thinking, dearest Paris, get thee to some somatic therapy, medication is just a start.</description></item><item><title>Blackouts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</guid><description>All the different layers of meaning to the title—the blackouts our narrator experiences due to PTSD, the blackouts of Juan and his fading memory, the failure of institutional memory, the queer erasure from history, the literal blackouts of the pages of the book. It feels like a work of art, not just a novel.</description></item><item><title>Earthlings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earthlings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earthlings/</guid><description>You could put trigger warnings on this book for child abuse, incest, and cannibalism(!!), and still the anguish of being forced to conform to society—“The Factory”—at the expense of all well-being forms the core of the horror. Particularly how women are reduced to wombs like mechanical components.</description></item><item><title>Clear and Muddy Loss of Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</guid><description>This is just what I was in the mood for, a 300+ chapter, 4000 page sapphic slow burn court intrigue. The prose (and/or translation?) is more functional than beautiful on a sentence level, but on a plot level, with the overall character arcs, QJMX has some mad skill.</description></item><item><title>Everyone in This Room Will Someday Be Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:21:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</guid><description>This is the most strongly coded [[notes/autism|autistic]] protagonist I’ve read. Especially of the female, high-masking, chronic burnout variety, and undiagnosed. (Or rather, insufficiently diagnosed with anxiety and depression.) The unconscious stimming! Chronic sensory overload! The shutdowns! The meltdowns! The masking!
I feel like I am operating my body like it’s a vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Interesting Facts about Space</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</guid><description>Me [page 1]: I’m worried I read too much about [[notes/autism|ASD]] into [[books/everyone in this room will someday be dead|Everyone in This Room Will Someday be Dead]]. This time I’m gonna look for all the ways it’s not autism. I will counteract my bias.
Me [page 20]: This is autism.</description></item><item><title>The Body Keeps the Score</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-body-keeps-the-score/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-body-keeps-the-score/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What My Bones Know</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-my-bones-know/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-my-bones-know/</guid><description>Incredible memoir. One of the best books I’ve read about healing from abuse, dysfunction, and trauma. So much to relate to on every page (and not just because she had the same Jimmy Eat World song as a lifeline in the early aughts).
It’s heartbreaking and eye-opening that her upbringing (Asian, middle-class, immigrant; raised in what she correctly calls the wreckage of America’s brutal proxy wars against communism) is almost a 1:1 overlap with what was going on behind the scenes for almost everyone I knew growing up (white, middle-class, evangelical; basically the inheritors of the “American dream”).</description></item><item><title>Something’s Not Right</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/somethings-not-right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/somethings-not-right/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>