<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bias on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/bias/</link><description>Recent content in bias on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/bias/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anatomy of a propaganda blitz</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</guid><description>Copying this straight from [[books/propaganda blitz|Propaganda Blitz]] ([[authors/david edwards|David Edwards]] and [[authors/david cromwell|David Cromwell]]) because it’s immensely helpful to reference.
Propaganda blitzes are fast-moving attacks intended to inflict maximum damage in minimum time. They are:
based on allegations of dramatic new evidence communicated with high emotional intensity and moral outrage apparently supported by an informed corporate media/academic/expert consensus reinforced by damning condemnation of anyone daring even to question the apparent consensus often generated with fortuitous timing characterised by tragicomic moral dissonance Every one of these things, much less the concatenation of all of them, signals red flag, red flag, red flag.</description></item><item><title>All of us are embedded in our own safe “reality”</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-of-us-are-embedded-in-our-own-safe-reality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-of-us-are-embedded-in-our-own-safe-reality/</guid><description>All of us are embedded in our own safe “reality,” shaping what we see and know in ways of which we are completely unaware.
Many circumstances conspire to extinguish scientific discoveries, especially those that cause discomfort about our culture’s sacred norms. As a species, we cling to the familiar, comforting conformities of the mainstream.</description></item><item><title>The human mind mistakes its opinions for truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-human-mind-mistakes-its-opinions-for-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-human-mind-mistakes-its-opinions-for-truth/</guid><description>I think of it like this: we’re always missing data. Our equations can never be perfect because, much like the cloud of probability in quantum physics, we can never have all the data. The people I trust most are the ones who know this, and act accordingly.</description></item><item><title>Our best defense against stupidity is diversity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-best-defense-against-stupidity-is-diversity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-best-defense-against-stupidity-is-diversity/</guid><description>Appealing as it is want an expert in charge, the last thing we need is a committee of enlightened despots ruling the world. Tyranny is still tyranny even when the tyrants have high IQs and the right diplomas on the wall.
In college, I knew this guy who was always talking about how the world should be ruled by a “panel of experts.</description></item><item><title>The most hideous ideologies are the ones we believe without realizing it</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-most-hideous-ideologies-are-the-ones-we-believe-without-realizing-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-most-hideous-ideologies-are-the-ones-we-believe-without-realizing-it/</guid><description>Hey! Here’s a thought! Do not yearn for the authoritarian school of social change! Do not force your ideas on anyone else! 💀
I love people, but a lot of them—maybe most?—yearn for their side to acquire absolute power. They seem to believe in the authoritarian school of social change: the only way to create a better world is for a strong central actor to force it on everybody else.</description></item><item><title>Thinking people are stupid is the gateway drug to worse ideas</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-people-are-stupid-is-the-gateway-drug-to-worse-ideas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-people-are-stupid-is-the-gateway-drug-to-worse-ideas/</guid><description>I’m highly allergic to the idea that other people are fundamentally stupid. It’s one small, flimsy step away from dehumanizing people completely, and once anyone is dehumanized, that leads to a lot of worse ideas.
If we can go from “only kings and dukes could possibly become less stupid” to “anybody can become less stupid,” maybe we can make it all the way to “people aren’t fundamentally stupid to begin with.</description></item><item><title>Cognitive biases don’t prove we’re bad at thinking</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cognitive-biases-dont-prove-were-bad-at-thinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cognitive-biases-dont-prove-were-bad-at-thinking/</guid><description>Instead of illustrating how stupid people are, cognitive biases actually show how much work our brain is doing to make us good at thinking. Visual illusions can fool the eye with clever tricks, and cognitive illusions can do the same, helping us understand how the mind works and how the mind breaks.</description></item></channel></rss>