<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>emotional-intelligence on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/emotional-intelligence/</link><description>Recent content in emotional-intelligence on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/emotional-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The indigenous ways of knowing</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-ways-of-knowing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-ways-of-knowing/</guid><description>Native scholar Greg Cajete has written that in indigenous ways of knowing, ==we understand a thing only when we understand it with all four aspects of our being: mind, body, emotion, and spirit.== I came to understand quite sharply when I began my training as a scientist that science privileges only one, possibly two, of those ways of knowing: mind and body.</description></item><item><title>Censorship does not make the ideas we disagree with go away</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/censorship-does-not-make-the-ideas-we-disagree-with-go-away/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/censorship-does-not-make-the-ideas-we-disagree-with-go-away/</guid><description>It strikes me how much facing bad things we disagree with is like facing the “bad” emotions we refuse to acknowledge. What we can’t face doesn’t go away—it festers and comes out in much worse ways.
Curiosity is always the answer. Curiosity and addressing the root cause in a meaningful way.</description></item><item><title>Core values</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/core-values/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/core-values/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Emodiversity is a sign of well-being</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emodiversity-is-a-sign-of-well-being/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emodiversity-is-a-sign-of-well-being/</guid><description>Experiencing a broad range of emotions, aka “emodiversity,” is more significant to wellness than happiness. The more we feel, the less we resist feeling, which leads to states of chronic stress and inflammation.
In 2017, positive psychology researchers published findings that suggested emodiversity—which they defined as “the breadth and relative abundance of emotions that individuals experience”—is more significant to wellness than happiness.</description></item><item><title>Emotions are experienced individually and collectively</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotions-are-experienced-individually-and-collectively/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotions-are-experienced-individually-and-collectively/</guid><description>From [[books/tarot for change|Tarot for Change]], [[authors/jessica dore|Jessica Dore]]:
But with emotions, it’s not always clear who “owns” them. I’ve woken up heavy with the boulder of my grandmother’s grief on my chest, breathed deeply while sweating from the fire of my mother’s rage, and I could say, “That’s theirs, not mine,” if I wanted to, but what good would that do?</description></item><item><title>The boundary is a meeting place</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-boundary-is-a-meeting-place/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-boundary-is-a-meeting-place/</guid><description>Instead of only viewing a boundary as a limit, what if we also view it as a meeting place? Therefore the boundary is doubly necessary—to meet people where they are, we must be where we are, not overextending ourselves into places we don’t belong.
This happens internally too.</description></item><item><title>The importance of anger</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-importance-of-anger/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-importance-of-anger/</guid><description>From [[books/tarot for change|Tarot for Change]], [[authors/jessica dore|Jessica Dore]]:
Validating fury in ourselves and others isn’t simply a means to an end of making it go away—==if your goal is to squash it, you’re not really validating anything.== Evolutionary psychology researchers have suggested a thing called ==the recalibration theory of anger==, which suggests that anger evolved to help us increase our social bargaining power and ensure that we demand better deals for ourselves when we’ve either been slighted or might be again.</description></item><item><title>Trust is a very simple thing</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/trust-is-a-very-simple-thing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:01:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/trust-is-a-very-simple-thing/</guid><description>I often hear the line now, “when someone shows you who they are, believe them.” It’s come up in therapy, it’s shared online a lot. I hope that means it’s becoming common knowledge, because it often really is that simple: trust is simple and usually very obvious.</description></item><item><title>Fear is a natural reaction to moving closer to the truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fear-is-a-natural-reaction-to-moving-closer-to-the-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fear-is-a-natural-reaction-to-moving-closer-to-the-truth/</guid><description>It’s amazing how much we fear fear, when there is no more universal experience. If we can get that little bit of space between it, allow the fear to exist and listen to it, underneath that is something very soft and tender and honest, the core of what it means to be alive.</description></item><item><title>The righting reflex</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-righting-reflex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:09:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-righting-reflex/</guid><description>From [[books/tarot for change|Tarot for Change]], [[authors/jessica dore|Jessica Dore]]:
The primary task in all healing relationships—such as that between a therapist and client—is to listen deeply. Conversely, traumatic relationships are ones in which people consistently deny, overlook, and avoid each other’s truths.
I first learned of exquisite empathy as a graduate student seeking ways to cope with the overwhelming grief and anguish I was bearing witness to as an intern at a community mental health agency in an under-resourced community.</description></item><item><title>Vorfreude</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vorfreude/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vorfreude/</guid><description>The German word vorfruede has no English equivalent. It comes from the words vor (“before”) and Freude (“joy”) and means something along the lines of “joyful anticipation.”
Often “vorfreude” is characterized as childish anticipation. It also includes the tension, impatience, and curiosity of anticipating an event.</description></item><item><title>The trust checklist</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-trust-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-trust-checklist/</guid><description>Trust is more of a cognitive assessment than an emotion. Distrust is when you feel “what is important to me is not safe with this person.” That lack of safety makes authenticity and vulnerability difficult for fear of betrayal (rightly so!).
In [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]], [[authors/brené brown|Brené Brown]] lists seven specific trustworthy behaviors:</description></item><item><title>Mitfreude</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mitfreude/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mitfreude/</guid><description>Mitfreude is feeling joy in another’s joy. The opposite of schadenfreude, where pleasure is derived from another’s misfortune.
Coined by Nietzsche in 1878,1 it originates in the German language, mit (“with”) + Freude (“joy”).
First encountered in [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]]’s essay on anime and manga, A Mitfreude of Anime and Manga’s Relationship with Anglophone Science Fiction), where she defines it as the joy of sharing joy with friends.</description></item><item><title>Emotional identification</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotional-identification/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotional-identification/</guid><description>Broadly speaking, we experience three different kinds of emotions in our brains: reactive, routine, and reflective emotions.
Reactive emotions are primitive, hardwired, and innate emotions, such as fear and defensive rage, produced in response to a perceived threat. They energize us for fight-and-flight and live in our limbic system.</description></item><item><title>Compersion</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/compersion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/compersion/</guid><description>Vicarious joy, experiencing pleasure because of another person’s pleasure. Basically the opposite of jealousy.
Coined by the Kerista Community in the 1970s, probably following the model of dispersion, so that use specifically applies to polyamorous relationships, the pleasure of your partner experiencing pleasure with someone else.</description></item><item><title>Common enemy intimacy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/common-enemy-intimacy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/common-enemy-intimacy/</guid><description>Via [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]]:
What’s really fascinating is that hate is actually fueled by our need for connection. I call this common enemy intimacy. I may not know anything about you, but we hate the same people and that creates a counterfeit bond and a sense of belonging.</description></item><item><title>The Buddhist concept of near enemies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/buddhist-concept-of-near-enemies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/buddhist-concept-of-near-enemies/</guid><description>via [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]]:
The Buddhist concept of near enemies: “Near enemies are states that appear similar to the desired quality but actually undermine it. Far enemies are the opposite of what we are trying to achieve. For example, a near enemy of loving-kindness is sentimentality—similar but different.</description></item><item><title>Despair is a state of repair</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/despair-is-a-state-of-repair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/despair-is-a-state-of-repair/</guid><description>[[authors/brené brown|Brené Brown]] puts despair as a synonym with hopelessness in [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]], so I’m going to go with [[authors/david whyte|David Whyte’s]] take on it instead. (Whyte and Brown, lol.)
((Note: maybe what I classify as despair would be more what Brown describes as anguish?</description></item><item><title>People bluff the opposite of the hand they’re holding</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/people-bluff-the-opposite-of-the-hand-theyre-holding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/people-bluff-the-opposite-of-the-hand-theyre-holding/</guid><description>People tend to bluff the opposite of whatever hand they’re holding; newbies do it in poker, and everyone does it with their ego. Conservatives are afraid of everything, so they posture as hypermasculine tough guys. Liberals are bootlickers who act like heroes of social justice.</description></item></channel></rss>