<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>language on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/language/</link><description>Recent content in language on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apophatic naming</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/apophatic-naming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/apophatic-naming/</guid><description>Apophatic naming, or negative naming, is the attempt to call a thing by so many names that its essential nature transcends all of them. It’s a practice “as old as philosophy itself,”1 and a central element of mysticism and early Christian thought.
I like the turn of phrase in this one: the Mystical Languages of Unsaying.</description></item><item><title>Both memes and needlework are collective folk texts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/both-memes-and-needlework-are-collective-folk-texts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/both-memes-and-needlework-are-collective-folk-texts/</guid><description>“Teks,” the root of “technology,” meant a treatise on an art, craft, or grammar, before the meaning transferred to mechanical arts and then to digital tech. The lineage back to arts and crafts is a compelling link between “text” and “textile,” where collective folk texts are remixed and remade endlessly.</description></item><item><title>Language is a network</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/language-is-a-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/language-is-a-network/</guid><description>We are not tending language like a garden—its order is emerging from the chaos in a natural way.
When we thought of language like a book, we thought of it as an unruly mess of words that had to be kept in order, like a Victorian gardener constantly retrimming the hedges into spirals and globes.</description></item><item><title>We rediscover and rename old ideas all the time</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-rediscover-and-rename-old-ideas-all-the-time/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-rediscover-and-rename-old-ideas-all-the-time/</guid><description> [[notes/could kinesiology explain the phenomenon of faith healing|could kinesiology explain the phenomenon of faith healing]] [[notes/modern science often repackages medieval categories|modern science often repackages medieval categories]]</description></item><item><title>The internet is a rhizome</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-internet-is-a-rhizome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-internet-is-a-rhizome/</guid><description>The internet is not a textbook, or even a wiki, or any kind of single, linear, finite entity. The internet is a rhizome.
When we thought of language as a book, we thought of it as linear and finite. A book can only have so many pages, so you have to decide what to keep in, what to fence out, and how to order what remains.</description></item><item><title>The curse of Latin-y grammar</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-curse-of-latin-y-grammar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-curse-of-latin-y-grammar/</guid><description>The Latin-worshipping tradition is responsible for the grammar elitism of infinitive splitting, proposition ending, and the singular “they.”
Robert Lowth, who wrote a widely used English grammar in 1792, passed an aesthetic judgment on the sentence-ending preposition (it wasn’t Latin-y enough), and later grammarians elevated this preference to a full-on ban.</description></item><item><title>Linguistic play as a writing exercise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</guid><description>[[authors/gretchen mcculloch|Gretchen McCulloch]], [[books/because internet|Because Internet]]:
I’ve taken up this sense of linguistic play as a writing exercise, especially when I’ve just read a bunch of academic papers and I’m having trouble shaking my thoughts free of Nominalization Accumulation Enunciation Contamination. Instead, I draft in Peak Internet Style, with no capitalization or punctuation, using acronyms and creative respelling to write my way through the muddle, rather than stopping when I don’t know how to articulate something or trying to sort through form and content at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Debility and disability justice</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/debility-is-the-denial-of-disability-rights-altogether/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/debility-is-the-denial-of-disability-rights-altogether/</guid><description>In [[books/the right to maim|The Right to Maim]], [[authors/jasbir puar|Jasbir Puar]] uses the concept of “debility”—bodily injury and social exclusion brought on by economic and political factors—to disrupt the category of disability and the neoliberal concept of disability justice.
Puar uses the term debilitation to describe what happens to Mohammed and so many others in Gaza that our neoliberal frame of disability rights can’t capture.</description></item></channel></rss>