<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>f-f on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/f-f/</link><description>Recent content in f-f on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/f-f/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iron &amp; Velvet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</guid><description>I have now done each of these in print (well, ebook, as print is sadly out of print) and each of these in audio, and all other vampire books can check themselves at the door. All other PI noirs too, for that matter.
“Yes, I was a faery-blooded, thirty-something PI with trust issues and a drinking problem, and she was a bloodthirsty undead nun with a pudding fixation, but I honestly thought we were in with a chance.</description></item><item><title>Mortal Follies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Something Fabulous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</guid><description>So far the theme of the year is romances that I read and then re-read right away and install on my best-of-year list (best-of-ever list too, in the case of Something Fabulous, which more than lives up to its name).
A few notes:
We’re starting to see the books written during the pandemic where authors are writing what they WANT, not what they SHOULD.</description></item><item><title>The Empress of Salt and Fortune</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-empress-of-salt-and-fortune/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-empress-of-salt-and-fortune/</guid><description>If you’re partial to storytelling as lush as this cover art, do not miss Nghi Vo. WOW.</description></item><item><title>Proper English</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</guid><description>It’s the House Party from Hell, and the first time I read it, I was like this is exhausting, it’s claustrophobic, not sure I can vibe with it—but then I read it again in 2020 and YES. It is a MOOD.</description></item><item><title>Delilah Green Doesn’t Care</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/delilah-green-doesnt-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/delilah-green-doesnt-care/</guid><description>One of those books where the friendships ALMOST outshine the romance. ALMOST. Everybody has arcs and character growth, even the exes; everybody contributes their piece of misunderstanding and conflict resolution to the plot. It’s like a big group hug from best friends, messy and comforting and silly and necessary.</description></item><item><title>Liberty &amp; Other Stories</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liberty-and-other-stories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liberty-and-other-stories/</guid><description>I did not think I could love the [[series/prosperityverse|Prosperityverse]] more, BUT I DO.</description></item><item><title>Shadows &amp; Dreams</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</guid><description>I’m almost sad I did this in audio because there are SO MANY lines I would have copy-pasted. Except the audio is SO GOOD I am not sad. I will just read it again in words-on-page form to copy-paste lines, and it will be no trial.</description></item><item><title>A Restless Truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</guid><description>This was so close to being great. SO CLOSE. But overall, the book felt kind of like the menagerie on board the ship, let loose in all directions, refusing to be corralled. There were some structure/plot/writing choices that left me more stumped than dazzled. Maud’s and Violet’s POV seemed really interchangeable for the first half, which is&amp;hellip; not great when one is a supposedly scandalous, sardonic, shrewd actress and one is a sheltered, capricious, stubborn young girl.</description></item><item><title>A Lady’s Guide to Scandal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</guid><description>Aah, this was so fun! It righted some wrongs from Persuasion (I’m not a Wentworth fan, okay—don’t @ me), and threw in enough hijinks that it didn’t have to be a faithful retelling. The only character I adore more than Melville is Margaret; I’m in love with them both.</description></item><item><title>Astrid Parker Doesn’t Fail</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/astrid-parker-doesnt-fail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/astrid-parker-doesnt-fail/</guid><description>Look, realistically, the destiny stuff did not work for me. They’ve known each other a handful of weeks; saying, “I really, really like you, we’re both hot messes, let’s try to make this work” would have been much more my speed.
But. I love Astrid Parker SO MUCH.</description></item><item><title>The Sugared Game</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</guid><description>The reason it takes me a week to read a book that I literally can’t put down is because I read it twice.
When I read [[books/slippery creatures|Slippery Creatures]], I wanted to say, this is what it looks like when an author levels up. I refrained, but I’m not going to wait til book three to say it: this is what it looks like when an author levels up.</description></item><item><title>Fire &amp; Water</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Something Extraordinary</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</guid><description>The high-strung Belle has left behind her heroine era, and the drama-prone Rufus has left behind his Sir Horley Comewithers era. Together they embark on the worst elopement kidnapping elopement in history (per Belle, it’s not vainglorious to claim that when it’s true), and what ensues is a meditation on friendship, love, sexuality, identity, self-discovery, society, and home in a way that only Alexis Hall can do it.</description></item><item><title>Subtle Blood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</guid><description>I might have accidentally read Subtle Blood again, since I might have accidentally experienced a vivid dream of Will, Kim, Phoebe, and Maisie on a Parisian adventure (cameo by Teddy Molyneaux, of course), and upon waking, might have accidentally been distraught that that book wasn’t going to exist.</description></item><item><title>Smoke &amp; Ashes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Ascent to Godhood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ascent-to-godhood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ascent-to-godhood/</guid><description>There are [[notes/mosaic novel|mosaic novels]]—these are mosaic novellas. I can see being disappointed with one if you picked it up standalone, but as a collective, each book a different facet of the whole, it’s some brilliant, satisfying storytelling.
The villain of the first three books? Yeah, this is her story, told by her lover.</description></item><item><title>Murder Most Actual</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/murder-most-actual/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/murder-most-actual/</guid><description>Speaking of [[books/proper english|sapphic murder house mysteries]], Alexis Hall has the contemporary version on lock.
There are few things I like more than an established relationship romance—so very difficult to do well—and here it’s a marriage very naturally on the rocks for very relatable, natural reasons, just the living of life and complexities that ensue.</description></item><item><title>Carmilla</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:13:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</guid><description>I suppose I should be talking about the book, but Megan Follows does the audio, so my actual takeaway is: my Megan Follows crush has not abated after 25 years. The absolute perfect choice of narrator for a gothic, queer, melodramatic, erotically-charged tale.
![[images/megan-follows-aogg.gif]]
Note: I borrowed the audiobook from the library, but I’ve marked this Lanternfish Press edition because I also sought it out solely for the Carmen Maria Machado foreword, which is excellent and should not be missed.</description></item><item><title>Come Out, Come Out</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</guid><description>In the same niche as [[books/camp damascus|Camp Damascus]], the conversion-therapy-as-horror genre. Similarities abound, even down to the senior class quarry jumps, which doesn’t indicate any co-opting of plot points but simply how ubiquitous this experience is, the same script across rural America, where any deviation from the script means there will be Consequences.</description></item><item><title>Spear</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Green Equinox</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-green-equinox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-green-equinox/</guid><description>Sometimes you’re just in the mood for moody, queer af British novels with all the fraught gender politics and literary melodrama of the 1970’s. What can I say! So odd and compelling, like a fever dream. (Often literally, as there is an outbreak of typhoid that infects the course of the story.</description></item><item><title>Experienced</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</guid><description>Bette gets dumped-but-not-dumped in truly shitty fashion by her girlfriend, who suggests she just needs more experience since she’s newly out as a lesbian. Commence a sex odyssey through the wilds of Bristol, aided by her first failed date of the odyssey, the kind and thoughtful Ruth.</description></item><item><title>Small Favors</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/small-favors/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/small-favors/</guid><description>Haaaaa, this was so FUN. And hot. And silly. I loved the manifesto introduction by Kelly Sue Deconnick about the power of play and the radical defiance of silliness, how it’s like lowering a rope in a dark well that saves the people at both ends.</description></item><item><title>Clear and Muddy Loss of Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</guid><description>This is just what I was in the mood for, a 300+ chapter, 4000 page sapphic slow burn court intrigue. The prose (and/or translation?) is more functional than beautiful on a sentence level, but on a plot level, with the overall character arcs, QJMX has some mad skill.</description></item><item><title>Infamous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</guid><description>This ending was the EXACT ENDING I’ve wanted to see for SO LONG. (Unapologetic all caps.) It took us ages to get there (more on that in a sec) but once we did? CHEF’S KISS.
Spoilery: %%it’s an f/f romance, and one half of the pair is affianced, to an amazing man, who’s gay, and they are going to use their marriage to give themselves and their true partners a safe harbor from society, and they go through with their marriage, and it’s just beautifully done, and… sniff I have a lot of feelings about friendships and healthy communication and unconventional choices and that kind of love.</description></item><item><title>Siren Queen</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/siren-queen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/siren-queen/</guid><description>I’ve been saving this one to be my birthday book because I knew Nghi Vo would deliver. Hoo boy, did she ever. Fav of the year? What she does with queerness, horror, and myth is just chef’s kiss.</description></item><item><title>Gwen &amp; Art Are Not in Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</guid><description>I think it wobbled a smiiiidge on the landing, a few things felt abrupt and/or undercooked, not to mention the jarring tonal shift into violence, but the ride to get there was super fun. There’s some fade-to-black, hand-wavey, don’t-think-too-hard-about-this energy re: the whole premature-inheritance, fix-a-broken-system-from-the-inside plan, but it is YA, and I wasn’t expecting an [[books/bitter|Akwaeke Emezi-level thesis]] on the subject of institutional power.</description></item><item><title>Kiss Her Once for Me</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</guid><description>Tried this one again, hoping I had one more festive read in me for the year, but there are just sooo many things that bug me right away. It’s gonna be one of those books where shitty systemic poverty gets magically fixed for one [pretty young white] woman by the power of romance with a [manipulative gaslighting] millionaire, isn’t it?</description></item><item><title>Everyone in This Room Will Someday Be Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:21:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</guid><description>This is the most strongly coded [[notes/autism|autistic]] protagonist I’ve read. Especially of the female, high-masking, chronic burnout variety, and undiagnosed. (Or rather, insufficiently diagnosed with anxiety and depression.) The unconscious stimming! Chronic sensory overload! The shutdowns! The meltdowns! The masking!
I feel like I am operating my body like it’s a vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Interesting Facts about Space</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</guid><description>Me [page 1]: I’m worried I read too much about [[notes/autism|ASD]] into [[books/everyone in this room will someday be dead|Everyone in This Room Will Someday be Dead]]. This time I’m gonna look for all the ways it’s not autism. I will counteract my bias.
Me [page 20]: This is autism.</description></item><item><title>Camp Damascus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</guid><description>I had to wait until I was in a good headspace to handle this. Ruth, an autistic devout Christian on the cusp of adulthood, begins to realize everything in her life is not as it seems, not even herself. Cue the horror of religious trauma and conversion therapy camps, right at home with the traditional trappings of the horror genre.</description></item></channel></rss>