<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>renaissance on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/renaissance/</link><description>Recent content in renaissance on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/renaissance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Inferno</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</guid><description>So good to read this while steeped in Florentine history. These are real people and real places, not just an abstract Lewis-esque allegory. Now I wish I knew Italian to read his terza rima original, especially since I’ve had to dig through the Longfellow to see what’s underneath.</description></item><item><title>Purgatorio</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</guid><description>Reading this alongside Guido Ruggiero’s [[books/the renaissance in italy|The Renaissance in Italy]] is A+ recommended. Once again, vastly more interesting than my first exposure, where school curriculum wanted it read like it was Pilgrim’s Progress. I needed the Bondanella introduction back then to dispense with the nonsense: “Such allegorical abstractions are simply not what Dante’s great poem is all about.</description></item><item><title>Paradiso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</guid><description>My dilemma since the early years of Sunday school: hell is more interesting than paradise. Thus, true to form, though I wanted to be contrary, [[books/inferno|Inferno]] is more interesting than any amount of heavenly light (so bright! so much dancing!), but get to that last line and you can’t help but feel the awe and poetry of it:</description></item><item><title>A Room with a View</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-room-with-a-view/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-room-with-a-view/</guid><description>It was the old, old battle of the room with the view.
Wow. Re-read in one sitting. I was only going to read the Florence bits, but then I just didn’t stop. This is why I’m a fan of coming back to books at different ages with different eyes and different contexts, because it makes them different books.</description></item><item><title>The Spirit Ring</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</guid><description>Sometimes when things connect, they really connect. I picked this up because I was ready for another Bujold, and this is what the library had, and what is right there when I open it up? Renaissance Italy! Borgias, Florentines; Sforzas, Medicis; Guelphs and Ghibellines.
Three true things: it’s a gem in the rough; Thur is my boy; every Bujold, even vintage Bujold, is the best Bujold.</description></item><item><title>Machiavelli in Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/machiavelli-in-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/machiavelli-in-love/</guid><description>Ruggiero does it again: a great companion piece to months of Renaissance reading, including [[authors/niccolo machiavelli|Machiavelli]].</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</guid><description>A note on translation: I used Reynolds to compare, contrast, and fill in the gaps with the [[books/orlando furioso a new verse translation|Slavitt translation]]. Slavitt takes liberties, and Reynolds has merit, but I’ve got to say, for compulsive readability, and cheeky irreverence that feels like it honors the spirit of the original, Slavitt it is.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso: A New Verse Translation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</guid><description>Ariosto writing like AO3 was a thing in the sixteenth century. I love it. Fiendishly clever layers of satire; a story where anything goes.</description></item><item><title>The Prince</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-prince/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-prince/</guid><description>Non-negotiable: read [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer’s]] five-part (plus?) series on Machiavelli. I’ll wait. She makes sense of the enigma, the real Machiavelli, neither lionized nor maligned. The brave thinker; the frightened statesman. Charismatic, unorthodox, forming a response to the Borgia tyranny, trying to save his beloved Florence, playing pranks on the monks, centuries ahead of his time.</description></item><item><title>The Renaissance in Italy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-renaissance-in-italy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-renaissance-in-italy/</guid><description>One of the most accessible yet in-depth histories I’ve read. Lively and engaging. It’s been my tour guide through the past month of [[authors/dante alighieri|Dante]], [[authors/benvenuto cellini|Cellini]], [[authors/niccolo machiavelli|Machiavelli]], [[authors/ludovico ariosto|Ariosto]], et. al. Highly recommended.</description></item><item><title>Everyone Knows Your Mother Is a Witch</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</guid><description>Historical (fan)fiction of Katarina Kepler, Johannes Kepler’s mother, famously tried as a witch. It’s fantastic, the character work, the structure, the narrative voice(s), the exuberant black humor that becomes blacker and blacker as it follows the warp of history. An impressive example of what the genre can do, no boring litfic pretentiousness here.</description></item></channel></rss>