<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>prehistorical on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/prehistorical/</link><description>Recent content in prehistorical on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/prehistorical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sex at Dawn</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sex-at-dawn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sex-at-dawn/</guid><description>For many societies, virginity is so unimportant there isn’t even a word for the concept in their language “Marriage,” “mating,” and “love” are socially constructed phenomena that have little or no transferable meaning outside any given culture No creature needs to be threatened with death to act in accord with its own nature We simply assume our own conception of family reflects something eternal and universal in human nature From savoring saliva beer or cow blood milkshakes to wearing socks with sandals, there is little doubt that people are willing to think, feel, wear, do, and believe pretty much anything if their society assures them it’s normal The majority of research on sexuality is based upon the responses of eighteen-to twenty-two-year-old American university students (!</description></item><item><title>Shattered Spear</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shattered-spear/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 22:00:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shattered-spear/</guid><description>Such a powerful example of what comics/graphic novels can do, with images more than words. I loved it. And more fiction of any kind set in the neolithic middle east, please.
Available from the author here, name your own price: https://claystorks.itch.io/shattered-spear</description></item></channel></rss>