<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sex-work on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/sex-work/</link><description>Recent content in sex-work on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/sex-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blackouts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</guid><description>All the different layers of meaning to the title—the blackouts our narrator experiences due to PTSD, the blackouts of Juan and his fading memory, the failure of institutional memory, the queer erasure from history, the literal blackouts of the pages of the book. It feels like a work of art, not just a novel.</description></item><item><title>The Good Life</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-good-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-good-life/</guid><description>Man takes [[books/the great gatsby|The Great Gatsby]] as a how-to manual, right down to the narcissism and body count, just with more explicit gay sex. (As in, Gatsby the way the good lord intended.) It’s unpleasant to read in the way obscene wealth always is, but it’s beautifully structured and compellingly written, an interesting artifact of both the era in which it’s set and when it’s written.</description></item><item><title>The Emperor and the Endless Palace</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-emperor-and-the-endless-palace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-emperor-and-the-endless-palace/</guid><description>I kept my expectations low, and the writing shows promise on the sentence level—but on the plot/structure/worldbuilding/thematic level, it falls apart. There are plot twists that change the entire point of the story, but Huang doesn’t write like he knows that. (If there’s a second book, perhaps he plans to explore that further, but it doesn’t come together in this book.</description></item><item><title>Kushiel’s Dart</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kushiels-dart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kushiels-dart/</guid><description>My semi-decennial attempt to finish this book. I made it farther this time, with determination, but despite an attempt every three to five years, I still bounce off it like a rubber ball. Taboo, kink, AND court intrigue in the same book?! This should be exactly my thing!</description></item><item><title>Margo’s Got Money Troubles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</guid><description>20-year-old Margo sleeps with her professor, gets pregnant, keeps the baby, and discovers what a capitalist hellscape the U.S. is for mothers of all stripes, but particularly the unwed. Creating porn online becomes the only ethical way to survive, and this searing social commentary is wrapped up with so much humor and heart the book practically explodes with it.</description></item><item><title>Freak Pleasures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/freak-pleasures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/freak-pleasures/</guid><description>Now this is protest art. Specifically, the protest of SESTA/FOSTA and the censorship it entails, not to mention the way it endangers those it purports to protect.
Available here: https://claystorks.itch.io/freak-pleasures</description></item><item><title>Giovanni’s Room</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</guid><description>Not everyone in book club was a fan, but I loved it, but it was brutal, but I’m glad I read it, but I’m glad I won’t be in a rush to read it again.
“Somebody,” said Jacques, “your father or mine, should have told us that not many people have ever died of love.</description></item></channel></rss>