<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>jesus-etc on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/jesus-etc/</link><description>Recent content in jesus-etc on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/jesus-etc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>Jesus: Apocalyptic Prophet of the New Millennium</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jesus-apocalyptic-prophet-of-the-new-millennium/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 12:34:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jesus-apocalyptic-prophet-of-the-new-millennium/</guid><description>What I wanted [[books/zealot|Zealot]] to be.</description></item><item><title>Pagans</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 12:34:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</guid><description>About as beautifully (and concisely) written as you can get for a history book. Fabulous stuff. Some fav lines:
—Augustus revived a thing that had barely been invented in his own time: “old-time religion,” rather like the nearly postmodern version of Christianity invented in nineteenth-century America and called “fundamentalism.</description></item><item><title>Kushiel’s Dart</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kushiels-dart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kushiels-dart/</guid><description>My semi-decennial attempt to finish this book. I made it farther this time, with determination, but despite an attempt every three to five years, I still bounce off it like a rubber ball. Taboo, kink, AND court intrigue in the same book?! This should be exactly my thing!</description></item><item><title>Margo’s Got Money Troubles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</guid><description>20-year-old Margo sleeps with her professor, gets pregnant, keeps the baby, and discovers what a capitalist hellscape the U.S. is for mothers of all stripes, but particularly the unwed. Creating porn online becomes the only ethical way to survive, and this searing social commentary is wrapped up with so much humor and heart the book practically explodes with it.</description></item><item><title>Camp Damascus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</guid><description>I had to wait until I was in a good headspace to handle this. Ruth, an autistic devout Christian on the cusp of adulthood, begins to realize everything in her life is not as it seems, not even herself. Cue the horror of religious trauma and conversion therapy camps, right at home with the traditional trappings of the horror genre.</description></item><item><title>Zealot</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/zealot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/zealot/</guid><description>Great at painting a picture of 1st century Palestine. So many inaccuracies though! [[books/jesus apocalyptic prophet of the new millennium|Ehrman’s was better]].
Pull quotes Nowhere is any such thing written: not in the Law of Moses, not in the prophets, not in the Psalms. In the entire history of Jewish thought there is not a single line of scripture that says the messiah is to suffer, die, and rise again on the third day, which may explain why Jesus does not bother to cite any scripture to back up his incredible claim.</description></item><item><title>A History of the Bible</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-history-of-the-bible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-history-of-the-bible/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Flowering Wand</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-flowering-wand/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-flowering-wand/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>