<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>myths-and-folklore on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/myths-and-folklore/</link><description>Recent content in myths-and-folklore on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/myths-and-folklore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iron &amp; Velvet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</guid><description>I have now done each of these in print (well, ebook, as print is sadly out of print) and each of these in audio, and all other vampire books can check themselves at the door. All other PI noirs too, for that matter.
“Yes, I was a faery-blooded, thirty-something PI with trust issues and a drinking problem, and she was a bloodthirsty undead nun with a pudding fixation, but I honestly thought we were in with a chance.</description></item><item><title>Mortal Follies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Inferno</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</guid><description>So good to read this while steeped in Florentine history. These are real people and real places, not just an abstract Lewis-esque allegory. Now I wish I knew Italian to read his terza rima original, especially since I’ve had to dig through the Longfellow to see what’s underneath.</description></item><item><title>The Black Tides of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</guid><description>Note from my future self: this makes an excellent prequel, I should have started with [[books/the red threads of fortune|book 2]]!</description></item><item><title>The Empress of Salt and Fortune</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-empress-of-salt-and-fortune/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-empress-of-salt-and-fortune/</guid><description>If you’re partial to storytelling as lush as this cover art, do not miss Nghi Vo. WOW.</description></item><item><title>A Marvellous Light</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</guid><description>Fun Edwardian murder mystery. Fun world building. God save Edwin from the idiotic flower of English manhood.</description></item><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>The Sorcerer of the Wildeeps</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sorcerer-of-the-wildeeps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sorcerer-of-the-wildeeps/</guid><description>Whoa. Masterful use of dialect and structure to deconstruct the traditional bounds of genre and narrative. The way the characters code-switch their way through multiple registers and languages—well-known and invented—is reflected in the way the novella flips through genres like a catalog, exposing the expectations and limitations of each.</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Grace</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-grace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-grace/</guid><description>Oops, I did my thing of accidentally reading out of order. I was doing the audiobooks and went by the listing on Scribd (now Everand), which had them listed out of order. So I read book 2 first.
I don’t think that changed my opinion of anything.</description></item><item><title>Confounding Oaths</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/confounding-oaths/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/confounding-oaths/</guid><description>I was exactly in the mood for this. Cynical fairies and curses from the gods and a family in shambles. The romance is there, and quite lovely, but it’s off to one side, and that suits my mood too. The Caesar sisters and the Irregulars of the militia take up space on page, which makes me happy.</description></item><item><title>Shadows &amp; Dreams</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</guid><description>I’m almost sad I did this in audio because there are SO MANY lines I would have copy-pasted. Except the audio is SO GOOD I am not sad. I will just read it again in words-on-page form to copy-paste lines, and it will be no trial.</description></item><item><title>Purgatorio</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</guid><description>Reading this alongside Guido Ruggiero’s [[books/the renaissance in italy|The Renaissance in Italy]] is A+ recommended. Once again, vastly more interesting than my first exposure, where school curriculum wanted it read like it was Pilgrim’s Progress. I needed the Bondanella introduction back then to dispense with the nonsense: “Such allegorical abstractions are simply not what Dante’s great poem is all about.</description></item><item><title>The Red Threads of Fortune</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</guid><description>This should have been book 1! Or I should have done my typical thing of reading out of order and started here! The one time I try to be responsible and read a series in order, this is what happens.
Technically, these are “twin novellas,” but IMO, Mokoya is the emotional core of the story, followed by Rider, and Akeha in [[books/the black tides of heaven|Black Tides]] is an interesting prequel.</description></item><item><title>When the Tiger Came Down the Mountain</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/when-the-tiger-came-down-the-mountain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/when-the-tiger-came-down-the-mountain/</guid><description>Just as lush and complex as the [[books/the empress of salt and fortune|first one]], and given the smaller scope of the story, arguably my favorite of the two.</description></item><item><title>The Tombs of Atuan</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-tombs-of-atuan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-tombs-of-atuan/</guid><description>The funny thing is, I sometimes resist reading Ursula K. Le Guin. Because I know I’ll have to stop, and do nothing else, and absorb through my pores, and not read any of the other ten or twelve things I might have read that week, and just camp out in her world as long as I can.</description></item><item><title>A Taste of Honey</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-taste-of-honey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-taste-of-honey/</guid><description>That ending! Talk about an ending that twists everything you thought you read for the previous 159 pages (I dare say, happily so).
Kai Ashante Williams [[books/the sorcerer of the wildeeps|messes with the genre bounds again]], melding psionics and telekinesis and Greek oracles as fluently as his languages.</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Strength</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-strength/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-strength/</guid><description>Oof, it pains me to say I had a tough time with this one. There was so much I liked—mainly CLARA—but it’s so unnecessarily long. Like at least a hundred pages too long because there’s so much repetition and angst and constant unresolved horniness. I love a road trip, I don’t mind a slow burn done right, but here the slow burn veers perilously close to miscommunication.</description></item><item><title>Fire &amp; Water</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Power Unbound</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</guid><description>Here is my theory from [[books/a restless truth|book 2]]: the Blyths suit me best in small doses. Robin and Maud, respectively, were the most difficult parts of their own books for me. They’re just so young, energetic, athletic, upstanding, so shiny, so beautiful, so aggressively… “normal,” for lack of a better word, when I prefer crankiness and weariness and a bit of tarnish on the bronze these days.</description></item><item><title>The Hallowed Hunt</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</guid><description>Not the heights of Ista or Cazaril, but going backwards in this timeline instead of forwards is a choice I admire. I can see returning to this one as often as the two favorites, especially if those two get worn out by re-reading.</description></item><item><title>Paradiso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</guid><description>My dilemma since the early years of Sunday school: hell is more interesting than paradise. Thus, true to form, though I wanted to be contrary, [[books/inferno|Inferno]] is more interesting than any amount of heavenly light (so bright! so much dancing!), but get to that last line and you can’t help but feel the awe and poetry of it:</description></item><item><title>Into the Riverlands</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/into-the-riverlands/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/into-the-riverlands/</guid><description>Our traveling cleric Chih wanders into a wuxia novel, crossing paths with a pair of martial sisters and a polyamorous triad of rogue cultivators (MORE FANFIC ON THAT PLS!). It’s a road trip novella, replete with multiple stories within a story, rumination on reality vs. myth, and Almost Brilliant being brilliant.</description></item><item><title>The Descent of Monsters</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</guid><description>So we’re completely changing protagonists AND writing style AND partially the genre too? Hell yes! Basically it’s the official report on the fallout of the [[books/the red threads of fortune|second book]], done epistolary style (with redactions!), introducing major revelations of its own.
Loved it. Definitely doesn’t stand on its own—don’t start here.</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Hope</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-hope/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-hope/</guid><description>Not me, caught up in the spookiness more than the romance. The romance was still solid, though. The audiobooks remain excellent.</description></item><item><title>Smoke &amp; Ashes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mammoths at the Gates</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mammoths-at-the-gates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:35:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mammoths-at-the-gates/</guid><description>Our beloved cleric Chih returns home to the Singing Hills monastery, only to find (spoiler alert) mammoths at the gates, an imperial delegation come to collect one of their own. A lovely mediation on grief, change, and love, through a plot revealed as always in the layers and sediment of myth.</description></item><item><title>The Ascent to Godhood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ascent-to-godhood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ascent-to-godhood/</guid><description>There are [[notes/mosaic novel|mosaic novels]]—these are mosaic novellas. I can see being disappointed with one if you picked it up standalone, but as a collective, each book a different facet of the whole, it’s some brilliant, satisfying storytelling.
The villain of the first three books? Yeah, this is her story, told by her lover.</description></item><item><title>The Left Hand of Darkness</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid><description>Imperfect and still utterly perfect. Favorite always.
The David Mitchell foreword
Picture if you will reading this book when it was published, 1969, the year of Stonewall
Gender, sex, romance, desire, power, nationalism, oppression… they’re all just stories we tell ourselves. And we can tell different stories if we choose.</description></item><item><title>The Brides of High Hill</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-brides-of-high-hill/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-brides-of-high-hill/</guid><description>Cleric Chih accompanies the bridal party of Pham Nhung to the estate of her potential husband, a man with monstrous secrets. For the first two acts, there are no stories-within-a-story, and no Almost Brilliant, in a way that indicates they’re connected—Chih keeps requesting to hear stories, but people refuse or prevaricate, until we miss the niexin as keenly as Chih does.</description></item><item><title>Amazing Asia</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/amazing-asia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/amazing-asia/</guid><description>The “explain it like I’m 5” primer that more people beyond the age of 5 could appreciate. It’s more thorough, interesting, and engaging than what got taught in school, that’s for sure.
ARC kindly provided by the publisher via NetGalley in exchange for an honest review.</description></item><item><title>Rakesfall</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rakesfall/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rakesfall/</guid><description>For the first half of this, it’s very much a sister-book to [[books/the saint of bright doors|The Saint of Bright Doors]]. If you didn’t like that one, you probably won’t vibe with this one. But if, like me, you loved Saint, then Rakesfall levels up and then some.</description></item><item><title>The City in Glass</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-city-in-glass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-city-in-glass/</guid><description>The blurbs compared it to [[authors/ursula k le guin|Le Guin]] and [[authors/italo calvino|Calvino]], and with any other author, that would be a disastrous claim to make. Here, Nghi Vo only takes the playful metaphysics of Calvino and the gentle worldbuilding of Le Guin, and weaves it with so much raw emotion that this slim little volume shouldn’t be able to contain it all.</description></item><item><title>The Saint of Bright Doors</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</guid><description>Gobsmacked at how good this is, without even the caveat of “for a first novel.” Fetter, the feral only child of a messiah, trained by his mother as assassin, destined to commit matricide and fratricide, navigates a dystopian Sri Lanka far too recognizable in the present.</description></item><item><title>The Salt Grows Heavy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</guid><description>Truly grisly horror with a truly touching love story. Most fairytale retellings (here, The Little Mermaid) course-correct from the Disney versions back to Hans Christian Andersen territory. This overshoots Andersen by quite some distance, landing in the realm of rapacious colonizers and ghoulish Mengele-style war crimes.</description></item><item><title>The Dragon Waiting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dragon-waiting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dragon-waiting/</guid><description>“The Velvet Underground of novels,” as Scott Lynch says in the introduction. This book is a masterwork. If I ever mix up my history on the Medicis, the War of the Roses, and the Byzantine Empire, it’s probably because I’ve misremembered this fiction as fact. It’s a fascinating thought experiment, imagining how the trajectory of history would look different (or not) if Julian the Apostate had had a long, successful rule.</description></item><item><title>The Collected Works of C.G. Jung</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-collected-works-of-cg-jung/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:09:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-collected-works-of-cg-jung/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Griso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/griso/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/griso/</guid><description>A very brief tale of a unicorn searching for other unicorns, with each spread rendered in a different historical style—Tang dynasty murals, medieval illustrations, cave paintings, African art, surrealist art, and more. The color palette and visual cues make it more cohesive than you’d think. I’d happily have it on my own shelves or gift it to nieces and nephews, both for art and story alike.</description></item><item><title>Tarot for Change</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tarot-for-change/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tarot-for-change/</guid><description>I’d prefer a bit less Joseph Campbell and Cognitive Behavioral Therapy,1 but overall, the best book on tarot I’ve encountered so far. Or, rather than a definitive superlative, it’s the book that most resonates with me so far. It’s how I engage with tarot, not for divination, but therapeutically, creatively, narratively, for introspection and storytelling.</description></item><item><title>A Sorceress Comes to Call</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</guid><description>I’m here all day long for T. Kingfisher’s aging, aching protagonists, with bad knees and big hearts and a well-honed sense of doom. The plot is a very loose retelling of The Goose Girl, minus princesses and kings and plus a conniving, murderous, sorceress mother. Evangeline, aka Doom, is determined to marry herself and her trapped, obedient daughter to the highest bidders in proper Regency-esque fashion, plans thwarted when she encounters a squire’s spinster sister who sees her for exactly who she is.</description></item><item><title>Minor Mage</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/minor-mage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/minor-mage/</guid><description>Oliver was already on his knees, but he bowed his head, feeling complicated things he didn’t know how to deal with. When kindness came from murdered ghosts and lost pigs, and the adults that were supposed to help you were monsters that walked like men… What was he supposed to do?</description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</guid><description>So this is everything a fairy tale should be. The only thing that didn’t work for me 100% was the romance side plot, but it was very sweet nonetheless, and I do understand that’s a common ingredient in fairy tales, and that for most it would be necessary.</description></item><item><title>Among Others</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</guid><description>“[[notes/bibliotropic|Bibliotropic]],” Hugh said. “Like sunflowers are heliotropic, they naturally turn towards the sun. We naturally turn towards the bookshop.”
Where do I begin? What is this book about? Books, yes. A love of books and of libraries. Books as lifeline and language. It’s about a girl growing up, and witches and fairies and boarding schools and grief and Wales and loneliness even amongst those with whom you might belong.</description></item><item><title>Ficciones</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ficciones/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ficciones/</guid><description>Borges is up to some delightful fuckery, playing with form, inventing books and authors and universes that are just as, to paraphrase, contaminated with fiction as our own history of the world. The stories are brief and vertiginous, mind-boggling and often cheeky. An undisputed masterpiece, even if I’m still partial to [[authors/italo calvino|Calvino]], even if Calvino himself would disagree with me (per his essay on Borges in [[books/six memos for the next millennium|Six Memos for the Next Millennium]]).</description></item><item><title>Lessons from Cruising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</guid><description>Joke’s on me, because I picked up this ARC for the last story, a retelling of Billy Budd from Captain Vere’s point of view. I figured I’d sample the rest; instead I went down the buffet line and inhaled them all. Rarely do I like every story in a short story collection, but that’s what Goodman’s done to me.</description></item><item><title>The Last of the Wine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-last-of-the-wine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-last-of-the-wine/</guid><description>So very good. Here I was thinking the writing style kept me at a remove from the story and I wasn’t as invested as I could be, and then the last two chapters walloped me in the gut and I realized it had me at the emotional level after all.</description></item><item><title>The Mask of Apollo</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-mask-of-apollo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-mask-of-apollo/</guid><description>I’m reserving five stars because Alexander shows up at the end and whoa, I want to see what she does with his books. But it’s a marvel. The best of Renault’s I’ve read yet? Thettalos is my fave.</description></item><item><title>Maurice</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/maurice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/maurice/</guid><description>I love this book because the characters are awful and snobby and wrong about so many things. Just like we’re awful and snobby and wrong in our own times. No historical revisionism, and still a happy ending. There’s great beauty within.
Not far from the lodge there was a nasty little climb, and the road, always in bad condition, was edged with dog roses that scratched the paint.</description></item><item><title>The Emperor and the Endless Palace</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-emperor-and-the-endless-palace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-emperor-and-the-endless-palace/</guid><description>I kept my expectations low, and the writing shows promise on the sentence level—but on the plot/structure/worldbuilding/thematic level, it falls apart. There are plot twists that change the entire point of the story, but Huang doesn’t write like he knows that. (If there’s a second book, perhaps he plans to explore that further, but it doesn’t come together in this book.</description></item><item><title>The Palace of Eros</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</guid><description>My adjectives for the prose: purple, dense, florid, bloated. It sounds like I’m describing a corpse. DNF @ 15% because none of it is connecting with me, not the first-person Psyche nor the third-person Eros, nor the prose that’s turgid to the point of hyperbole. (Did I just want the chance to deploy the word turgid?</description></item><item><title>The Autobiography of Benvenuto Cellini</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autobiography-of-benvenuto-cellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autobiography-of-benvenuto-cellini/</guid><description>Necromancy, assassinations, prison breaks, poisonings, stabbings (so many stabbings!!), pranks on Michelangelo… dude lived a life. Come for the adventure, stay for the fascinating glimpse into Renaissance life and art. I read because [[authors/lois mcmaster bujold|Bujold]] based part of [[books/the spirit ring|The Spirit Ring]] on Cellini and said fact was stranger than fiction… she was not wrong.</description></item><item><title>The Spirit Ring</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</guid><description>Sometimes when things connect, they really connect. I picked this up because I was ready for another Bujold, and this is what the library had, and what is right there when I open it up? Renaissance Italy! Borgias, Florentines; Sforzas, Medicis; Guelphs and Ghibellines.
Three true things: it’s a gem in the rough; Thur is my boy; every Bujold, even vintage Bujold, is the best Bujold.</description></item><item><title>Decameron</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/decameron/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/decameron/</guid><description>Hey, remember way back when there was this pandemic happening? This was good reading during it.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</guid><description>A note on translation: I used Reynolds to compare, contrast, and fill in the gaps with the [[books/orlando furioso a new verse translation|Slavitt translation]]. Slavitt takes liberties, and Reynolds has merit, but I’ve got to say, for compulsive readability, and cheeky irreverence that feels like it honors the spirit of the original, Slavitt it is.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso: A New Verse Translation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</guid><description>Ariosto writing like AO3 was a thing in the sixteenth century. I love it. Fiendishly clever layers of satire; a story where anything goes.</description></item><item><title>Spear</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Castle of Crossed Destinies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-castle-of-crossed-destinies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-castle-of-crossed-destinies/</guid><description>A lot of [[authors/ludovico ariosto|Ariosto]], a little of [[authors/giovanni boccaccio|Boccaccio]], a lot of Homer, Sophocles, and Shakespeare and a little of [[authors/dante alighieri|Dante]] too. Had I not been recently indulging in all of those authors, the story might have lost me, but now it’s just in good company.</description></item><item><title>The Cloven Viscount</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cloven-viscount/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cloven-viscount/</guid><description>Now this is how you do a fable. What a joy the language is, even in translation. Not to mention each character, good and bad alike, equal parts lovable and bizarre. [[books/the complete cosmicomics|Once again]], the only reason I’d want to have kids is to read them Calvino.</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item><item><title>The Fox Wife</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</guid><description>Not the right choice to follow Nghi Vo’s [[books/the brides of high hill|fox-spirit tale]]. Atmospheric, but I feel talked down to and everything is over-explained. This is why I like sticking to genre for Asian fantasy instead of litfic. DNF @ pg 60. (I did flip through the rest because the hardcover had wide margins for sidenotes, but there were… barely any?</description></item><item><title>Pagans</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 12:34:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</guid><description>About as beautifully (and concisely) written as you can get for a history book. Fabulous stuff. Some fav lines:
—Augustus revived a thing that had barely been invented in his own time: “old-time religion,” rather like the nearly postmodern version of Christianity invented in nineteenth-century America and called “fundamentalism.</description></item><item><title>Ninetails</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ninetails/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ninetails/</guid><description>I love mythology turned feminist, but something about this was so on the nose that it didn’t quite pull me in. I may revisit in a different mood to see if I feel differently, or whether I’m comparing it unfairly to [[books/home remedies|Home Remedies]], which was a better match to my taste in short stories.</description></item><item><title>Lunar New Year Love Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lunar-new-year-love-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lunar-new-year-love-story/</guid><description>What I loved: the cultural stuff, especially lion dancing, and the nuance about the Asian diaspora (Vietnamese, Chinese, and Korean all represented).
What I wasn’t expecting: Lunar New Year actually plays a small part in the story; it’s much more focused on Valentine’s Day and Catholicism.</description></item><item><title>On the Fox Roads</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</guid><description>Nghi Vo can write [[books/the chosen and the beautiful|queer Jazz Age fanfic]] for me all day any day. (Also excellent: the Venn diagram of her Chinese and Vietnamese characters, the overlapping similarities and the differences.)</description></item><item><title>Siren Queen</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/siren-queen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/siren-queen/</guid><description>I’ve been saving this one to be my birthday book because I knew Nghi Vo would deliver. Hoo boy, did she ever. Fav of the year? What she does with queerness, horror, and myth is just chef’s kiss.</description></item><item><title>The Chosen and the Beautiful</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</guid><description>As someone who has long loved [[authors/f scott fitzgerald|F. Scott Fitzgerald]]’s writing, despite his depressing and often problematic deal, this [[books/the great gatsby|Gatsby]] retelling vis-à-vis a Vietnamese Jordan Baker is exquisite. Absolutely true to the spirit of the original, while absolutely its own fantastical, queer, eerie, spectacular thing.</description></item><item><title>The Magic Fish</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-magic-fish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-magic-fish/</guid><description>Wow. Absolutely lovely. Destroyed me in the best way.
And just on a visual level, what Nguyen does with the coloring for the different timelines, and the extensive notes on historical fashion and mythological context in the afterword make me appreciate it even more.</description></item><item><title>The Twice-Drowned Saint</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-twice-drowned-saint/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-twice-drowned-saint/</guid><description>I don’t even know how the hell to describe this, except amazing. Apparently my unintentional theme lately is biblically accurate angels—see [[books/pet|Pet]], see [[books/exodus 20|Freydís Moon]]. Here, Cooney made the mythology its own thing and the worldbuilding is fiendishly clever. A refugee crisis in the midst of a celestial city with bloodthirsty angels who must be overthrown by two secret saints, a newly-sprouted godhead, and a family of filmmakers and waste collectors—that’s the best stab I can take at the plot.</description></item><item><title>Three Kings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</guid><description>Another for my collection of killer opening lines:
Ethan Shaw carried two knives, one for lilies, the other for veins.
And the book just gets better and better from there. It counters all my usual problems with cozy witchy books, and sometimes cozy fantasy in general, not to mention the fraught subject of fertility.</description></item><item><title>Exodus 20</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:55:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</guid><description>If you’re gonna write monster kink, make it a biblically accurate angel. And throw in some searing social/political/theological commentary. This was excellent.</description></item><item><title>Underland</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/underland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 16:34:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/underland/</guid><description>For to think in deep time can be a means not of escaping our troubled present, but rather of re-imagining it; countermanding its quick greeds and furies with older, slower stories of making and unmaking.
Three different siren calls for me: geology, linguistics, and [[notes/deep time|deep time]].</description></item><item><title>Kalpa Imperial</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kalpa-imperial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kalpa-imperial/</guid><description>Exquisite. I could gush about it, or quote it; instead, I’ll say that Angélica translated by Ursula is about the best match you could ask for. Up there with [[authors/italo calvino|Calvino]] and Orsinian Tales and Always Coming Home. A [[notes/mosaic novel|mosaic novel]], yes?</description></item><item><title>Pantheologies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pantheologies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pantheologies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Braiding Sweetgrass</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Entangled Life</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/entangled-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/entangled-life/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Hidden Life of Trees</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hidden-life-of-trees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hidden-life-of-trees/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Flowering Wand</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-flowering-wand/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-flowering-wand/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>