<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>list on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/list/</link><description>Recent content in list on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/list/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anatomy of a propaganda blitz</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</guid><description>Copying this straight from [[books/propaganda blitz|Propaganda Blitz]] ([[authors/david edwards|David Edwards]] and [[authors/david cromwell|David Cromwell]]) because it’s immensely helpful to reference.
Propaganda blitzes are fast-moving attacks intended to inflict maximum damage in minimum time. They are:
based on allegations of dramatic new evidence communicated with high emotional intensity and moral outrage apparently supported by an informed corporate media/academic/expert consensus reinforced by damning condemnation of anyone daring even to question the apparent consensus often generated with fortuitous timing characterised by tragicomic moral dissonance Every one of these things, much less the concatenation of all of them, signals red flag, red flag, red flag.</description></item><item><title>How to beat a manipulator</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-beat-a-manipulator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-beat-a-manipulator/</guid><description>Conveniently, the strategies for dealing with sociopathic manipulators are the exact same, whether it’s a partner, a parent, a pastor, or a plutocrat. 🙃
Get clear on your own will Watch where all the resources are going Watch actions, not their words Don’t try to out manipulate Apply the manipulator’s rules in reverse Here’s the key: simply reverse the pronouns.</description></item><item><title>The three stages of gaslighting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-stages-of-gaslighting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-stages-of-gaslighting/</guid><description>Gaslighting is basically a step-by-step psychological process to manipulate and destabilize you. It’s repetitive information force-fed to you that builds up over time, undermining your faith in your own logic, reason, and judgement. It’s super hard to detect because it’s encoded on the subconscious “hard disk,” which isn’t overridden by the conscious “floppy disk.</description></item><item><title>The holistic definition of trauma</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-holistic-definition-of-trauma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-holistic-definition-of-trauma/</guid><description>One of the most accurate definitions of trauma I’ve found is from [[books/chinese medicine for the mind|Chinese Medicine for the Mind]] ([[authors/nina cheng|Nina Cheng]]), which acknowledges that it involves many aspects of emotional, psychological, and physiological conditions.
The defining characteristics:
Overwhelms the nervous system Violates boundaries Disrupts relationality Severs connections Admits feelings of powerlessness Damages the sense of meaning Inhibits the sense of self Disrupts contact with the self Instigates or stimulates collapse/separation of yin and yang (dysregulation) Interestingly, I was just looking up TRE on the cptsdfoundation.</description></item><item><title>Core values</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/core-values/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/core-values/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The relationship abuse checklist</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-relationship-abuse-checklist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-relationship-abuse-checklist/</guid><description>In the years since I read it, I still haven’t come across a better relationship inventory than [[authors/anton fulmen|Anton Fulmen’s]] in [[books/the dominance playbook|The Dominance Playbook]]. (Leave it to the kink community to nail down the dynamics of abuse.) I reference it all the time, and what I like most is it applies to any interactions between people, not just sexual or romantic relationships.</description></item><item><title>The trust checklist</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-trust-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-trust-checklist/</guid><description>Trust is more of a cognitive assessment than an emotion. Distrust is when you feel “what is important to me is not safe with this person.” That lack of safety makes authenticity and vulnerability difficult for fear of betrayal (rightly so!).
In [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]], [[authors/brené brown|Brené Brown]] lists seven specific trustworthy behaviors:</description></item><item><title>Institutional betrayal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</guid><description>Institutional betrayal is when an institution causes harm (by action or inaction) to anyone who trusts or depends on them. Red flags include strict membership requirements (the military, elite sports), prestige or power differentials (caregivers v. patients, clergy v. parishioners), and rigid priorities, like extreme efforts to protect the reputation of the organization.</description></item></channel></rss>