<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>colonialism on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/colonialism/</link><description>Recent content in colonialism on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/colonialism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Genocide</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-genocide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-genocide/</guid><description>Sartre in 1967:
When a peasant falls in his rice paddy, mowed down by a machine gun, every one of us is hit. The Vietnamese fight for all men and the American forces against all. Neither figuratively nor abstractly. And not only because genocide would be a crime universally condemned by international law, but because little by little the whole human race is being subjected to this genocidal blackmail piled on top of atomic blackmail, that is, to absolute, total war.</description></item><item><title>On Palestine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</guid><description>Many of the world’s problems are so intractable that it’s hard to think of ways even to take steps toward mitigating them.
The Israel-Palestine conflict is not one of these.
I admit I’ve fallen prey to the line, re: the occupation of Palestine, “it’s too complex to understand.</description></item><item><title>Our History Is the Future</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/our-history-is-the-future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/our-history-is-the-future/</guid><description>An excellent re-issue of a book that&amp;rsquo;s been on my to-read list since it first published in 2019. I&amp;rsquo;m glad it finally prompted me to get to it. It’s the history of two centuries of indigenous activism in the context of even broader indigenous exploitation and resistance, and it needs to be more widely known.</description></item><item><title>We the Gathered Heat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</guid><description>Superb. This is how to do an anthology, where the disparate voices are the point—how do we even define AAPI except as “the other,” non-white? Who is the “we” in question? To whom is that category useful? The poems are sorted into themes of “mourn,” “pronounce,” “fight,” “love,” each as powerful as the last.</description></item><item><title>On History</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-history/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-history/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Salt Grows Heavy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</guid><description>Truly grisly horror with a truly touching love story. Most fairytale retellings (here, The Little Mermaid) course-correct from the Disney versions back to Hans Christian Andersen territory. This overshoots Andersen by quite some distance, landing in the realm of rapacious colonizers and ghoulish Mengele-style war crimes.</description></item><item><title>Howards End</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/howards-end/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/howards-end/</guid><description>At least this one holds up to my initial perception; it’s still my least favorite of the Forster novels.* The energy and wit are a feast for the senses, especially in the dialogue, but it’s so much about England and Empire, it gets, dare I say… tiresome?</description></item></channel></rss>