<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jo Walton on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/authors/jo-walton/</link><description>Recent content in Jo Walton on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/authors/jo-walton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Among Others</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</guid><description>“[[notes/bibliotropic|Bibliotropic]],” Hugh said. “Like sunflowers are heliotropic, they naturally turn towards the sun. We naturally turn towards the bookshop.”
Where do I begin? What is this book about? Books, yes. A love of books and of libraries. Books as lifeline and language. It’s about a girl growing up, and witches and fairies and boarding schools and grief and Wales and loneliness even amongst those with whom you might belong.</description></item><item><title>Lent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lent/</guid><description>It seems like every year there’s a book that I want to beg people to read because I struggle to describe it, and it’s nothing like what they’d expect. This year, it’s this book.
It’s beautiful. It’s delightful and unusual and quietly profound. It’s a master class in plot.</description></item><item><title>Starlings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starlings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starlings/</guid><description>My favorite stories are clustered right in the middle: “What A Piece of Work,” “Parable Lost,” “What Would Sam Spade Do?” But the first story is where the heroine has the line that makes me laugh, clap, and cheer:
“Love? Well now. You feel what you feel, and I feel what I feel, but that doesn’t mean you have to fit us into a story and wreck both our lives.</description></item><item><title>What Makes This Book So Great</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-makes-this-book-so-great/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-makes-this-book-so-great/</guid><description>We need an SF laureate the way we have poet laureate. I nominate Jo.</description></item></channel></rss>