<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fairytales on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/fairytales/</link><description>Recent content in fairytales on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/fairytales/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Salt Grows Heavy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</guid><description>Truly grisly horror with a truly touching love story. Most fairytale retellings (here, The Little Mermaid) course-correct from the Disney versions back to Hans Christian Andersen territory. This overshoots Andersen by quite some distance, landing in the realm of rapacious colonizers and ghoulish Mengele-style war crimes.</description></item><item><title>A Sorceress Comes to Call</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</guid><description>I’m here all day long for T. Kingfisher’s aging, aching protagonists, with bad knees and big hearts and a well-honed sense of doom. The plot is a very loose retelling of The Goose Girl, minus princesses and kings and plus a conniving, murderous, sorceress mother. Evangeline, aka Doom, is determined to marry herself and her trapped, obedient daughter to the highest bidders in proper Regency-esque fashion, plans thwarted when she encounters a squire’s spinster sister who sees her for exactly who she is.</description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</guid><description>So this is everything a fairy tale should be. The only thing that didn’t work for me 100% was the romance side plot, but it was very sweet nonetheless, and I do understand that’s a common ingredient in fairy tales, and that for most it would be necessary.</description></item><item><title>Starlings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starlings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starlings/</guid><description>My favorite stories are clustered right in the middle: “What A Piece of Work,” “Parable Lost,” “What Would Sam Spade Do?” But the first story is where the heroine has the line that makes me laugh, clap, and cheer:
“Love? Well now. You feel what you feel, and I feel what I feel, but that doesn’t mean you have to fit us into a story and wreck both our lives.</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item></channel></rss>