<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gods-and-monsters on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/gods-and-monsters/</link><description>Recent content in gods-and-monsters on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/gods-and-monsters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Too Like the Lightning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</guid><description>Of course I’m immediately starting all over again after [[books/perhaps the stars|Perhaps The Stars]]. Every time, tingling chills down my spine on page 254:
I am the window through which you watch the coming storm. He is the lightning.
I can ditto [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]], who says, “I love this book with the passionate love of an exploding supernova, but every book isn’t for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Clockwork Boys</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clockwork-boys/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clockwork-boys/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mortal Follies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mortal-follies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Curse of Chalion</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-curse-of-chalion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-curse-of-chalion/</guid><description>It’s been easier lately for me to review the books I don’t like than the ones I do, because the ones I do, it’s just love, love, love. And it’s often difficult to articulate why.
This is one of the above. I just loved the… gentleness of it.</description></item><item><title>Gideon the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</guid><description>WOULD HAVE HARROWHARK’S BABIES.
I mean, it’s a good thing I like nice people in real life, because in fiction, Harrowhark is 10000% my type.
And just, 10/10 on working through your Catholic upbringing by writing meme-filled fic about blood sacrifice and redemption and necromancy and lesbian saints and cavaliers.</description></item><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Grace</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-grace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-grace/</guid><description>Oops, I did my thing of accidentally reading out of order. I was doing the audiobooks and went by the listing on Scribd (now Everand), which had them listed out of order. So I read book 2 first.
I don’t think that changed my opinion of anything.</description></item><item><title>Confounding Oaths</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/confounding-oaths/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/confounding-oaths/</guid><description>I was exactly in the mood for this. Cynical fairies and curses from the gods and a family in shambles. The romance is there, and quite lovely, but it’s off to one side, and that suits my mood too. The Caesar sisters and the Irregulars of the militia take up space on page, which makes me happy.</description></item><item><title>The Wonder Engine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-wonder-engine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-wonder-engine/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Paladin of Souls</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</guid><description>Magnificent. I didn’t think Bujold could top Cazaril as a character, and she does. Illvin and beloved Ista. Such a rich, full, scarred world she’s created. It spoke to me deeply, even more than the first. I cried. I felt joy-struck. Cursed, bitter Ista is also blessed, beloved Ista.</description></item><item><title>A Taste of Honey</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-taste-of-honey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-taste-of-honey/</guid><description>That ending! Talk about an ending that twists everything you thought you read for the previous 159 pages (I dare say, happily so).
Kai Ashante Williams [[books/the sorcerer of the wildeeps|messes with the genre bounds again]], melding psionics and telekinesis and Greek oracles as fluently as his languages.</description></item><item><title>Seven Surrenders</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</guid><description>There’s no way I can talk comprehensively about this series, so for now I’m just going to keep a running list of different things I notice each time I read them. This time (2/2023), it was how the many names for JEDD Mason echoes the [[notes/apophatic naming|apophatic naming]] of God, a classical theological strategy of the “negative” naming, an effort to call God by every time, thereby acknowledging and preserving God’s transcendence of all of them.</description></item><item><title>Harrow the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</guid><description>Amount of times this book made me cry: [redacted]. It is a sum equal to or only slightly less than the amount of times it made me cackle, gasp, and yelp.
“I cannot behold that apocalypse, Harrow. I think you are one of the only Lyctors who can really and truly understand apocalypse… It is not a death of fire.</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Strength</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-strength/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-strength/</guid><description>Oof, it pains me to say I had a tough time with this one. There was so much I liked—mainly CLARA—but it’s so unnecessarily long. Like at least a hundred pages too long because there’s so much repetition and angst and constant unresolved horniness. I love a road trip, I don’t mind a slow burn done right, but here the slow burn veers perilously close to miscommunication.</description></item><item><title>The Will to Battle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</guid><description>Reader, I cried like Mycroft Canner. It’s very much the first half of a whole (third quarter of four?), and it needs [[books/perhaps the stars|the last book]] to be complete, but what a feat it is on its own.</description></item><item><title>The Hallowed Hunt</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</guid><description>Not the heights of Ista or Cazaril, but going backwards in this timeline instead of forwards is a choice I admire. I can see returning to this one as often as the two favorites, especially if those two get worn out by re-reading.</description></item><item><title>The Descent of Monsters</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</guid><description>So we’re completely changing protagonists AND writing style AND partially the genre too? Hell yes! Basically it’s the official report on the fallout of the [[books/the red threads of fortune|second book]], done epistolary style (with redactions!), introducing major revelations of its own.
Loved it. Definitely doesn’t stand on its own—don’t start here.</description></item><item><title>Nona the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</guid><description>Verdict still stands after book three: would have Harrowhark’s babies.
The end of [[books/gideon the ninth|Gideon]] had some pacing things, the start of [[books/harrow the ninth|Harrow]] had some pacing things; Nona was the one I barreled through in 1.5 days because I could not put the book down.</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Hope</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-hope/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-hope/</guid><description>Not me, caught up in the spookiness more than the romance. The romance was still solid, though. The audiobooks remain excellent.</description></item><item><title>The Ascent to Godhood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ascent-to-godhood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ascent-to-godhood/</guid><description>There are [[notes/mosaic novel|mosaic novels]]—these are mosaic novellas. I can see being disappointed with one if you picked it up standalone, but as a collective, each book a different facet of the whole, it’s some brilliant, satisfying storytelling.
The villain of the first three books? Yeah, this is her story, told by her lover.</description></item><item><title>Perhaps the Stars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</guid><description>I still haven’t found the words to talk about this one. Maybe next year I will. It should be in the Smithsonian, or win the Nobel prize, or something, as one of humanity’s greatest achievements.</description></item><item><title>Frankenstein; or, the Modern Prometheus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/frankenstein/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/frankenstein/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Affair of the Mysterious Letter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</guid><description>The only thing I’ve had brain space for this week is Alexis Hall, and I say that as the highest compliment. He brings so much heart, joy, and snark even when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery. Or should I say, especially when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery.</description></item><item><title>The Palace of Eros</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</guid><description>My adjectives for the prose: purple, dense, florid, bloated. It sounds like I’m describing a corpse. DNF @ 15% because none of it is connecting with me, not the first-person Psyche nor the third-person Eros, nor the prose that’s turgid to the point of hyperbole. (Did I just want the chance to deploy the word turgid?</description></item><item><title>Lent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lent/</guid><description>It seems like every year there’s a book that I want to beg people to read because I struggle to describe it, and it’s nothing like what they’d expect. This year, it’s this book.
It’s beautiful. It’s delightful and unusual and quietly profound. It’s a master class in plot.</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item><item><title>The Second Safest Mountain</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-second-safest-mountain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-second-safest-mountain/</guid><description>What even is Otava Heikkilä’s brain? There are nuns and orgies and authoritarian patriarchal tentacle gods, and it maps completely onto the experience of being outcast in our world, for simply being true to yourself. As with [[books/shattered spear|Shattered Spear]], the images are more powerful than words.</description></item><item><title>The Saint of Bright Doors</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</guid><description>Gobsmacked at how good this is, without even the caveat of “for a first novel.” Fetter, the feral only child of a messiah, trained by his mother as assassin, destined to commit matricide and fratricide, navigates a dystopian Sri Lanka far too recognizable in the present.</description></item><item><title>Starling House</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</guid><description>After burning out on southern gothic, it delights me when there are authors that make it fresh again, doing something fun in the genre.
Here’s how you write horror in Kentucky. All of the elements, from the book-within-a-book to the lingering satanic panic to the generational trauma to the historical footnotes to the ecological elegy to the snarky wit, worked for me.</description></item><item><title>Exodus 20</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:55:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</guid><description>If you’re gonna write monster kink, make it a biblically accurate angel. And throw in some searing social/political/theological commentary. This was excellent.</description></item><item><title>Pantheologies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pantheologies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pantheologies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Flowering Wand</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-flowering-wand/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-flowering-wand/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>