<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>greece on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/greece/</link><description>Recent content in greece on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/greece/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Too Like the Lightning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</guid><description>Of course I’m immediately starting all over again after [[books/perhaps the stars|Perhaps The Stars]]. Every time, tingling chills down my spine on page 254:
I am the window through which you watch the coming storm. He is the lightning.
I can ditto [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]], who says, “I love this book with the passionate love of an exploding supernova, but every book isn’t for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Seven Surrenders</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</guid><description>There’s no way I can talk comprehensively about this series, so for now I’m just going to keep a running list of different things I notice each time I read them. This time (2/2023), it was how the many names for JEDD Mason echoes the [[notes/apophatic naming|apophatic naming]] of God, a classical theological strategy of the “negative” naming, an effort to call God by every time, thereby acknowledging and preserving God’s transcendence of all of them.</description></item><item><title>A Taste of Honey</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-taste-of-honey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-taste-of-honey/</guid><description>That ending! Talk about an ending that twists everything you thought you read for the previous 159 pages (I dare say, happily so).
Kai Ashante Williams [[books/the sorcerer of the wildeeps|messes with the genre bounds again]], melding psionics and telekinesis and Greek oracles as fluently as his languages.</description></item><item><title>The Will to Battle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</guid><description>Reader, I cried like Mycroft Canner. It’s very much the first half of a whole (third quarter of four?), and it needs [[books/perhaps the stars|the last book]] to be complete, but what a feat it is on its own.</description></item><item><title>Perhaps the Stars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</guid><description>I still haven’t found the words to talk about this one. Maybe next year I will. It should be in the Smithsonian, or win the Nobel prize, or something, as one of humanity’s greatest achievements.</description></item><item><title>Pagans</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</guid><description>About as beautifully (and concisely) written as you can get for a history book. Fabulous stuff. Some fav lines:
—Augustus revived a thing that had barely been invented in his own time: “old-time religion,” rather like the nearly postmodern version of Christianity invented in nineteenth-century America and called “fundamentalism.</description></item><item><title>The Castle of Crossed Destinies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-castle-of-crossed-destinies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-castle-of-crossed-destinies/</guid><description>A lot of [[authors/ludovico ariosto|Ariosto]], a little of [[authors/giovanni boccaccio|Boccaccio]], a lot of Homer, Sophocles, and Shakespeare and a little of [[authors/dante alighieri|Dante]] too. Had I not been recently indulging in all of those authors, the story might have lost me, but now it’s just in good company.</description></item><item><title>The Palace of Eros</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</guid><description>My adjectives for the prose: purple, dense, florid, bloated. It sounds like I’m describing a corpse. DNF @ 15% because none of it is connecting with me, not the first-person Psyche nor the third-person Eros, nor the prose that’s turgid to the point of hyperbole. (Did I just want the chance to deploy the word turgid?</description></item></channel></rss>