<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gender-bender on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/gender-bender/</link><description>Recent content in gender-bender on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/gender-bender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Too Like the Lightning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</guid><description>Of course I’m immediately starting all over again after [[books/perhaps the stars|Perhaps The Stars]]. Every time, tingling chills down my spine on page 254:
I am the window through which you watch the coming storm. He is the lightning.
I can ditto [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]], who says, “I love this book with the passionate love of an exploding supernova, but every book isn’t for everyone.</description></item><item><title>What Moves the Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</guid><description>Just what I wanted for October: brilliant gothic fanfiction of The Fall of the House of Usher with even more fungi than Poe. Creepy and exquisite, and that’s not just the cover art.
(With a bonus Beatrix Potter relative, clever worldbuilding linguistics w/r/t gender, and a hat tip to Prisoner of Zenda!</description></item><item><title>Prosperity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/prosperity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/prosperity/</guid><description>Adore it truly, deeply.</description></item><item><title>Something Fabulous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</guid><description>So far the theme of the year is romances that I read and then re-read right away and install on my best-of-year list (best-of-ever list too, in the case of Something Fabulous, which more than lives up to its name).
A few notes:
We’re starting to see the books written during the pandemic where authors are writing what they WANT, not what they SHOULD.</description></item><item><title>The Black Tides of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</guid><description>Note from my future self: this makes an excellent prequel, I should have started with [[books/the red threads of fortune|book 2]]!</description></item><item><title>Gideon the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</guid><description>WOULD HAVE HARROWHARK’S BABIES.
I mean, it’s a good thing I like nice people in real life, because in fiction, Harrowhark is 10000% my type.
And just, 10/10 on working through your Catholic upbringing by writing meme-filled fic about blood sacrifice and redemption and necromancy and lesbian saints and cavaliers.</description></item><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>Liberty &amp; Other Stories</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liberty-and-other-stories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liberty-and-other-stories/</guid><description>I did not think I could love the [[series/prosperityverse|Prosperityverse]] more, BUT I DO.</description></item><item><title>Something Spectacular</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</guid><description>You couldn’t write your own story in the margins of someone else’s.
I want to write something long and complex about the concept of family in this book (the Tarletons enfolding Valentine and Sir Horley and Periwinkle and practically every other stray into their own little world; the stitched-together warmth of the Delanceys’ parenting, wrapped around Peggy like a quilt; that spectacular ending of creating a new family when convention says it’s impossible).</description></item><item><title>The Red Threads of Fortune</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</guid><description>This should have been book 1! Or I should have done my typical thing of reading out of order and started here! The one time I try to be responsible and read a series in order, this is what happens.
Technically, these are “twin novellas,” but IMO, Mokoya is the emotional core of the story, followed by Rider, and Akeha in [[books/the black tides of heaven|Black Tides]] is an interesting prequel.</description></item><item><title>When the Tiger Came Down the Mountain</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/when-the-tiger-came-down-the-mountain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/when-the-tiger-came-down-the-mountain/</guid><description>Just as lush and complex as the [[books/the empress of salt and fortune|first one]], and given the smaller scope of the story, arguably my favorite of the two.</description></item><item><title>Seven Surrenders</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</guid><description>There’s no way I can talk comprehensively about this series, so for now I’m just going to keep a running list of different things I notice each time I read them. This time (2/2023), it was how the many names for JEDD Mason echoes the [[notes/apophatic naming|apophatic naming]] of God, a classical theological strategy of the “negative” naming, an effort to call God by every time, thereby acknowledging and preserving God’s transcendence of all of them.</description></item><item><title>Harrow the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</guid><description>Amount of times this book made me cry: [redacted]. It is a sum equal to or only slightly less than the amount of times it made me cackle, gasp, and yelp.
“I cannot behold that apocalypse, Harrow. I think you are one of the only Lyctors who can really and truly understand apocalypse… It is not a death of fire.</description></item><item><title>The Will to Battle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</guid><description>Reader, I cried like Mycroft Canner. It’s very much the first half of a whole (third quarter of four?), and it needs [[books/perhaps the stars|the last book]] to be complete, but what a feat it is on its own.</description></item><item><title>How to Belong with a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-belong-with-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-belong-with-a-billionaire/</guid><description>If there’s an author who could get me to love books with billionaire in the title, it’s Alexis Hall. Just like if there’s an author who could get me to love books with duke in the title, it’s going to be Alexis Hall’s [[books/a lady for a duke|upcoming historical romance]].</description></item><item><title>Something Extraordinary</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</guid><description>The high-strung Belle has left behind her heroine era, and the drama-prone Rufus has left behind his Sir Horley Comewithers era. Together they embark on the worst elopement kidnapping elopement in history (per Belle, it’s not vainglorious to claim that when it’s true), and what ensues is a meditation on friendship, love, sexuality, identity, self-discovery, society, and home in a way that only Alexis Hall can do it.</description></item><item><title>Into the Riverlands</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/into-the-riverlands/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/into-the-riverlands/</guid><description>Our traveling cleric Chih wanders into a wuxia novel, crossing paths with a pair of martial sisters and a polyamorous triad of rogue cultivators (MORE FANFIC ON THAT PLS!). It’s a road trip novella, replete with multiple stories within a story, rumination on reality vs. myth, and Almost Brilliant being brilliant.</description></item><item><title>The Descent of Monsters</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-descent-of-monsters/</guid><description>So we’re completely changing protagonists AND writing style AND partially the genre too? Hell yes! Basically it’s the official report on the fallout of the [[books/the red threads of fortune|second book]], done epistolary style (with redactions!), introducing major revelations of its own.
Loved it. Definitely doesn’t stand on its own—don’t start here.</description></item><item><title>Iris Kelly Doesn’t Date</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</guid><description>Yes to the gender-bending production of Much Ado About Nothing; yes to practice dating and sex lessons. Beyond that, the plot was a hot mess for me, trying to both validate Iris’s singledom yet ultimately get her in a relationship. I appreciate that Blake acknowledged the difficulty of walking that tightrope, and it is a rom-com—of course it’s gonna be an HEA.</description></item><item><title>Nona the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</guid><description>Verdict still stands after book three: would have Harrowhark’s babies.
The end of [[books/gideon the ninth|Gideon]] had some pacing things, the start of [[books/harrow the ninth|Harrow]] had some pacing things; Nona was the one I barreled through in 1.5 days because I could not put the book down.</description></item><item><title>Mammoths at the Gates</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mammoths-at-the-gates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:35:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mammoths-at-the-gates/</guid><description>Our beloved cleric Chih returns home to the Singing Hills monastery, only to find (spoiler alert) mammoths at the gates, an imperial delegation come to collect one of their own. A lovely mediation on grief, change, and love, through a plot revealed as always in the layers and sediment of myth.</description></item><item><title>The Ascent to Godhood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ascent-to-godhood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ascent-to-godhood/</guid><description>There are [[notes/mosaic novel|mosaic novels]]—these are mosaic novellas. I can see being disappointed with one if you picked it up standalone, but as a collective, each book a different facet of the whole, it’s some brilliant, satisfying storytelling.
The villain of the first three books? Yeah, this is her story, told by her lover.</description></item><item><title>The Left Hand of Darkness</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid><description>Imperfect and still utterly perfect. Favorite always.
The David Mitchell foreword
Picture if you will reading this book when it was published, 1969, the year of Stonewall
Gender, sex, romance, desire, power, nationalism, oppression… they’re all just stories we tell ourselves. And we can tell different stories if we choose.</description></item><item><title>Perhaps the Stars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</guid><description>I still haven’t found the words to talk about this one. Maybe next year I will. It should be in the Smithsonian, or win the Nobel prize, or something, as one of humanity’s greatest achievements.</description></item><item><title>The Brides of High Hill</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-brides-of-high-hill/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-brides-of-high-hill/</guid><description>Cleric Chih accompanies the bridal party of Pham Nhung to the estate of her potential husband, a man with monstrous secrets. For the first two acts, there are no stories-within-a-story, and no Almost Brilliant, in a way that indicates they’re connected—Chih keeps requesting to hear stories, but people refuse or prevaricate, until we miss the niexin as keenly as Chih does.</description></item><item><title>A Lady for a Duke</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-lady-for-a-duke/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-lady-for-a-duke/</guid><description>Re-read 11/24. Drastic measures were needed after so many historical romance duds lately, especially with duke in the title. I wanted something full of sweeping romance on a foggy moor, angst and glory and tenderness. This was the safest bet possible.
I liked it the first time, but I loved it this time.</description></item><item><title>Country Queers</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/country-queers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/country-queers/</guid><description>A book after my little southern queer heart. Garringer crisscrosses the Bible Belt, collecting a scrapbook and oral history of various LGBTQ+ people living in the rural margins. The older interviewees—the elders who survived the AIDS crisis and more—are the best and most emotional part. It’s easy to get miffed when people act like the Brooklyn or San Francisco subcultures are the only ones that matter, or like gay and trans people don’t exist in the south except to be persecuted.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>The Salt Grows Heavy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-salt-grows-heavy/</guid><description>Truly grisly horror with a truly touching love story. Most fairytale retellings (here, The Little Mermaid) course-correct from the Disney versions back to Hans Christian Andersen territory. This overshoots Andersen by quite some distance, landing in the realm of rapacious colonizers and ghoulish Mengele-style war crimes.</description></item><item><title>I Cross-Dressed for the IRL Meetup</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-cross-dressed-for-the-irl-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-cross-dressed-for-the-irl-meetup/</guid><description>I love seeing what Japanese manga does with gender. [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer’s]] essay on anime and manga has some of the historical context for it, but you don’t need a history lesson to enjoy this fun volume. I particularly liked the seamless inclusion of a trans girl alongside the cross-dressing boys, highlighting the differences and similarities among the two, and the lack of moral panic surrounding cross-dressing and gender in general.</description></item><item><title>Orlando</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Affair of the Mysterious Letter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</guid><description>The only thing I’ve had brain space for this week is Alexis Hall, and I say that as the highest compliment. He brings so much heart, joy, and snark even when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery. Or should I say, especially when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery.</description></item><item><title>We the Gathered Heat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:23:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</guid><description>Superb. This is how to do an anthology, where the disparate voices are the point—how do we even define AAPI except as “the other,” non-white? Who is the “we” in question? To whom is that category useful? The poems are sorted into themes of “mourn,” “pronounce,” “fight,” “love,” each as powerful as the last.</description></item><item><title>Come Out, Come Out</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</guid><description>In the same niche as [[books/camp damascus|Camp Damascus]], the conversion-therapy-as-horror genre. Similarities abound, even down to the senior class quarry jumps, which doesn’t indicate any co-opting of plot points but simply how ubiquitous this experience is, the same script across rural America, where any deviation from the script means there will be Consequences.</description></item><item><title>The Palace of Eros</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</guid><description>My adjectives for the prose: purple, dense, florid, bloated. It sounds like I’m describing a corpse. DNF @ 15% because none of it is connecting with me, not the first-person Psyche nor the third-person Eros, nor the prose that’s turgid to the point of hyperbole. (Did I just want the chance to deploy the word turgid?</description></item><item><title>Spear</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Second Safest Mountain</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-second-safest-mountain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-second-safest-mountain/</guid><description>What even is Otava Heikkilä’s brain? There are nuns and orgies and authoritarian patriarchal tentacle gods, and it maps completely onto the experience of being outcast in our world, for simply being true to yourself. As with [[books/shattered spear|Shattered Spear]], the images are more powerful than words.</description></item><item><title>On the Fox Roads</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</guid><description>Nghi Vo can write [[books/the chosen and the beautiful|queer Jazz Age fanfic]] for me all day any day. (Also excellent: the Venn diagram of her Chinese and Vietnamese characters, the overlapping similarities and the differences.)</description></item><item><title>Clear and Muddy Loss of Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</guid><description>This is just what I was in the mood for, a 300+ chapter, 4000 page sapphic slow burn court intrigue. The prose (and/or translation?) is more functional than beautiful on a sentence level, but on a plot level, with the overall character arcs, QJMX has some mad skill.</description></item><item><title>Siren Queen</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/siren-queen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/siren-queen/</guid><description>I’ve been saving this one to be my birthday book because I knew Nghi Vo would deliver. Hoo boy, did she ever. Fav of the year? What she does with queerness, horror, and myth is just chef’s kiss.</description></item><item><title>Three Kings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</guid><description>Another for my collection of killer opening lines:
Ethan Shaw carried two knives, one for lilies, the other for veins.
And the book just gets better and better from there. It counters all my usual problems with cozy witchy books, and sometimes cozy fantasy in general, not to mention the fraught subject of fertility.</description></item><item><title>Exodus 20</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:55:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</guid><description>If you’re gonna write monster kink, make it a biblically accurate angel. And throw in some searing social/political/theological commentary. This was excellent.</description></item></channel></rss>