<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>creative-practice on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/creative-practice/</link><description>Recent content in creative-practice on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/creative-practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>All transmission is recreation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-transmission-is-recreation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-transmission-is-recreation/</guid><description>Heyo, just like copyright, the notion of faithful reproduction is a very modern notion. And I’m gonna add Western industrialized notion—surely many if not all indigenous cultures still see the transmission of stories as re-creation.
A storyteller is a spinner of yarns, and the internet’s founding metaphor is of a web.</description></item><item><title>How do draw good</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-do-draw-good/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 22:15:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-do-draw-good/</guid><description>Basically the only art advice you need, by (I think) @bontext on tumblr:
![[images/howdodrawgood.jpg]]
How do write good I’ve modified it for writing as follows:
fill 14 note book bad stuff is good stuff bc you made stuff do you like sparkle???? write sparkle write what make your heart do the smiley emote member to drink lotsa aqua or else bad time d not stress friend all is well your work is hot like potato crisps don’t let anyone piss on your good mood amigo if they do eat them</description></item><item><title>The Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-carrier-bag-theory-of-fiction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-carrier-bag-theory-of-fiction/</guid><description>by [[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula K. Le Guin]]
Ed. note: just me copying and annotating this text in full, it’s that brilliant.
In the temperate and tropical regions where it appears that hominids evolved into human beings, the principal food of the species was vegetable.</description></item><item><title>Linguistic play as a writing exercise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</guid><description>[[authors/gretchen mcculloch|Gretchen McCulloch]], [[books/because internet|Because Internet]]:
I’ve taken up this sense of linguistic play as a writing exercise, especially when I’ve just read a bunch of academic papers and I’m having trouble shaking my thoughts free of Nominalization Accumulation Enunciation Contamination. Instead, I draft in Peak Internet Style, with no capitalization or punctuation, using acronyms and creative respelling to write my way through the muddle, rather than stopping when I don’t know how to articulate something or trying to sort through form and content at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Creativity should have fallow days too</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/creativity-should-have-fallow-days-too/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/creativity-should-have-fallow-days-too/</guid><description>Austin Kleon has written for years about the creative process of chain smoking. It’s never resonated with me; I can’t be that person of work every day even while a project is in progress. It ebbs and flows like the tide, days of rampant blooming interspersed with the fallow days of rootwork, day dreaming, glorious nothingness.</description></item></channel></rss>