<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>comfort-food on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/comfort-food/</link><description>Recent content in comfort-food on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/comfort-food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prosperity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/prosperity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/prosperity/</guid><description>Adore it truly, deeply.</description></item><item><title>10 Things That Never Happened</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</guid><description>It’s about grief and melancholy and connection and hope; it hit me so hard in the feels I cried through the last chapters. Outstanding use of the cheesy amnesia trope, a worthy homage to While You Were Sleeping. (Sam is absolutely the British Sandra Bullock.)</description></item><item><title>Something Fabulous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</guid><description>So far the theme of the year is romances that I read and then re-read right away and install on my best-of-year list (best-of-ever list too, in the case of Something Fabulous, which more than lives up to its name).
A few notes:
We’re starting to see the books written during the pandemic where authors are writing what they WANT, not what they SHOULD.</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 1</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-1/</guid><description>Back when I first read this, only the first Seven Seas volume had come out in the US. I thought I could just dip my toe in, get the gist, no harm done. I’d only read [[books/heaven official’s blessing vol 1|one other xianxia]] at that point and it was by the same author, so I’d just read others in the meantime to have more points of comparison by the time I got around to evaluating MDZS as a whole.</description></item><item><title>Glitterland</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/glitterland/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/glitterland/</guid><description>Give me any book where the hero is not conventional hero material, and is devalued by the world, and is the best person in the world anyway, and is unashamed to be themselves, and makes molehills out of mountains because they love freely and completely. I cried through the whole end because I am a marshmallow with a weakness for glitter pirates from Essex.</description></item><item><title>Something Spectacular</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</guid><description>You couldn’t write your own story in the margins of someone else’s.
I want to write something long and complex about the concept of family in this book (the Tarletons enfolding Valentine and Sir Horley and Periwinkle and practically every other stray into their own little world; the stitched-together warmth of the Delanceys’ parenting, wrapped around Peggy like a quilt; that spectacular ending of creating a new family when convention says it’s impossible).</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 2</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Waiting for the Flood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/waiting-for-the-flood/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/waiting-for-the-flood/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Something Extraordinary</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</guid><description>The high-strung Belle has left behind her heroine era, and the drama-prone Rufus has left behind his Sir Horley Comewithers era. Together they embark on the worst elopement kidnapping elopement in history (per Belle, it’s not vainglorious to claim that when it’s true), and what ensues is a meditation on friendship, love, sexuality, identity, self-discovery, society, and home in a way that only Alexis Hall can do it.</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 3</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 4</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-4/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 5</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-5/</guid><description/></item><item><title>You Made a Fool of Death with Your Beauty</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/you-made-a-fool-of-death-with-your-beauty/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/you-made-a-fool-of-death-with-your-beauty/</guid><description>Re-read. The widowed Feyi hooks up with a stranger, then dates his best friend Nasir, then falls in love with Nasir’s father, and none of that sentence captures the raw transcendence of this novel. It makes me not just cry, but weep, multiple times—not (only) because of the grief but because of the way it vibrates with life, with pain, with joy, with every raw emotion.</description></item><item><title>Minor Mage</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/minor-mage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/minor-mage/</guid><description>Oliver was already on his knees, but he bowed his head, feeling complicated things he didn’t know how to deal with. When kindness came from murdered ghosts and lost pigs, and the adults that were supposed to help you were monsters that walked like men… What was he supposed to do?</description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</guid><description>So this is everything a fairy tale should be. The only thing that didn’t work for me 100% was the romance side plot, but it was very sweet nonetheless, and I do understand that’s a common ingredient in fairy tales, and that for most it would be necessary.</description></item><item><title>Looking for Group</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/looking-for-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/looking-for-group/</guid><description>Very nearly chaste because there’s a different love language, and that makes it one of the most romantic books I’ve read.</description></item><item><title>The Affair of the Mysterious Letter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</guid><description>The only thing I’ve had brain space for this week is Alexis Hall, and I say that as the highest compliment. He brings so much heart, joy, and snark even when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery. Or should I say, especially when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery.</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item><item><title>The Magic Fish</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-magic-fish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-magic-fish/</guid><description>Wow. Absolutely lovely. Destroyed me in the best way.
And just on a visual level, what Nguyen does with the coloring for the different timelines, and the extensive notes on historical fashion and mythological context in the afterword make me appreciate it even more.</description></item><item><title>Everyone in This Room Will Someday Be Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:21:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</guid><description>This is the most strongly coded [[notes/autism|autistic]] protagonist I’ve read. Especially of the female, high-masking, chronic burnout variety, and undiagnosed. (Or rather, insufficiently diagnosed with anxiety and depression.) The unconscious stimming! Chronic sensory overload! The shutdowns! The meltdowns! The masking!
I feel like I am operating my body like it’s a vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Interesting Facts about Space</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</guid><description>Me [page 1]: I’m worried I read too much about [[notes/autism|ASD]] into [[books/everyone in this room will someday be dead|Everyone in This Room Will Someday be Dead]]. This time I’m gonna look for all the ways it’s not autism. I will counteract my bias.
Me [page 20]: This is autism.</description></item><item><title>Band Sinister</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</guid><description>If this isn’t everything that’s wholesome and good in the world, I don’t know what is. A tribute to Heyer indeed; it just includes those who paint with oils outside conventional lines. It cranked my heart open without being saccharine or heavy. One of those books where I have to be careful what I read next because it might not measure up.</description></item></channel></rss>