<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pleasure-and-play on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/pleasure-and-play/</link><description>Recent content in pleasure-and-play on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/pleasure-and-play/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You’re a wiggle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/wiggles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/wiggles/</guid><description>[[authors/alan watts|Alan Watts]] in [[books/out of your mind|Out of Your Mind]]:
See, the physical world is wiggly. Clouds, mountains, trees, people—everything is wiggly. It’s only when human beings get working on things that they build buildings in straight lines and try to make the world unwiggly.</description></item><item><title>What’s the point if we can’t have fun?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/whats-the-point-if-we-cant-have-fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/whats-the-point-if-we-cant-have-fun/</guid><description>In the essay What’s the point if we can’t have fun?, [[authors/david graeber|David Graeber]] argues that we’re fools for focusing on rational explanations and economic terms in animal behavior, and for undervaluing play.
Why do animals play? Why does the existence of action carried out for the sheer pleasure of acting strike us as mysterious?</description></item><item><title>Play gives meaning to life</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-gives-meaning-to-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-gives-meaning-to-life/</guid><description>Play gives meaning to life, wrote the Dutch historian Johan Huizinga back in 1938. He christened us homo ludens—‘playing man.’ Everything we call ‘culture,’ said Huizinga, originates in play.1
Almost all mammals play, and many other animals can’t resist. It’s the most intelligent animals that exhibit the most playful behavior.</description></item><item><title>Playfulness vs. epistemic traps</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/playfulness-vs-epistemic-traps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/playfulness-vs-epistemic-traps/</guid><description>A pre-print by C. Thi Nguyen, full download here.</description></item><item><title>Linguistic play as a writing exercise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</guid><description>[[authors/gretchen mcculloch|Gretchen McCulloch]], [[books/because internet|Because Internet]]:
I’ve taken up this sense of linguistic play as a writing exercise, especially when I’ve just read a bunch of academic papers and I’m having trouble shaking my thoughts free of Nominalization Accumulation Enunciation Contamination. Instead, I draft in Peak Internet Style, with no capitalization or punctuation, using acronyms and creative respelling to write my way through the muddle, rather than stopping when I don’t know how to articulate something or trying to sort through form and content at the same time.</description></item><item><title>How do draw good</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-do-draw-good/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-do-draw-good/</guid><description>Basically the only art advice you need, by (I think) @bontext on tumblr:
![[images/howdodrawgood.jpg]]
How do write good I’ve modified it for writing as follows:
fill 14 note book bad stuff is good stuff bc you made stuff do you like sparkle???? write sparkle write what make your heart do the smiley emote member to drink lotsa aqua or else bad time d not stress friend all is well your work is hot like potato crisps don’t let anyone piss on your good mood amigo if they do eat them</description></item><item><title>Pleasure is therapeutic</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pleasure-is-therapeutic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pleasure-is-therapeutic/</guid><description>In Who Gets to Medicate Me?, Jesse Meadows (@sluggish) interrogates the cultural, puritanical idea that pleasure is destructive.
Psychoactive drugs have direct effects on us, and sometimes those effects feel good, which can be helpful in itself. Puritanical thought and anti-drug propaganda have led us to think of pleasure as destructive, but pleasure can be therapeutic, too.</description></item><item><title>The necessity of third places</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-necessity-of-third-places/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-necessity-of-third-places/</guid><description>Ray Oldenberg coined the term “third place” in 1989 to describe our social centers. In the OG definition, the first place is home, the second place is work. The third place is a shared place to socialize that’s neither home nor work, distinguished by conversation and [[notes/play gives meaning to life|playfulness]], familiar faces but no formal membership, freedom to come and go as you please, home away from home.</description></item></channel></rss>