<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pleasure-and-play on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/pleasure-and-play/</link><description>Recent content in pleasure-and-play on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/pleasure-and-play/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>All transmission is recreation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-transmission-is-recreation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-transmission-is-recreation/</guid><description>Heyo, just like copyright, the notion of faithful reproduction is a very modern notion. And I’m gonna add Western industrialized notion—surely many if not all indigenous cultures still see the transmission of stories as re-creation.
A storyteller is a spinner of yarns, and the internet’s founding metaphor is of a web.</description></item><item><title>Cooperation is a form of pleasure and play in itself</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cooperation-is-a-form-of-pleasure-and-play-in-itself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cooperation-is-a-form-of-pleasure-and-play-in-itself/</guid><description>An alternative school of Darwinism emerged in Russia emphasizing cooperation, not competition, as the driver of evolutionary change—see [[books/mutual aid|Mutual Aid]] by [[authors/pyotr kropotkin|Pyotr Kropotkin]]. It’s not just about cooperation as a means to an end though—Kropotkin posits that cooperation is a form of pleasure and social play in itself.</description></item><item><title>Fear destroys curiosity and playfulness</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fear-destroys-curiosity-and-playfulness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fear-destroys-curiosity-and-playfulness/</guid><description>You cannot be curious and playful when you’re afraid. Any healthy individual and healthy society must be able to safely play and learn.
Fear destroys curiosity and playfulness. In order to have a healthy society we must raise children who can safely play and learn.</description></item><item><title>Physicists are the poets of the scientific world</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/physicists-are-the-poets-of-the-scientific-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/physicists-are-the-poets-of-the-scientific-world/</guid><description>Physicists are the poets of the scientific world, more playful and less hidebound creatures than, say, biologists—once you can embrace alternate universes, dark matter, and quantum physics, it’s not much of a leap for other things.
Curiously, it’s largely physicists who have proved receptive to such ideas.</description></item><item><title>Play could be the basis of physical reality</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-could-be-the-basis-of-physical-reality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-could-be-the-basis-of-physical-reality/</guid><description>The principle of play repeats so often in nature, it’s worth asking whether it’s the basis of physical reality. That’s not as wild an assertion as it seems, and even more plausible and less inconsistent than our image of a mindless robotic universe.
I don’t deny that what I’ve presented so far is a savage simplification of very complicated issues.</description></item><item><title>Play is not an anomaly</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-is-not-an-anomaly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-is-not-an-anomaly/</guid><description>What if we treated play as our starting point? Not as an anomaly, but a principle to every self-organizing system?
What would happen if we proceeded from the reverse perspective and agreed to treat play not as some peculiar anomaly, but as our starting point, a principle already present not just in lobsters and indeed all living creatures, but also on every level where we find what physicists, chemists, and biologists refer to as “self-organizing systems”?</description></item><item><title>Pleasure can be therapeutic</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pleasure-can-be-therapeutic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pleasure-can-be-therapeutic/</guid><description>In Who Gets to Medicate Me?, Jesse Meadows (@sluggish) interrogates the cultural, puritanical idea that pleasure is destructive.
Psychoactive drugs have direct effects on us, and sometimes those effects feel good, which can be helpful in itself. Puritanical thought and anti-drug propaganda have led us to think of pleasure as destructive, but pleasure can be therapeutic, too.</description></item><item><title>We are doing exactly what the fish are doing</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-doing-exactly-what-the-fish-are-doing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-doing-exactly-what-the-fish-are-doing/</guid><description>[[authors/david graeber|David Graeber]] says that when he taught at Yale, he would assign a reading of the following Taoist story, offering an automatic “A” to any student who could tell him why the last line made sense. (None ever succeeded.)
Zhuangzi and Huizi were strolling on a bridge over the River Hao, when the former observed, “See how the minnows dart between the rocks!</description></item><item><title>How do draw good</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-do-draw-good/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 22:15:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-do-draw-good/</guid><description>Basically the only art advice you need, by (I think) @bontext on tumblr:
![[images/howdodrawgood.jpg]]
How do write good I’ve modified it for writing as follows:
fill 14 note book bad stuff is good stuff bc you made stuff do you like sparkle???? write sparkle write what make your heart do the smiley emote member to drink lotsa aqua or else bad time d not stress friend all is well your work is hot like potato crisps don’t let anyone piss on your good mood amigo if they do eat them</description></item><item><title>The necessity of third places</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-necessity-of-third-places/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:44:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-necessity-of-third-places/</guid><description>Ray Oldenberg coined the term “third place” in 1989 to describe our social centers. In the OG definition, the first place is home, the second place is work. The third place is a shared place to socialize that’s neither home nor work, distinguished by conversation and [[notes/play gives meaning to life|playfulness]], familiar faces but no formal membership, freedom to come and go as you please, home away from home.</description></item><item><title>We are wiggles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-wiggles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-wiggles/</guid><description>The physical world is wiggly as all get-out! We are the ones who try to box things in with our concrete categories and straight lines.
See, the physical world is wiggly. Clouds, mountains, trees, people—everything is wiggly. It’s only when human beings get working on things that they build buildings in straight lines and try to make the world unwiggly.</description></item><item><title>What’s the point if we can’t have fun?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/whats-the-point-if-we-cant-have-fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/whats-the-point-if-we-cant-have-fun/</guid><description>In the essay What’s the point if we can’t have fun?, [[authors/david graeber|David Graeber]] argues that we’re foolish for focusing only on rational explanations and economic terms in animal behavior, and for undervaluing play.
Why do animals play? Well, why shouldn’t they? The real question is: Why does the existence of action carried out for the sheer pleasure of acting, the exertion of powers for the sheer pleasure of exerting them, strike us as mysterious?</description></item><item><title>Play gives meaning to life</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-gives-meaning-to-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-gives-meaning-to-life/</guid><description>Almost all mammals play, and many other animals can’t resist. It’s the most intelligent animals that exhibit the most playful behavior. Domesticated animals play their whole lives.
Play gives meaning to life, wrote the Dutch historian Johan Huizinga back in 1938. He christened us homo ludens—‘playing man.</description></item><item><title>Playfulness vs. epistemic traps</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/playfulness-vs-epistemic-traps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/playfulness-vs-epistemic-traps/</guid><description>A pre-print by C. Thi Nguyen, full download here.</description></item><item><title>Linguistic play as a writing exercise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</guid><description>[[authors/gretchen mcculloch|Gretchen McCulloch]], [[books/because internet|Because Internet]]:
I’ve taken up this sense of linguistic play as a writing exercise, especially when I’ve just read a bunch of academic papers and I’m having trouble shaking my thoughts free of Nominalization Accumulation Enunciation Contamination. Instead, I draft in Peak Internet Style, with no capitalization or punctuation, using acronyms and creative respelling to write my way through the muddle, rather than stopping when I don’t know how to articulate something or trying to sort through form and content at the same time.</description></item></channel></rss>