<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>satire on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/satire/</link><description>Recent content in satire on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/satire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Inferno</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</guid><description>So good to read this while steeped in Florentine history. These are real people and real places, not just an abstract Lewis-esque allegory. Now I wish I knew Italian to read his terza rima original, especially since I’ve had to dig through the Longfellow to see what’s underneath.</description></item><item><title>Purgatorio</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</guid><description>Reading this alongside Guido Ruggiero’s [[books/the renaissance in italy|The Renaissance in Italy]] is A+ recommended. Once again, vastly more interesting than my first exposure, where school curriculum wanted it read like it was Pilgrim’s Progress. I needed the Bondanella introduction back then to dispense with the nonsense: “Such allegorical abstractions are simply not what Dante’s great poem is all about.</description></item><item><title>Paradiso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</guid><description>My dilemma since the early years of Sunday school: hell is more interesting than paradise. Thus, true to form, though I wanted to be contrary, [[books/inferno|Inferno]] is more interesting than any amount of heavenly light (so bright! so much dancing!), but get to that last line and you can’t help but feel the awe and poetry of it:</description></item><item><title>Ficciones</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ficciones/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ficciones/</guid><description>Borges is up to some delightful fuckery, playing with form, inventing books and authors and universes that are just as, to paraphrase, contaminated with fiction as our own history of the world. The stories are brief and vertiginous, mind-boggling and often cheeky. An undisputed masterpiece, even if I’m still partial to [[authors/italo calvino|Calvino]], even if Calvino himself would disagree with me (per his essay on Borges in [[books/six memos for the next millennium|Six Memos for the Next Millennium]]).</description></item><item><title>Lessons from Cruising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</guid><description>Joke’s on me, because I picked up this ARC for the last story, a retelling of Billy Budd from Captain Vere’s point of view. I figured I’d sample the rest; instead I went down the buffet line and inhaled them all. Rarely do I like every story in a short story collection, but that’s what Goodman’s done to me.</description></item><item><title>Lesley Castle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lesley-castle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lesley-castle/</guid><description>I like the goodreads review that says “So you think you are a writer. Read this slim volume and weep.” Austen did this at sixteen, and it’s unpardonably good for any writer, much less someone that young. The one fault of the slim volume is that it is indeed slim.</description></item><item><title>Juliette</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/juliette/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/juliette/</guid><description>I rarely do this, but there’s another review that says it so well, I’m going to quote it instead of trying to sum up my own thoughts:
Sade the philosopher is in force, and his treatises — like his other novels delivered by key characters — are interspersed with the sex and violence one expects.</description></item><item><title>Justine, Philosophy in the Bedroom, and Other Writings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/justine-philosophy-in-the-bedroom-and-other-writings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/justine-philosophy-in-the-bedroom-and-other-writings/</guid><description>Thank you, [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]]. I had my suspicions about Sade, that more was going on than just some shock and awe erotica, and in [[books/too like the lightning|Too Like The Lightning]], when he becomes part of the dialogue in a key way, she makes it clear that to read Sade as sadism is too narrow a view.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</guid><description>A note on translation: I used Reynolds to compare, contrast, and fill in the gaps with the [[books/orlando furioso a new verse translation|Slavitt translation]]. Slavitt takes liberties, and Reynolds has merit, but I’ve got to say, for compulsive readability, and cheeky irreverence that feels like it honors the spirit of the original, Slavitt it is.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso: A New Verse Translation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</guid><description>Ariosto writing like AO3 was a thing in the sixteenth century. I love it. Fiendishly clever layers of satire; a story where anything goes.</description></item><item><title>Yellowface</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</guid><description>After witnessing the accidental death of her frenemy Athena Liu, failed author June Hayward refashions herself as Juniper Song and steals Athena’s posthumous masterpiece to pass it off as her own. Cue white woman tears, as she’s victimized and vilified by the consequences of her own egregious actions.</description></item><item><title>Cat’s Cradle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/cats-cradle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/cats-cradle/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>