<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>class-politics on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/class-politics/</link><description>Recent content in class-politics on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/class-politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Duke at Hazard</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</guid><description>I have a few auto-buy (auto-preorder) authors, but KJ Charles is the only one where I drop everything to start reading the day a new book comes out. Here, that impatience is rewarded with a tender, slow-blooming romance-on-the-run between Daizell, a disgraced non-scoundrel scoundrel (he’s paying for the sins of his father), and Cassian, aka The Duke, aka Vernon Fortescue Cassian George de Vere Crosse, the fourth Duke of Severn, the Earl of Harmsford, Baron Crosse of Wotton, and Baron Vere, who’s incognito for a month to hunt down a thief and win a wager (he’s burdened with the premature inheritance of his father’s title).</description></item><item><title>Abolish Rent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</guid><description>An enthusiastic and persuasive manifesto on housing rights as human rights. It’s encouraging to see such robust organizing among tenants across the country, and the practical template for how to expand it. The authors rightly quote [[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula Le Guin]]: our housing system is a human power—produced by people, not God or nature.</description></item><item><title>Emma</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma/</guid><description>Emma in context Since this was a re-read after [[books/jane austen the secret radical|Jane Austen, The Secret Radical]], I’m going to put my relevant highlights from that book here.</description></item><item><title>Jane Austen, the Secret Radical</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jane-austen-the-secret-radical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jane-austen-the-secret-radical/</guid><description>Superb and long-overdue reevaluation of Jane Austen and the context in which she wrote her beloved novels. For many people, I imagine “radical” is the word in the subtitle that lifts eyebrows; for me, it’s the word “secret.” Austen’s politics have always felt clear on the page, and this is how I’ve read her, even lacking some of the well-researched context Helena Kelly provides here.</description></item><item><title>Mansfield Park</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mansfield-park/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mansfield-park/</guid><description>Mansfield Park in context Since this was a re-read after [[books/jane austen the secret radical|Jane Austen, The Secret Radical]], I’m going to put my relevant highlights from that book here.</description></item><item><title>Pride and Prejudice</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pride-and-prejudice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pride-and-prejudice/</guid><description>Austen is so compulsively readable that I’ve already accomplished my re-read of Pride and Prejudice too. And don’t worry, I’m not about to be the killjoy that strips the romance from it this time. This novel is romantic, a true meeting of minds with the happiest ending Jane Austen has on offer.</description></item><item><title>Sense and Sensibility</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sense-and-sensibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sense-and-sensibility/</guid><description>The Austen re-read commences, while [[authors/helena kelly|Helena Kelly’s]] book is fresh in my mind. And hoo boy does it benefit from close reading.
I’m already predisposed to read Jane Austen politically, and I’m already inclined to claim Sense and Sensibility is Austen venting her spleen at the English inheritance law instead of a swoony romance.</description></item><item><title>Sister Outsider</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sister-outsider/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sister-outsider/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Room with a View</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-room-with-a-view/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-room-with-a-view/</guid><description>It was the old, old battle of the room with the view.
Wow. Re-read in one sitting. I was only going to read the Florence bits, but then I just didn’t stop. This is why I’m a fan of coming back to books at different ages with different eyes and different contexts, because it makes them different books.</description></item><item><title>Howards End</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/howards-end/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/howards-end/</guid><description>At least this one holds up to my initial perception; it’s still my least favorite of the Forster novels.* The energy and wit are a feast for the senses, especially in the dialogue, but it’s so much about England and Empire, it gets, dare I say… tiresome?</description></item><item><title>Maurice</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/maurice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/maurice/</guid><description>I love this book because the characters are awful and snobby and wrong about so many things. Just like we’re awful and snobby and wrong in our own times. No historical revisionism, and still a happy ending. There’s great beauty within.
Not far from the lodge there was a nasty little climb, and the road, always in bad condition, was edged with dog roses that scratched the paint.</description></item><item><title>Yellowface</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</guid><description>After witnessing the accidental death of her frenemy Athena Liu, failed author June Hayward refashions herself as Juniper Song and steals Athena’s posthumous masterpiece to pass it off as her own. Cue white woman tears, as she’s victimized and vilified by the consequences of her own egregious actions.</description></item><item><title>Giovanni’s Room</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</guid><description>Not everyone in book club was a fan, but I loved it, but it was brutal, but I’m glad I read it, but I’m glad I won’t be in a rush to read it again.
“Somebody,” said Jacques, “your father or mine, should have told us that not many people have ever died of love.</description></item></channel></rss>