<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>islam on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/islam/</link><description>Recent content in islam on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/islam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>Paris Daillencourt is About to Crumble</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</guid><description>Once again Alexis Hall takes away the book I thought I wanted and replaces it with the book I actually need.
Reading this at the same time as [[books/the body keeps the score|The Body Keeps the Score]], though, just means I’m peeking between the lines of all the parental neglect and trauma and thinking, dearest Paris, get thee to some somatic therapy, medication is just a start.</description></item><item><title>Forest of Noise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</guid><description>How do you write the unimaginable? How do you craft art from the horror? How do you count your loved ones, now dead, in lines of poems?
I read this twice, once fast, once slow, and let it break me. 50 years of occupation and apartheid.</description></item><item><title>On Palestine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</guid><description>Many of the world’s problems are so intractable that it’s hard to think of ways even to take steps toward mitigating them.
The Israel-Palestine conflict is not one of these.
I admit I’ve fallen prey to the line, re: the occupation of Palestine, “it’s too complex to understand.</description></item><item><title>A Woman Is No Man</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</guid><description>We need more books by Palestinian and Arab authors. I intend to read more by Etaf Rum. But it pains me to say… I think this could have been a (powerful) short story. The structure and even dialogue is very repetitive, in a way that I’m sure is meant to illustrate the cyclical and generational cycle of abuse, but instead means you could skim chapters and not miss anything.</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item></channel></rss>