<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>geopolitical on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/geopolitical/</link><description>Recent content in geopolitical on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/geopolitical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Left Hand of Darkness</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid><description>Imperfect and still utterly perfect. Favorite always.
The David Mitchell foreword
Picture if you will reading this book when it was published, 1969, the year of Stonewall
Gender, sex, romance, desire, power, nationalism, oppression… they’re all just stories we tell ourselves. And we can tell different stories if we choose.</description></item><item><title>The Dispossessed</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dispossessed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dispossessed/</guid><description>Sublime. Carefully constructed, nuanced, warmly empathetic, passionately human, complex. If you want a rose-colored ideologue that purports to fix problems with simplistic utopias, look elsewhere. If you want an accounting of our society’s ills, and alternatives that are just as complicated and imperfect, you’re in the right place.</description></item><item><title>Dirty Wars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/dirty-wars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/dirty-wars/</guid><description>[Insert string of obscenities] at the things the United States has done. The best thing this book does is make it perfectly clear there isn’t right-wing or left-wing. It spans two crucial presidencies (Bush II and Obama), and the substantive difference is that the former worried how far they could push things and the latter did not care.</description></item><item><title>Manufacturing Consent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/manufacturing-consent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/manufacturing-consent/</guid><description>Infuriatingly and terrifyingly relevant. Like, up to this very day, where you couldn’t even update the book with current examples because there are too many to choose from. Venezuela, Syria, Iran. Ad infinitum. It’s all following the same script. Where you could argue the book is dated, that actually further proves its point, such as the west’s support and glorification of Putin thirty years ago when he fit their needs in a different way.</description></item><item><title>On Genocide</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-genocide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-genocide/</guid><description>Sartre in 1967:
When a peasant falls in his rice paddy, mowed down by a machine gun, every one of us is hit. The Vietnamese fight for all men and the American forces against all. Neither figuratively nor abstractly. And not only because genocide would be a crime universally condemned by international law, but because little by little the whole human race is being subjected to this genocidal blackmail piled on top of atomic blackmail, that is, to absolute, total war.</description></item><item><title>Propaganda Blitz</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/propaganda-blitz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/propaganda-blitz/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rakesfall</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rakesfall/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rakesfall/</guid><description>For the first half of this, it’s very much a sister-book to [[books/the saint of bright doors|The Saint of Bright Doors]]. If you didn’t like that one, you probably won’t vibe with this one. But if, like me, you loved Saint, then Rakesfall levels up and then some.</description></item><item><title>The Saint of Bright Doors</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</guid><description>Gobsmacked at how good this is, without even the caveat of “for a first novel.” Fetter, the feral only child of a messiah, trained by his mother as assassin, destined to commit matricide and fratricide, navigates a dystopian Sri Lanka far too recognizable in the present.</description></item><item><title>The Prince</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-prince/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-prince/</guid><description>Non-negotiable: read [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer’s]] five-part (plus?) series on Machiavelli. I’ll wait. She makes sense of the enigma, the real Machiavelli, neither lionized nor maligned. The brave thinker; the frightened statesman. Charismatic, unorthodox, forming a response to the Borgia tyranny, trying to save his beloved Florence, playing pranks on the monks, centuries ahead of his time.</description></item><item><title>Pagans</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 12:34:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</guid><description>About as beautifully (and concisely) written as you can get for a history book. Fabulous stuff. Some fav lines:
—Augustus revived a thing that had barely been invented in his own time: “old-time religion,” rather like the nearly postmodern version of Christianity invented in nineteenth-century America and called “fundamentalism.</description></item><item><title>Clear and Muddy Loss of Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</guid><description>This is just what I was in the mood for, a 300+ chapter, 4000 page sapphic slow burn court intrigue. The prose (and/or translation?) is more functional than beautiful on a sentence level, but on a plot level, with the overall character arcs, QJMX has some mad skill.</description></item><item><title>The Twice-Drowned Saint</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-twice-drowned-saint/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-twice-drowned-saint/</guid><description>I don’t even know how the hell to describe this, except amazing. Apparently my unintentional theme lately is biblically accurate angels—see [[books/pet|Pet]], see [[books/exodus 20|Freydís Moon]]. Here, Cooney made the mythology its own thing and the worldbuilding is fiendishly clever. A refugee crisis in the midst of a celestial city with bloodthirsty angels who must be overthrown by two secret saints, a newly-sprouted godhead, and a family of filmmakers and waste collectors—that’s the best stab I can take at the plot.</description></item><item><title>China Mountain Zhang</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Lathe Of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</guid><description>I can’t remember the last time I read a book with a truly passive protagonist, where his qualities are not his weakness, but his strength. He doesn’t change who he is. There is no lesson needed. He is the virtue, not the flaw. Le Guin stacks George Orr up against the passionate Huber who wants to save the world, and carefully and thoroughly makes the case for the former.</description></item><item><title>The Word for World is Forest</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-word-for-world-is-forest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-word-for-world-is-forest/</guid><description>This is how I like a thinly-veiled parable to work, especially an anti-colonialism one.
(There’s barely any need for fiction; it’s Vietnam.)</description></item></channel></rss>