<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>working-theories on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/working-theories/</link><description>Recent content in working-theories on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/working-theories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Confusion is a crucible</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/confusion-is-a-crucible/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/confusion-is-a-crucible/</guid><description>On the whole radical acceptance front, even confusion—especially confusion—can be enormously helpful in our lives. It points to where the soil needs to be tilled, old ways dug up and new ways cultivated and planted.
The idea that confusion could have therapeutic value is powerful because it takes a human condition that’s generally thought to be negative and suggests that it could actually be a kind of crucible.</description></item><item><title>How to detect manipulation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-detect-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-detect-manipulation/</guid><description>If you feel muddled, scrambled, disoriented, that’s a sign of psychological manipulation/distortion, or often downright abuse. If you feel clarity, even if it’s challenging and uncomfortable, you’re likely on to something true.
Note: to me this is different than feeling uncertain. Uncertainty is an honest and even necessary state, open to inquiry and reflection.</description></item><item><title>Purity and supremacy go hand-in-hand</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/purity-and-supremacy-go-hand-in-hand/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/purity-and-supremacy-go-hand-in-hand/</guid><description>This has been one of my private working theories for years, and the more I see confirms it. Any aspiration towards purity—be it spiritual, moral, ideological, cultural, political, on and on—leads to supremacy. The concept of purity means that impurity exists, so you’re drawing a line between the two, and placing yourself on the side that is elevated, superior, preferred.</description></item><item><title>Our sense of the erotic is more plastic than we think</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-sense-of-the-erotic-is-more-plastic-than-we-think/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-sense-of-the-erotic-is-more-plastic-than-we-think/</guid><description>How fluid is our sense of the erotic? Like neurological plasticity, probably a lot more fluid than we think.
Whether it involves livestock or people, this sexual-imprinting process (in which a highly circumscribed set of erotic targets is stamped early into the individual’s brain) appears to be a decidedly male characteristic.</description></item><item><title>Conservation of novelty</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/conservation-of-novelty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/conservation-of-novelty/</guid><description>We are the inheritors of all the complexity that proceeded us.
Each stage of advancement into novelty, into complexity, into concrescence, has proceeded more quickly than the phase which preceded it. The universe is in a state of asymptotic acceleration of some sort.</description></item><item><title>Enshittification</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/enshittification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/enshittification/</guid><description>Cory Doctorow on the enshittification of TikTok:
Here is how platforms die: first, they are good to their users; then they abuse their users to make things better for their business customers; finally, they abuse those business customers to claw back all the value for themselves.</description></item><item><title>What’s the point if we can’t have fun?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/whats-the-point-if-we-cant-have-fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/whats-the-point-if-we-cant-have-fun/</guid><description>In the essay What’s the point if we can’t have fun?, [[authors/david graeber|David Graeber]] argues that we’re foolish for focusing only on rational explanations and economic terms in animal behavior, and for undervaluing play.
Why do animals play? Well, why shouldn’t they? The real question is: Why does the existence of action carried out for the sheer pleasure of acting, the exertion of powers for the sheer pleasure of exerting them, strike us as mysterious?</description></item><item><title>Rhizomatic thinking is non-hierarchal and relational</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/rhizomatic-thinking-is-non-hierarchal-and-relational/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/rhizomatic-thinking-is-non-hierarchal-and-relational/</guid><description>The rhizome was adopted as a philosophical concept to describe a process of existence and growth with no clear hierarchy or single central point of origin. It doesn’t start from anywhere or end anywhere; it grows from everywhere, can reproduce from any node, and has no center, which makes it difficult to uproot or destroy.</description></item><item><title>Multiple intelligence theory</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/multiple-intelligence-theory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/multiple-intelligence-theory/</guid><description>Howard Gardner first outlined his theory in his 1983 book Frames of Mind, where he suggested that all people have different kinds of intelligence.
He proposed that there are eight intelligences, and has suggested the possible addition of a ninth known as “existentialist intelligence.”
Linguistic intelligence—a deep-rooted understanding and nuanced use of language, a proficiency that goes beyond fluency.</description></item><item><title>Choosing the familiar doesn’t take you somewhere new</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/choosing-the-familiar-doesnt-take-you-somewhere-new/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/choosing-the-familiar-doesnt-take-you-somewhere-new/</guid><description>When you’re stuck or encountering an obstacle: choosing the least familiar path is the best way forward. Going with what feels safe can keep you stuck in that loop. Forging new terrain, scary as it is, is the way to get somewhere better.
Oftentimes, you might feel that you’re stuck between a rock and hard place—there are two sets of unpleasant feelings, one on either side, that you’re having to choose between.</description></item></channel></rss>