<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>questions on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/questions/</link><description>Recent content in questions on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/questions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is fear of groupthink another pursuit of purity?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/is-fear-of-groupthink-another-pursuit-of-purity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/is-fear-of-groupthink-another-pursuit-of-purity/</guid><description>Is ridding yourself of all “groupthink” another pursuit of purity? Does the quest for purity only happen within the groupthink/ideology? Are there elements of “groupthink” that are merely the human traits as a communal species? Like censorship, there has never been some ideal state without it, only existing to various healthy or toxic degrees?</description></item><item><title>Self-organizing systems of vast complexity are the way of the world</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-organizing-systems-of-vast-complexity-are-the-way-of-the-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-organizing-systems-of-vast-complexity-are-the-way-of-the-world/</guid><description>We get in trouble when we try to impose external, hierarchical order on ourselves—much like how monoculture fails to thrive, and instead entangled ecosystems are key.
If you think chaos is the only result of a non-hierarchal system, your own body disproves it. Try to get your mind to tell your lungs to breathe, your heart to beat, your stomach to digest, your skin to sweat, your colon to poop.</description></item><item><title>Could kinesiology explain the phenomenon of faith healing?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/could-kinesiology-explain-the-phenomenon-of-faith-healing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/could-kinesiology-explain-the-phenomenon-of-faith-healing/</guid><description>Can kinesiology—specifically the therapeutic practices of body talk, acupressure, emotional stress release, etc.—explain what’s occurring in many instances of faith healing?
In the Pentecostal tradition that I grew up in (and escaped from), faith healing often happens in a highly charged environment, with lots of prayer (meditation), and emotional catharsis.</description></item><item><title>Play could be the basis of physical reality</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-could-be-the-basis-of-physical-reality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-could-be-the-basis-of-physical-reality/</guid><description>The principle of play repeats so often in nature, it’s worth asking whether it’s the basis of physical reality. That’s not as wild an assertion as it seems, and even more plausible and less inconsistent than our image of a mindless robotic universe.
I don’t deny that what I’ve presented so far is a savage simplification of very complicated issues.</description></item><item><title>PMS and other pathologies are culture-bound syndromes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pms-and-other-pathologies-are-culture-bound-syndromes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pms-and-other-pathologies-are-culture-bound-syndromes/</guid><description>Look, I’m gonna side eye any opinion on menstruation authored by a man, but the essay Is PMS Real? by Frank Bures offers a fascinating glimpse at culture-bound syndromes:1
The phenomenon of so-called culture-bound syndromes, which more recently have come to be known as “cultural syndromes,” or sometimes, “cultural idioms of distress.</description></item></channel></rss>