<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lexicon on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/lexicon/</link><description>Recent content in lexicon on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/lexicon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An amateur is one who loves</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/an-amateur-is-one-who-loves/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/an-amateur-is-one-who-loves/</guid><description>A proposition: what if amateur could outrank professional in terms of our respect? We tend to use amateur pejoratively, to indicate the lack of skill, but the word in French means lover. If you think about it this way:
Amateur: one who loves
Professional: one who is financially obligated</description></item><item><title>Karass</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/karass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/karass/</guid><description>A group of people linked in a cosmically significant manner, even when superficial linkages are not evident.
Coined by [[authors/kurt vonnegut|Kurt Vonnegut]] in 1963, as a Bokononist term in the novel [[books/cats cradle|Cat’s Cradle]]. Other karass-related terms:
duprass – a karass of only two people, who almost always die within a week of each other.</description></item><item><title>“Modern” science often repackages medieval categories</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/modern-science-often-repackages-medieval-categories/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/modern-science-often-repackages-medieval-categories/</guid><description>There is a longstanding tradition of borrowing older scientific or medical categories, merely updating the terminology but keeping the same (invalid) assertions.
When the nineteenth-century medicolegal term “homosexuality” was brought into official Catholic speech, it replaced the eleventh-century theological term “sodomy.” “Homosexuality” took the place of “sodomy” in the way a substitute teacher takes over a class.</description></item><item><title>Moral dumbfounding is not moral reasoning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-dumbfounding-is-not-moral-reasoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-dumbfounding-is-not-moral-reasoning/</guid><description>Moral judgement and moral reasoning are basically two different processes. People tend to have a knee-jerk reaction for what’s good or bad, often based more on cultural conditioning, prejudice, or gut feelings than any reasonable morality or ethics. When asked to elaborate, you get “moral dumbfounding,” moral reasoning made up ex-post facto to justify moral judgement.</description></item><item><title>Moral panics and mass hysteria</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-panics-and-mass-hysteria/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-panics-and-mass-hysteria/</guid><description>Imma start collecting moral panics from the past so our current ones sound less wild. Moral of the story: humans will moral panic over just about anything 💀
The pig-man hunts of New Haven Courtesy of [[authors/jesse bering|Jesse Bering]] in his book [[books/perv|Perv]]:
You’ve heard of the witch hunts in Salem, but I’m guessing you’re not as familiar with the pig-man hunts of New Haven.</description></item><item><title>Phatic phrases</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/phatic-phrases/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:44:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/phatic-phrases/</guid><description>Phatic phrases are the phrases that follow a well-worn script, and as long as you don’t miss the beat, the words themselves don’t matter.
For example:
Hi!
What’s up?
Fine, how are you?
Not much.
Each person is responding to questions that weren’t asked, but the script is so familiar and the beats so ingrained that nobody notices.</description></item><item><title>Bibliotropic</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bibliotropic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:23:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bibliotropic/</guid><description>To leans towards a book as flowers leans toward the sun.
I’m guessing [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]] didn’t coin this one so much as borrow it, but most of the top results in google reference [[books/among others|her use of it]], or at least the SFF community.</description></item><item><title>Vorfreude</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vorfreude/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vorfreude/</guid><description>The German word vorfruede has no English equivalent. It comes from the words vor (“before”) and Freude (“joy”) and means something along the lines of “joyful anticipation.”
Often “vorfreude” is characterized as childish anticipation. It also includes the tension, impatience, and curiosity of anticipating an event.</description></item><item><title>Vocateur</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vocateur/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vocateur/</guid><description>Ha @ [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]] describing herself as a vocateur reader on the Ex Urbe Ad Astra podcast! Totally fits because as much as I love her as an author ([[books/lent|Lent]]! [[books/among others|Among Others]]!), I always say Jo is my favorite reader.
I was trying to find out if [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]] coined vocateur in the [[series/terra ignota|Terra Ignota]] series, and the results of just a cursory google search all give her credit for the term.</description></item><item><title>Mitfreude</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mitfreude/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mitfreude/</guid><description>Mitfreude is feeling joy in another’s joy. The opposite of schadenfreude, where pleasure is derived from another’s misfortune.
Coined by Nietzsche in 1878,1 it originates in the German language, mit (“with”) + Freude (“joy”).
First encountered in [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]]’s essay on anime and manga, A Mitfreude of Anime and Manga’s Relationship with Anglophone Science Fiction), where she defines it as the joy of sharing joy with friends.</description></item><item><title>Humanitas/humus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/humanitas-humus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/humanitas-humus/</guid><description>Humanitas in Latin comes first and properly from humando, meaning ‘burying, burial’, itself from humus, meaning ‘earth’ or ‘soil.’ In burial, the human body becomes a component of the earth, returned as dust to dust—inhumed, restored to humility, rendered humble.
[[books/underland|Underland]], [[authors/robert macfarlane|Robert Macfarlane]]</description></item><item><title>Glimmering</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/glimmering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/glimmering/</guid><description>The opposite of a trigger. A little glimmering of affirmation.
First encountered on IG, @tialevings and others</description></item><item><title>The Chinese word for endurance</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/endurance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/endurance/</guid><description>In [[books/what my bones know|What My Bones Know]], [[authors/stephanie foo|Stephanie Foo]] says:
It made perfect sense to me later in life when I discovered that the Chinese word for endurance is simply the word knife on top of the word heart. You walk around with a knife in your heart.</description></item><item><title>Calliphony</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/calliphony/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 14:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/calliphony/</guid><description>Calliphony is the as-of-yet uncoined and obviously absent opposite of the well-known adjective cacophony (which is currently notably lacking in any other accurately or articulately quotable antithesis).1
Roots come from the Greek words calli and caco, meaning ‘beautiful’ and ‘ugly’ when used to preface nouns.</description></item><item><title>Compersion</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/compersion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/compersion/</guid><description>Vicarious joy, experiencing pleasure because of another person’s pleasure. Basically the opposite of jealousy.
Coined by the Kerista Community in the 1970s, probably following the model of dispersion, so that use specifically applies to polyamorous relationships, the pleasure of your partner experiencing pleasure with someone else.</description></item><item><title>Naft</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/naft/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/naft/</guid><description>Naft (نفت in Persian) is a naturally occurring petroleum (naphtha), often a flammable mix used in war such as Greek fire—a highly flammable substance of unknown composition first used by the Greeks of Constantinople in the 7th century C.E. to set fire to enemy ships.1</description></item><item><title>Crypsis</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/crypsis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/crypsis/</guid><description>Concealment. In biology, it’s the ability of an organism to avoid observation.
Also, interestingly enough: it’s a term used in the seventeenth century to designate Christ’s possession of divine omnipotence and divine omniscience, with conscious restraint in the use of them.
First encountered in [[books/following the water|Following the Water]] by [[authors/david m carroll|David M.</description></item></channel></rss>