<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>m-f on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/m-f/</link><description>Recent content in m-f on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/m-f/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Rat-Catcher’s Daughter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</guid><description>Very sweet and dare I say necessary before [[books/gilded cage|Gilded Cage]]. It has some pretty key context. And come on—that title.</description></item><item><title>A Lady’s Guide to Fortune-Hunting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-fortune-hunting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-fortune-hunting/</guid><description>I didn’t love this quite as much as [[books/a lady&amp;rsquo;s guide to scandal|book two]]. (Read them out of order, oops!) Lots of promise, but I think the difference in POV—floating omniscient instead of tight third—didn’t work quite as well for me, possibly because it’s such a high bar of difficulty, possibly because it’s much closer to Jane Austen’s voice, which means the differences in quality are glaring.</description></item><item><title>The Curse of Chalion</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-curse-of-chalion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-curse-of-chalion/</guid><description>It’s been easier lately for me to review the books I don’t like than the ones I do, because the ones I do, it’s just love, love, love. And it’s often difficult to articulate why.
This is one of the above. I just loved the… gentleness of it.</description></item><item><title>The Love Remedy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</guid><description>I noped out hard at the kiss during a panic attack(!!!), and it never won me back. I did skim through the rest to find out whodunnit, which means I was annoyed by whodunnit (it’s just nonsensical based on the characterization within the book!), with bonus annoyance that there’s some minor kinkiness (yay blindfolds!</description></item><item><title>A Lady’s Guide to Scandal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</guid><description>Aah, this was so fun! It righted some wrongs from Persuasion (I’m not a Wentworth fan, okay—don’t @ me), and threw in enough hijinks that it didn’t have to be a faithful retelling. The only character I adore more than Melville is Margaret; I’m in love with them both.</description></item><item><title>Paladin of Souls</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</guid><description>Magnificent. I didn’t think Bujold could top Cazaril as a character, and she does. Illvin and beloved Ista. Such a rich, full, scarred world she’s created. It spoke to me deeply, even more than the first. I cried. I felt joy-struck. Cursed, bitter Ista is also blessed, beloved Ista.</description></item><item><title>Gilded Cage</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gilded-cage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gilded-cage/</guid><description>Yes, this is Susan Lazarus from [[series/sins of the cities|Sins of the Cities]]. I love a prickly, ruthless heroine. I love jewel thieves and morality that is questionable at best. I love all that the most. This one didn’t quite click all the way with me despite all of the above, so I will be revisiting to see what I missed.</description></item><item><title>Something Extraordinary</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</guid><description>The high-strung Belle has left behind her heroine era, and the drama-prone Rufus has left behind his Sir Horley Comewithers era. Together they embark on the worst elopement kidnapping elopement in history (per Belle, it’s not vainglorious to claim that when it’s true), and what ensues is a meditation on friendship, love, sexuality, identity, self-discovery, society, and home in a way that only Alexis Hall can do it.</description></item><item><title>The Hallowed Hunt</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</guid><description>Not the heights of Ista or Cazaril, but going backwards in this timeline instead of forwards is a choice I admire. I can see returning to this one as often as the two favorites, especially if those two get worn out by re-reading.</description></item><item><title>A Governess’s Guide to Passion and Peril</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-governesss-guide-to-passion-and-peril/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-governesss-guide-to-passion-and-peril/</guid><description>The fourth in a series, and I read at least one of the first three during the fugue state years when my dad’s health was failing, so I have only the haziest memory of it. That might mean I’m missing something, as it never felt explained in the text why the other women hadn’t come to Jane’s aid before now, nor why Jane’s feelings for Adrian would evolve beyond a schoolgirl crush.</description></item><item><title>A Room with a View</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-room-with-a-view/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-room-with-a-view/</guid><description>It was the old, old battle of the room with the view.
Wow. Re-read in one sitting. I was only going to read the Florence bits, but then I just didn’t stop. This is why I’m a fan of coming back to books at different ages with different eyes and different contexts, because it makes them different books.</description></item><item><title>Emma of 83rd Street</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</guid><description>Emma is my favorite Austen, and arguably the most difficult to modernize without losing the spirit of the story.1 I don’t envy any author who attempts it, but this one lost me in the weeds, with pacing that seems twice the length of Austen with half the page count.</description></item><item><title>Hot Earl Summer</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hot-earl-summer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hot-earl-summer/</guid><description>A goofy, over-the-top farce with the volume dialed up to 11. Which seems absurd to complain about, given how I just read and loved [[books/something extraordinary|Something Extraordinary]]—surely if anything is dialed up to 11 it’s the Tarletons. But [[authors/alexis hall|Alexis Hall]] grounds his farce with deep emotion and intimacy, using it to scratch away at the actual farce of a society that dictates such rigid, preposterous roles.</description></item><item><title>How to Fall for a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>A thief and a private investigator team up to solve a theft, and the vibes are basically a case-of-the-week tv episode (think Charlie’s Angels, Remington Steele, White Collar, etc) playing historical dress-up. The plot is as straightforward as it gets—they search for a macguffin, they get a clue, they get another clue, they solve the case.</description></item><item><title>Racing to You</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</guid><description>“Has someone written a romance about pro cycling?” was something I wondered last week. And voila, this book.
It actually:
Has some legit knowledge of cycling! Addresses doping as a plot point Addresses the extremely monastic and high-pressure lifestyle Gets the team dynamic! Has real races like Paris-Nice!</description></item><item><title>Reputation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</guid><description>Lex Croucher’s lols-per-page cannot be beat.
Weirdly, the only character I was meh on was the love interest, just because he’s too perfect. (My notes say “Col Brandon in a Henry Tilney body???”) I also would have been fine if this had swung more towards a coming-of-age instead of HEA romance, but I won’t hold that against it.</description></item><item><title>Starling House</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/starling-house/</guid><description>After burning out on southern gothic, it delights me when there are authors that make it fresh again, doing something fun in the genre.
Here’s how you write horror in Kentucky. All of the elements, from the book-within-a-book to the lingering satanic panic to the generational trauma to the historical footnotes to the ecological elegy to the snarky wit, worked for me.</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item><item><title>Trouble</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/trouble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/trouble/</guid><description>Perfection. I knew Lex Croucher could do it. Each standalone entry in this not-quite-series has been good, better, best. This one is THE BEST. In Emily, Croucher has written the prickly heroine of my dreams, who isn’t required to sand down any sharp edges for plot or relationship reasons.</description></item></channel></rss>