<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>palestine on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/palestine/</link><description>Recent content in palestine on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 14:28:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/palestine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Right to Maim</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-right-to-maim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 14:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-right-to-maim/</guid><description>In The Right to Maim Jasbir K. Puar brings her pathbreaking work on the liberal state, sexuality, and biopolitics to bear on our understanding of disability. Drawing on a stunning array of theoretical and methodological frameworks, Puar uses the concept of “debility”—bodily injury and social exclusion brought on by economic and political factors—to disrupt the category of disability.</description></item><item><title>Zealot</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/zealot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/zealot/</guid><description>Great at painting a picture of 1st century Palestine. So many inaccuracies though! [[books/jesus apocalyptic prophet of the new millennium|Ehrman’s was better]].
Pull quotes Nowhere is any such thing written: not in the Law of Moses, not in the prophets, not in the Psalms. In the entire history of Jewish thought there is not a single line of scripture that says the messiah is to suffer, die, and rise again on the third day, which may explain why Jesus does not bother to cite any scripture to back up his incredible claim.</description></item><item><title>A Woman Is No Man</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</guid><description>We need more books by Palestinian and Arab authors. I intend to read more by Etaf Rum. But it pains me to say… I think this could have been a (powerful) short story. The structure and even dialogue is very repetitive, in a way that I’m sure is meant to illustrate the cyclical and generational cycle of abuse, but instead means you could skim chapters and not miss anything.</description></item><item><title>Evil Eye</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</guid><description>This is why I wanted to read more Etaf Rum. This is the book I knew she had in her. It’s just as brilliant and damning a portrait of a toxic marriage as [[books/liars|Liars]] was, with the added generational trauma and displacement of a Palestinian family.</description></item><item><title>Jesus: Apocalyptic Prophet of the New Millennium</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jesus-apocalyptic-prophet-of-the-new-millennium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jesus-apocalyptic-prophet-of-the-new-millennium/</guid><description>What I wanted [[books/zealot|Zealot]] to be.</description></item><item><title>Shattered Spear</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shattered-spear/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shattered-spear/</guid><description>Such a powerful example of what comics/graphic novels can do, with images more than words. I loved it. And more fiction of any kind set in the neolithic middle east, please.
Available from the author here, name your own price: https://claystorks.itch.io/shattered-spear</description></item></channel></rss>