<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tarot on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/tarot/</link><description>Recent content in tarot on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/tarot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tarot for Change</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tarot-for-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tarot-for-change/</guid><description>I’d prefer a bit less Joseph Campbell and Cognitive Behavioral Therapy,1 but overall, the best book on tarot I’ve encountered so far. Or, rather than a definitive superlative, it’s the book that most resonates with me so far. It’s how I engage with tarot, not for divination, but therapeutically, creatively, narratively, for introspection and storytelling.</description></item><item><title>Finding the Fool</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/finding-the-fool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/finding-the-fool/</guid><description>Bounced off it big time. I like the introduction, especially with Meg Jones Wall’s ex-evangelical background, but once she got to the cards, very little resonated. I feel at odds with her perspective and energy level, and not in a challenging, interesting way. I’ll stick with [[books/tarot for change|Tarot for Change]] and keep exploring.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>I Ching, the Oracle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-ching-the-oracle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-ching-the-oracle/</guid><description>I now understand the I Ching a fraction more than I did before! It’s a great and thorough introduction. I can’t attest to how well it stacks up against others of its ilk, but it suited my needs and rewarded my curiosity. Beautifully designed too, which counts for a lot.</description></item></channel></rss>