<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>speculative on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/speculative/</link><description>Recent content in speculative on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/speculative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beneath the Rising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/beneath-the-rising/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/beneath-the-rising/</guid><description>The coincidence of snagging this series on sale1 the night before I finished [[books/rakesfall|Rakesfall]], where [[authors/vajra chandrasekera|Vajra Chandrasekera]] names Premee Mohamed in his acknowledgments.
Indeed, it plays on similar themes, albeit in an entirely different style. Here we’ve got an action-adventure race across the continents when Johnny, young super-genius inventor/do-gooder in a kind of Greta Thurnberg mold, accidentally creates such a powerful clean energy reactor that it warps space and time and calls up eldritch gods from the deep… which she knows full well because she’s made a deal with those same gods to exchange her mortality for the fame and brains to save the world.</description></item><item><title>Never Whistle at Night</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/never-whistle-at-night/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/never-whistle-at-night/</guid><description>As awesome as the cover. I agree with Stephen Graham Jones, who writes the foreword, that the cream of the current horror crop is written by indigenous authors.
“But what feels like an even better explanation for why we tend to like our stories to end like that, with bleeding over, bleeding across, haunting us, it’s that it feels kind of fake and wrong and all too American to throw up walls between what’s real and what’s maybe not real.</description></item><item><title>Ficciones</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ficciones/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ficciones/</guid><description>Borges is up to some delightful fuckery, playing with form, inventing books and authors and universes that are just as, to paraphrase, contaminated with fiction as our own history of the world. The stories are brief and vertiginous, mind-boggling and often cheeky. An undisputed masterpiece, even if I’m still partial to [[authors/italo calvino|Calvino]], even if Calvino himself would disagree with me (per his essay on Borges in [[books/six memos for the next millennium|Six Memos for the Next Millennium]]).</description></item><item><title>Lessons from Cruising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</guid><description>Joke’s on me, because I picked up this ARC for the last story, a retelling of Billy Budd from Captain Vere’s point of view. I figured I’d sample the rest; instead I went down the buffet line and inhaled them all. Rarely do I like every story in a short story collection, but that’s what Goodman’s done to me.</description></item><item><title>Earthlings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earthlings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earthlings/</guid><description>You could put trigger warnings on this book for child abuse, incest, and cannibalism(!!), and still the anguish of being forced to conform to society—“The Factory”—at the expense of all well-being forms the core of the horror. Particularly how women are reduced to wombs like mechanical components.</description></item></channel></rss>