<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>spy-games on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/spy-games/</link><description>Recent content in spy-games on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/spy-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clockwork Boys</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clockwork-boys/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clockwork-boys/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Love Remedy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:35:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</guid><description>I noped out hard at the kiss during a panic attack(!!!), and it never won me back. I did skim through the rest to find out whodunnit, which means I was annoyed by whodunnit (it’s just nonsensical based on the characterization within the book!), with bonus annoyance that there’s some minor kinkiness (yay blindfolds!</description></item><item><title>A Marvellous Light</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</guid><description>Fun Edwardian murder mystery. Fun world building. God save Edwin from the idiotic flower of English manhood.</description></item><item><title>Proper English</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</guid><description>It’s the House Party from Hell, and the first time I read it, I was like this is exhausting, it’s claustrophobic, not sure I can vibe with it—but then I read it again in 2020 and YES. It is a MOOD.</description></item><item><title>Slippery Creatures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</guid><description>After the recent spate of lackluster histroms that were trying to do various spy and mystery related things, I was pining for Will Darling. Enter Chirp audiobooks with a well-timed deal on the series bundle, and before you could say Lord Arthur Aloysius Kimberly de Brabazon Secretan, I had the dulcet tones of Cornell Collins narrating my favorite KJ Charles competence porn.</description></item><item><title>The Wonder Engine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-wonder-engine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-wonder-engine/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Restless Truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</guid><description>This was so close to being great. SO CLOSE. But overall, the book felt kind of like the menagerie on board the ship, let loose in all directions, refusing to be corralled. There were some structure/plot/writing choices that left me more stumped than dazzled. Maud’s and Violet’s POV seemed really interchangeable for the first half, which is&amp;hellip; not great when one is a supposedly scandalous, sardonic, shrewd actress and one is a sheltered, capricious, stubborn young girl.</description></item><item><title>A Lady’s Guide to Scandal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</guid><description>Aah, this was so fun! It righted some wrongs from Persuasion (I’m not a Wentworth fan, okay—don’t @ me), and threw in enough hijinks that it didn’t have to be a faithful retelling. The only character I adore more than Melville is Margaret; I’m in love with them both.</description></item><item><title>Think of England</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</guid><description>This is pulp with all the trappings—daring spies, dastardly villains, plots galore—and yet it’s so grounded in real emotion it hardly feels like pulp at all. Except for the part that’s so entertaining I devoured it in two days.
Great book. Great pairing. KJ Charles does it again.</description></item><item><title>The Sugared Game</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sugared-game/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sugared-game/</guid><description>Re-read 12/24.
Way back the first time I read it, I praised all the talk—long pages and chapters full of Will and Kim talking. That still stands, but I would also like to add praise for the long pages and chapters full of Will and Phoebe talking, and Will and Maisie talking.</description></item><item><title>A Nobleman’s Guide to Seducing a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>So I somehow didn’t even realize my preorder of the paperback arrived two weeks early (!!!), meaning I’ve already read this twice by the time I got the “book release day!” email this morning.
Oops.
Except not oops, because I needed the last two weeks with this book.</description></item><item><title>The Duke at Hazard</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</guid><description>I have a few auto-buy (auto-preorder) authors, but KJ Charles is the only one where I drop everything to start reading the day a new book comes out. Here, that impatience is rewarded with a tender, slow-blooming romance-on-the-run between Daizell, a disgraced non-scoundrel scoundrel (he’s paying for the sins of his father), and Cassian, aka The Duke, aka Vernon Fortescue Cassian George de Vere Crosse, the fourth Duke of Severn, the Earl of Harmsford, Baron Crosse of Wotton, and Baron Vere, who’s incognito for a month to hunt down a thief and win a wager (he’s burdened with the premature inheritance of his father’s title).</description></item><item><title>A Power Unbound</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</guid><description>Here is my theory from [[books/a restless truth|book 2]]: the Blyths suit me best in small doses. Robin and Maud, respectively, were the most difficult parts of their own books for me. They’re just so young, energetic, athletic, upstanding, so shiny, so beautiful, so aggressively… “normal,” for lack of a better word, when I prefer crankiness and weariness and a bit of tarnish on the bronze these days.</description></item><item><title>Subtle Blood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</guid><description>I might have accidentally read Subtle Blood again, since I might have accidentally experienced a vivid dream of Will, Kim, Phoebe, and Maisie on a Parisian adventure (cameo by Teddy Molyneaux, of course), and upon waking, might have accidentally been distraught that that book wasn’t going to exist.</description></item><item><title>Earl Crush</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earl-crush/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earl-crush/</guid><description>Listen, I’ve just about sworn off m/f romance after so many recent flops, but this one snuck in under the wire, as I was already committed to the ARC. It’s good! Not amazing, but good, in the fulfilled-the-brief, let’s-not-overthink-it kind of way I’ve been looking for [[digest/books of august ’24|since August]].</description></item><item><title>How to Fall for a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>A thief and a private investigator team up to solve a theft, and the vibes are basically a case-of-the-week tv episode (think Charlie’s Angels, Remington Steele, White Collar, etc) playing historical dress-up. The plot is as straightforward as it gets—they search for a macguffin, they get a clue, they get another clue, they solve the case.</description></item><item><title>The Spirit Ring</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</guid><description>Sometimes when things connect, they really connect. I picked this up because I was ready for another Bujold, and this is what the library had, and what is right there when I open it up? Renaissance Italy! Borgias, Florentines; Sforzas, Medicis; Guelphs and Ghibellines.
Three true things: it’s a gem in the rough; Thur is my boy; every Bujold, even vintage Bujold, is the best Bujold.</description></item><item><title>Clear and Muddy Loss of Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</guid><description>This is just what I was in the mood for, a 300+ chapter, 4000 page sapphic slow burn court intrigue. The prose (and/or translation?) is more functional than beautiful on a sentence level, but on a plot level, with the overall character arcs, QJMX has some mad skill.</description></item></channel></rss>