<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>language on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/language/</link><description>Recent content in language on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Several Short Sentences About Writing</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/several-short-sentences-about-writing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/several-short-sentences-about-writing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Underland</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/underland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 16:34:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/underland/</guid><description>For to think in deep time can be a means not of escaping our troubled present, but rather of re-imagining it; countermanding its quick greeds and furies with older, slower stories of making and unmaking.
Three different siren calls for me: geology, linguistics, and [[notes/deep time|deep time]].</description></item><item><title>Lexicon Urthus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lexicon-urthus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lexicon-urthus/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Because Internet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/because-internet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/because-internet/</guid><description>Ooh, this was FUN. It’s a fascinating look at how language evolves, and how rapidly it’s evolving now because internet—and arguably for the better, because internet-speak conveys this whole spectrum of emotional nuance that formal written language cannot.
Highlights and takeaways, an incomplete list:
It’s not just that we make patterns; humans are basically incapable of doing things without patterns Young women are the language disrupters Twitter, where you’re encouraged to follow people you don’t already know, has more linguistic innovation (not to mention [[notes/memes and social movements|memes and social movements]]) than Facebook, where you primarily friend people you already know offline [[notes/the curse of latin-y grammar|The curse of Latin-y grammar]] Grammar and spelling are collective agreements, not eternal truths; collective agreements can change What teens are doing is sophisticated [[notes/linguistic play as a writing exercise|Linguistic play as a writing exercise]] Reshaping informal writing into something that could more deeply convey the full range of human emotions Incoherence is the invitation to create Our language about emotion is embodied; you believe their body, not their words Japanese (eastern) anime and emoticons emphasize the eyes; western emphasizes the mouth Illustrative emoji (the birthday cake; it means what it means) vs.</description></item><item><title>Braiding Sweetgrass</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Annals of the Former World</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/annals-of-the-former-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/annals-of-the-former-world/</guid><description>I’m glad I’m not beyond the age where books I read can change the way I see the world. If that is an age you can reach, I don’t want to. I can’t even drive down the highway now without seeing something as simple as roadcuts in a whole different light.</description></item><item><title>Consolations</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/consolations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/consolations/</guid><description>Profound devotional. Nourishment is right. I keep dipping into different pages throughout the year.
We are all compost for worlds we cannot yet imagine.</description></item><item><title>Word by Word</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/word-by-word/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/word-by-word/</guid><description>I love words, I love English, and there is no way I could be a lexicographer. I will never read a dictionary the same way again. This was even more interesting than I hoped it would be.
I call it “craft” and not “art” for connotative reasons.</description></item></channel></rss>