<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pacific-northwest on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/pacific-northwest/</link><description>Recent content in pacific-northwest on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/pacific-northwest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Delilah Green Doesn’t Care</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/delilah-green-doesnt-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/delilah-green-doesnt-care/</guid><description>One of those books where the friendships ALMOST outshine the romance. ALMOST. Everybody has arcs and character growth, even the exes; everybody contributes their piece of misunderstanding and conflict resolution to the plot. It’s like a big group hug from best friends, messy and comforting and silly and necessary.</description></item><item><title>Astrid Parker Doesn’t Fail</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/astrid-parker-doesnt-fail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/astrid-parker-doesnt-fail/</guid><description>Look, realistically, the destiny stuff did not work for me. They’ve known each other a handful of weeks; saying, “I really, really like you, we’re both hot messes, let’s try to make this work” would have been much more my speed.
But. I love Astrid Parker SO MUCH.</description></item><item><title>Iris Kelly Doesn’t Date</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</guid><description>Yes to the gender-bending production of Much Ado About Nothing; yes to practice dating and sex lessons. Beyond that, the plot was a hot mess for me, trying to both validate Iris’s singledom yet ultimately get her in a relationship. I appreciate that Blake acknowledged the difficulty of walking that tightrope, and it is a rom-com—of course it’s gonna be an HEA.</description></item><item><title>Come Out, Come Out</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</guid><description>In the same niche as [[books/camp damascus|Camp Damascus]], the conversion-therapy-as-horror genre. Similarities abound, even down to the senior class quarry jumps, which doesn’t indicate any co-opting of plot points but simply how ubiquitous this experience is, the same script across rural America, where any deviation from the script means there will be Consequences.</description></item><item><title>Kiss Her Once for Me</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</guid><description>Tried this one again, hoping I had one more festive read in me for the year, but there are just sooo many things that bug me right away. It’s gonna be one of those books where shitty systemic poverty gets magically fixed for one [pretty young white] woman by the power of romance with a [manipulative gaslighting] millionaire, isn’t it?</description></item></channel></rss>