<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>france on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/france/</link><description>Recent content in france on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/france/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Too Like the Lightning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</guid><description>Of course I’m immediately starting all over again after [[books/perhaps the stars|Perhaps The Stars]]. Every time, tingling chills down my spine on page 254:
I am the window through which you watch the coming storm. He is the lightning.
I can ditto [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]], who says, “I love this book with the passionate love of an exploding supernova, but every book isn’t for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Seven Surrenders</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</guid><description>There’s no way I can talk comprehensively about this series, so for now I’m just going to keep a running list of different things I notice each time I read them. This time (2/2023), it was how the many names for JEDD Mason echoes the [[notes/apophatic naming|apophatic naming]] of God, a classical theological strategy of the “negative” naming, an effort to call God by every time, thereby acknowledging and preserving God’s transcendence of all of them.</description></item><item><title>The Will to Battle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</guid><description>Reader, I cried like Mycroft Canner. It’s very much the first half of a whole (third quarter of four?), and it needs [[books/perhaps the stars|the last book]] to be complete, but what a feat it is on its own.</description></item><item><title>Perhaps the Stars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</guid><description>I still haven’t found the words to talk about this one. Maybe next year I will. It should be in the Smithsonian, or win the Nobel prize, or something, as one of humanity’s greatest achievements.</description></item><item><title>The Good Life</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-good-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-good-life/</guid><description>Man takes [[books/the great gatsby|The Great Gatsby]] as a how-to manual, right down to the narcissism and body count, just with more explicit gay sex. (As in, Gatsby the way the good lord intended.) It’s unpleasant to read in the way obscene wealth always is, but it’s beautifully structured and compellingly written, an interesting artifact of both the era in which it’s set and when it’s written.</description></item><item><title>Gothic Tales</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</guid><description>Turns out I’ve read most of these stories before, but it makes sense to repackage them here for their gothic themes and add a pleasing cover. My hope springs eternal, with each new edition, that Sade gets placed in his rightful political context, his radical philosophy that’s more dangerous than any pornography.</description></item><item><title>Leviathan</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/leviathan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/leviathan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Social Contract</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-social-contract/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-social-contract/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Autobiography of Benvenuto Cellini</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autobiography-of-benvenuto-cellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autobiography-of-benvenuto-cellini/</guid><description>Necromancy, assassinations, prison breaks, poisonings, stabbings (so many stabbings!!), pranks on Michelangelo… dude lived a life. Come for the adventure, stay for the fascinating glimpse into Renaissance life and art. I read because [[authors/lois mcmaster bujold|Bujold]] based part of [[books/the spirit ring|The Spirit Ring]] on Cellini and said fact was stranger than fiction… she was not wrong.</description></item><item><title>Juliette</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/juliette/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/juliette/</guid><description>I rarely do this, but there’s another review that says it so well, I’m going to quote it instead of trying to sum up my own thoughts:
Sade the philosopher is in force, and his treatises — like his other novels delivered by key characters — are interspersed with the sex and violence one expects.</description></item><item><title>Justine, Philosophy in the Bedroom, and Other Writings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/justine-philosophy-in-the-bedroom-and-other-writings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/justine-philosophy-in-the-bedroom-and-other-writings/</guid><description>Thank you, [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]]. I had my suspicions about Sade, that more was going on than just some shock and awe erotica, and in [[books/too like the lightning|Too Like The Lightning]], when he becomes part of the dialogue in a key way, she makes it clear that to read Sade as sadism is too narrow a view.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</guid><description>A note on translation: I used Reynolds to compare, contrast, and fill in the gaps with the [[books/orlando furioso a new verse translation|Slavitt translation]]. Slavitt takes liberties, and Reynolds has merit, but I’ve got to say, for compulsive readability, and cheeky irreverence that feels like it honors the spirit of the original, Slavitt it is.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso: A New Verse Translation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</guid><description>Ariosto writing like AO3 was a thing in the sixteenth century. I love it. Fiendishly clever layers of satire; a story where anything goes.</description></item><item><title>Kushiel’s Dart</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kushiels-dart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kushiels-dart/</guid><description>My semi-decennial attempt to finish this book. I made it farther this time, with determination, but despite an attempt every three to five years, I still bounce off it like a rubber ball. Taboo, kink, AND court intrigue in the same book?! This should be exactly my thing!</description></item><item><title>Racing to You</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</guid><description>“Has someone written a romance about pro cycling?” was something I wondered last week. And voila, this book.
It actually:
Has some legit knowledge of cycling! Addresses doping as a plot point Addresses the extremely monastic and high-pressure lifestyle Gets the team dynamic! Has real races like Paris-Nice!</description></item><item><title>The Black Jersey</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</guid><description>It takes until page 280 for the main character to say, “I am an imbecile,” which is the truest thing in the book.
Oh boy. So many feelings. That are conflicted. Is this a book about cycling? Yes. Do I love cycling? Yes. Do I love books about cycling?</description></item><item><title>The Cyclist and His Shadow</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cyclist-and-his-shadow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cyclist-and-his-shadow/</guid><description>I like how right away, in the forward, Thomazeau François is pitting this book against [[books/the rider|The Rider]] as the seminal classic of cycling literature. I arched a skeptical eyebrow, and… was in total agreement by like, chapter 3.
Brilliant. Insane. Philosophical. Spiritual. Erotic. I read it during the nearly-hallucinatory six hours of Milan—San Remo and feel like bits of it have embedded in my brain like gravel, because I think of it every time I watch a race.</description></item><item><title>The Rider</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rider/</guid><description>My dear friend Karen made sure I got this book for an October gift, and since pro cycling is currently trying to do a nine month season in two months, including three grand tours, why not pile on some more and make this my cycling read of the (Covid-shortened) season?</description></item><item><title>Underland</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/underland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 16:34:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/underland/</guid><description>For to think in deep time can be a means not of escaping our troubled present, but rather of re-imagining it; countermanding its quick greeds and furies with older, slower stories of making and unmaking.
Three different siren calls for me: geology, linguistics, and [[notes/deep time|deep time]].</description></item><item><title>Giovanni’s Room</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</guid><description>Not everyone in book club was a fan, but I loved it, but it was brutal, but I’m glad I read it, but I’m glad I won’t be in a rush to read it again.
“Somebody,” said Jacques, “your father or mine, should have told us that not many people have ever died of love.</description></item></channel></rss>