<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>working-class on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/working-class/</link><description>Recent content in working-class on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/working-class/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slippery Creatures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</guid><description>After the recent spate of lackluster histroms that were trying to do various spy and mystery related things, I was pining for Will Darling. Enter Chirp audiobooks with a well-timed deal on the series bundle, and before you could say Lord Arthur Aloysius Kimberly de Brabazon Secretan, I had the dulcet tones of Cornell Collins narrating my favorite KJ Charles competence porn.</description></item><item><title>For Real</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/for-real/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/for-real/</guid><description>Re-read, for the new annotated print edition. And let me tell you, just when I thought one of my favorite romances could not get better, the annotations add a new layer. Dare I say, much as I enjoyed them, the annotations in [[books/glitterland|Glitterland]] felt… superfluous? In [[books/waiting for the flood|Waiting for the Flood]] and [[books/chasing the light|Chasing the Light]], they were a welcome addition to help stitch the old half of the story with the new.</description></item><item><title>Abolish Rent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</guid><description>An enthusiastic and persuasive manifesto on housing rights as human rights. It’s encouraging to see such robust organizing among tenants across the country, and the practical template for how to expand it. The authors rightly quote [[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula Le Guin]]: our housing system is a human power—produced by people, not God or nature.</description></item><item><title>Bullshit Jobs</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bullshit-jobs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bullshit-jobs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Direct Action</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/direct-action/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/direct-action/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pride and Prejudice</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pride-and-prejudice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pride-and-prejudice/</guid><description>Austen is so compulsively readable that I’ve already accomplished my re-read of Pride and Prejudice too. And don’t worry, I’m not about to be the killjoy that strips the romance from it this time. This novel is romantic, a true meeting of minds with the happiest ending Jane Austen has on offer.</description></item><item><title>Cash Delgado Is Living the Dream</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/cash-delgado-is-living-the-dream/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/cash-delgado-is-living-the-dream/</guid><description>This is so good. As in, read the sample, bought immediately, read the rest, finished at 10:30 at night. It takes several of my recent disappointments—[[books/iris kelly doesn&amp;rsquo;t date|Iris Kelly Doesn’t Date]], [[books/kiss her once for me|Kiss Her Once for Me]], [[books/late bloomer|Late Bloomer]]—and does that vibe right.</description></item><item><title>The Spring Before Obergefell</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spring-before-obergefell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spring-before-obergefell/</guid><description>It’s strange how a book like this—small-town rural Ohio circa 2015—can feel like an artifact of the past and yet an ongoing present. Mike is middle-aged, gay, single, and lost, with no cultural script for how someone like him can find connection and happiness. He believes the best he can hope for is hookup apps and casual flings, until he meets the capricious Matteo and the enigmatic Dave, who each challenge him in different ways.</description></item><item><title>The Worst Duke in London</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-worst-duke-in-london/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-worst-duke-in-london/</guid><description>I’m not averse to anachronisms in my historicals ([[authors/alexis hall|Alexis Hall]], [[authors/lex croucher|Lex Croucher]], et al. can get away with ahistorical murder), but there is anachronistic, and then there is untethered from reality. This was the latter, and not in a fun way. The info-dumping, the choppy writing, the shallow girlboss feminism, the hypersexual internal monologues, the plentiful (and destitute) dukes,1 the chaotic plot and even more chaotic characters, all of it made me bail earlier than usual.</description></item><item><title>Maurice</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/maurice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/maurice/</guid><description>I love this book because the characters are awful and snobby and wrong about so many things. Just like we’re awful and snobby and wrong in our own times. No historical revisionism, and still a happy ending. There’s great beauty within.
Not far from the lodge there was a nasty little climb, and the road, always in bad condition, was edged with dog roses that scratched the paint.</description></item></channel></rss>