<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Penguin on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/publishers/penguin/</link><description>Recent content in Penguin on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/publishers/penguin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Love Remedy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:35:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</guid><description>I noped out hard at the kiss during a panic attack(!!!), and it never won me back. I did skim through the rest to find out whodunnit, which means I was annoyed by whodunnit (it’s just nonsensical based on the characterization within the book!), with bonus annoyance that there’s some minor kinkiness (yay blindfolds!</description></item><item><title>A Lady’s Guide to Fortune-Hunting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-fortune-hunting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-fortune-hunting/</guid><description>I didn’t love this quite as much as [[books/a lady&amp;rsquo;s guide to scandal|book two]]. (Read them out of order, oops!) Lots of promise, but I think the difference in POV—floating omniscient instead of tight third—didn’t work quite as well for me, possibly because it’s such a high bar of difficulty, possibly because it’s much closer to Jane Austen’s voice, which means the differences in quality are glaring.</description></item><item><title>Delilah Green Doesn’t Care</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/delilah-green-doesnt-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/delilah-green-doesnt-care/</guid><description>One of those books where the friendships ALMOST outshine the romance. ALMOST. Everybody has arcs and character growth, even the exes; everybody contributes their piece of misunderstanding and conflict resolution to the plot. It’s like a big group hug from best friends, messy and comforting and silly and necessary.</description></item><item><title>A Lady’s Guide to Scandal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-scandal/</guid><description>Aah, this was so fun! It righted some wrongs from Persuasion (I’m not a Wentworth fan, okay—don’t @ me), and threw in enough hijinks that it didn’t have to be a faithful retelling. The only character I adore more than Melville is Margaret; I’m in love with them both.</description></item><item><title>Astrid Parker Doesn’t Fail</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/astrid-parker-doesnt-fail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/astrid-parker-doesnt-fail/</guid><description>Look, realistically, the destiny stuff did not work for me. They’ve known each other a handful of weeks; saying, “I really, really like you, we’re both hot messes, let’s try to make this work” would have been much more my speed.
But. I love Astrid Parker SO MUCH.</description></item><item><title>Iris Kelly Doesn’t Date</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</guid><description>Yes to the gender-bending production of Much Ado About Nothing; yes to practice dating and sex lessons. Beyond that, the plot was a hot mess for me, trying to both validate Iris’s singledom yet ultimately get her in a relationship. I appreciate that Blake acknowledged the difficulty of walking that tightrope, and it is a rom-com—of course it’s gonna be an HEA.</description></item><item><title>The Left Hand of Darkness</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid><description>Imperfect and still utterly perfect. Favorite always.
The David Mitchell foreword
Picture if you will reading this book when it was published, 1969, the year of Stonewall
Gender, sex, romance, desire, power, nationalism, oppression… they’re all just stories we tell ourselves. And we can tell different stories if we choose.</description></item><item><title>Tarot for Change</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tarot-for-change/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tarot-for-change/</guid><description>I’d prefer a bit less Joseph Campbell and Cognitive Behavioral Therapy,1 but overall, the best book on tarot I’ve encountered so far. Or, rather than a definitive superlative, it’s the book that most resonates with me so far. It’s how I engage with tarot, not for divination, but therapeutically, creatively, narratively, for introspection and storytelling.</description></item><item><title>A Vindication of the Rights of Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-vindication-of-the-rights-of-woman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-vindication-of-the-rights-of-woman/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Leviathan</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/leviathan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/leviathan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Affair of the Mysterious Letter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</guid><description>The only thing I’ve had brain space for this week is Alexis Hall, and I say that as the highest compliment. He brings so much heart, joy, and snark even when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery. Or should I say, especially when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery.</description></item><item><title>The Social Contract</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-social-contract/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-social-contract/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Come Out, Come Out</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</guid><description>In the same niche as [[books/camp damascus|Camp Damascus]], the conversion-therapy-as-horror genre. Similarities abound, even down to the senior class quarry jumps, which doesn’t indicate any co-opting of plot points but simply how ubiquitous this experience is, the same script across rural America, where any deviation from the script means there will be Consequences.</description></item><item><title>Experienced</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</guid><description>Bette gets dumped-but-not-dumped in truly shitty fashion by her girlfriend, who suggests she just needs more experience since she’s newly out as a lesbian. Commence a sex odyssey through the wilds of Bristol, aided by her first failed date of the odyssey, the kind and thoughtful Ruth.</description></item><item><title>Ninetails</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ninetails/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ninetails/</guid><description>I love mythology turned feminist, but something about this was so on the nose that it didn’t quite pull me in. I may revisit in a different mood to see if I feel differently, or whether I’m comparing it unfairly to [[books/home remedies|Home Remedies]], which was a better match to my taste in short stories.</description></item><item><title>Wintering</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</guid><description>DNF due to the health scare(s) both May and her husband experience at the beginning of the book. Even though I knew they were okay, it was too much to relive in the moment, my own recent family health scares too fresh. I skimmed ahead to see if I could just skip that part, but multiple other chapters failed to grab me.</description></item><item><title>Meditations</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/meditations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/meditations/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Body Keeps the Score</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-body-keeps-the-score/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-body-keeps-the-score/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Great Gatsby</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-great-gatsby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-great-gatsby/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Because Internet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/because-internet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/because-internet/</guid><description>Ooh, this was FUN. It’s a fascinating look at how language evolves, and how rapidly it’s evolving now because internet—and arguably for the better, because internet-speak conveys this whole spectrum of emotional nuance that formal written language cannot.
Highlights and takeaways, an incomplete list:
It’s not just that we make patterns; humans are basically incapable of doing things without patterns Young women are the language disrupters Twitter, where you’re encouraged to follow people you don’t already know, has more linguistic innovation (not to mention [[notes/memes and social movements|memes and social movements]]) than Facebook, where you primarily friend people you already know offline [[notes/the curse of latin-y grammar|The curse of Latin-y grammar]] Grammar and spelling are collective agreements, not eternal truths; collective agreements can change What teens are doing is sophisticated [[notes/linguistic play as a writing exercise|Linguistic play as a writing exercise]] Reshaping informal writing into something that could more deeply convey the full range of human emotions Incoherence is the invitation to create Our language about emotion is embodied; you believe their body, not their words Japanese (eastern) anime and emoticons emphasize the eyes; western emphasizes the mouth Illustrative emoji (the birthday cake; it means what it means) vs.</description></item><item><title>Braiding Sweetgrass</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/braiding-sweetgrass/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A History of the Bible</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-history-of-the-bible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-history-of-the-bible/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Giovanni’s Room</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</guid><description>Not everyone in book club was a fan, but I loved it, but it was brutal, but I’m glad I read it, but I’m glad I won’t be in a rush to read it again.
“Somebody,” said Jacques, “your father or mine, should have told us that not many people have ever died of love.</description></item></channel></rss>