<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>emergence on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/emergence/</link><description>Recent content in emergence on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/emergence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Individuality is inseparable from community</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/individuality-is-inseparable-from-community/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/individuality-is-inseparable-from-community/</guid><description>It shouldn’t surprise me anymore that I keep running across taoism when reading about anarchism or indigenous animism, or running across anarchism/animism when reading about the tao. (But it still does, bc I wanna stay childlike like that ☺️)
The principle is that if everything is allowed to go its own way the harmony of the universe will be established, since every process in the world can “do its own thing” only in relation to all others.</description></item><item><title>Language is a network</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/language-is-a-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/language-is-a-network/</guid><description>We are not tending language like a garden—its order is emerging from the chaos in a natural way.
When we thought of language like a book, we thought of it as an unruly mess of words that had to be kept in order, like a Victorian gardener constantly retrimming the hedges into spirals and globes.</description></item><item><title>Life is constantly creating options</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/life-is-constantly-creating-options/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/life-is-constantly-creating-options/</guid><description>From the macro to the micro, life is constantly creating options. Nature is not fixed and immutable, but emergent and adaptive.
Whether you take the planet as a whole, or the ecosystems at a smaller scale—a forest, a pond, a puddle—life is constantly creating options.</description></item><item><title>Enshittification</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/enshittification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/enshittification/</guid><description>Cory Doctorow on the enshittification of TikTok:
Here is how platforms die: first, they are good to their users; then they abuse their users to make things better for their business customers; finally, they abuse those business customers to claw back all the value for themselves.</description></item><item><title>Emergence occurs at a certain level of complexity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emergence-occurs-at-a-certain-level-of-complexity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emergence-occurs-at-a-certain-level-of-complexity/</guid><description>Faced with the puzzle of how life might emerge from dead matter or how conscious beings might evolve from microbes, philosophers of science have developed the theory of emergence.
The argument here is that once a certain level of complexity is reached, there is a kind of qualitative leap where completely new sorts of physical laws can “emerge”—ones that are premised on, but cannot be reduced to, what came before.</description></item></channel></rss>