<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>T Kingfisher on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/authors/t-kingfisher/</link><description>Recent content in T Kingfisher on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/authors/t-kingfisher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clockwork Boys</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clockwork-boys/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clockwork-boys/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What Moves the Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</guid><description>Just what I wanted for October: brilliant gothic fanfiction of The Fall of the House of Usher with even more fungi than Poe. Creepy and exquisite, and that’s not just the cover art.
(With a bonus Beatrix Potter relative, clever worldbuilding linguistics w/r/t gender, and a hat tip to Prisoner of Zenda!</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Grace</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-grace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-grace/</guid><description>Oops, I did my thing of accidentally reading out of order. I was doing the audiobooks and went by the listing on Scribd (now Everand), which had them listed out of order. So I read book 2 first.
I don’t think that changed my opinion of anything.</description></item><item><title>The Wonder Engine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-wonder-engine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-wonder-engine/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What Feasts at Night</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-feasts-at-night/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-feasts-at-night/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Paladin’s Strength</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-strength/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-strength/</guid><description>Oof, it pains me to say I had a tough time with this one. There was so much I liked—mainly CLARA—but it’s so unnecessarily long. Like at least a hundred pages too long because there’s so much repetition and angst and constant unresolved horniness. I love a road trip, I don’t mind a slow burn done right, but here the slow burn veers perilously close to miscommunication.</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Hope</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-hope/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-hope/</guid><description>Not me, caught up in the spookiness more than the romance. The romance was still solid, though. The audiobooks remain excellent.</description></item><item><title>A House With Good Bones</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-house-with-good-bones/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-house-with-good-bones/</guid><description>Yay, vultures save the day! A horror novel where racist grandmothers and roses are the problem, not the bugs and the vultures. That, along with the fantastic characters and very specific (and accurate!) North Carolina setting, makes this spooky book a treat.
(Out of 247 pages, I have 152 highlights—mostly lols, entomologist rants, and perfect encapsulations of NC life.</description></item><item><title>A Sorceress Comes to Call</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</guid><description>I’m here all day long for T. Kingfisher’s aging, aching protagonists, with bad knees and big hearts and a well-honed sense of doom. The plot is a very loose retelling of The Goose Girl, minus princesses and kings and plus a conniving, murderous, sorceress mother. Evangeline, aka Doom, is determined to marry herself and her trapped, obedient daughter to the highest bidders in proper Regency-esque fashion, plans thwarted when she encounters a squire’s spinster sister who sees her for exactly who she is.</description></item><item><title>Minor Mage</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/minor-mage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/minor-mage/</guid><description>Oliver was already on his knees, but he bowed his head, feeling complicated things he didn’t know how to deal with. When kindness came from murdered ghosts and lost pigs, and the adults that were supposed to help you were monsters that walked like men… What was he supposed to do?</description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</guid><description>So this is everything a fairy tale should be. The only thing that didn’t work for me 100% was the romance side plot, but it was very sweet nonetheless, and I do understand that’s a common ingredient in fairy tales, and that for most it would be necessary.</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item></channel></rss>