<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sex-education on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/sex-education/</link><description>Recent content in sex-education on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/sex-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gender and Our Brains</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gender-and-our-brains/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gender-and-our-brains/</guid><description>The takeaway: 19th century biological essentialism is bunk (duh), and the majority of crappy research in neurology and biology has been undertaken to prove that women are inferior (yay!). We don’t even know what we don’t know, because the pseudoscience myths we’ve inherited will NOT die; but it’s a gendered world that produces a gendered brain, not our biology.</description></item><item><title>Perv</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perv/</guid><description>For the longest time, to be a pervert wasn’t to be a sex deviant; it was to be an atheist Almost overnight, “pervert” goes from “immoral religious heretic” to “immoral sexual deviant” because Havelock Ellis The [[notes/naturalistic fallacy|naturalistic fallacy]] of polyamory, homosexuality, etc. (a rebuttal to [[books/sex at dawn|Sex at Dawn]]) Instead of “natural” or “unnatural”: Is it harmful?</description></item><item><title>Sex at Dawn</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sex-at-dawn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sex-at-dawn/</guid><description>For many societies, virginity is so unimportant there isn’t even a word for the concept in their language “Marriage,” “mating,” and “love” are socially constructed phenomena that have little or no transferable meaning outside any given culture No creature needs to be threatened with death to act in accord with its own nature We simply assume our own conception of family reflects something eternal and universal in human nature From savoring saliva beer or cow blood milkshakes to wearing socks with sandals, there is little doubt that people are willing to think, feel, wear, do, and believe pretty much anything if their society assures them it’s normal The majority of research on sexuality is based upon the responses of eighteen-to twenty-two-year-old American university students (!</description></item><item><title>The Dominance Playbook</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dominance-playbook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dominance-playbook/</guid><description>There’s a wealth of good relationship knowledge hidden in here, apart from any kink or power play stuff, like: [[notes/abuse is best recognized by the effect it has on the abused|Abuse is best recognized by the effect it has on the abused]].
In fact, he has a list of questions to ask yourself when you’re involved in any type of relationship, and I’m gonna recap it here, because it should be mandatory reading, and deserves a much wider audience than people reading kink books:</description></item><item><title>Refusing Compulsory Sexuality</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/refusing-compulsory-sexuality/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/refusing-compulsory-sexuality/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Woman in the Body</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-woman-in-the-body/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-woman-in-the-body/</guid><description>I had just finished reading this book when the Supreme Court leak happened, which means my ear has been tuned to the language as the outrage exploded and conversations whirled around.
A large part of Emily Martin’s thesis is about the language and metaphor we use for the body—particularly women’s bodies.</description></item><item><title>Machiavelli in Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/machiavelli-in-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/machiavelli-in-love/</guid><description>Ruggiero does it again: a great companion piece to months of Renaissance reading, including [[authors/niccolo machiavelli|Machiavelli]].</description></item></channel></rss>