<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>memoir on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/memoir/</link><description>Recent content in memoir on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/memoir/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Road to San Giovanni</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-road-to-san-giovanni/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-road-to-san-giovanni/</guid><description>I have missed Calvino.</description></item><item><title>Hanami</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hanami/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hanami/</guid><description>The art is beautiful! The story is stressful. I have known various people in my life where, let’s just say their enthusiasm for an idea exceeds their preparation for the reality of it. I’ve suffered the consequences of this (when it’s a parent), tried to mitigate the damage (when it’s a sibling), or offered consolation in the aftermath (when it’s a friend).</description></item><item><title>Untypical</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/untypical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/untypical/</guid><description>Part memoir of a late-diagnosed autistic person (straight white British male version); part comprehensive outline of accommodations that would make the world a safer, more autistic-friendly place. Some are so laughably trivial that it’s shameful they even have to be requested in the first place—but alas, that’s the world we live in.</description></item><item><title>Wintering</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</guid><description>DNF due to the health scare(s) both May and her husband experience at the beginning of the book. Even though I knew they were okay, it was too much to relive in the moment, my own recent family health scares too fresh. I skimmed ahead to see if I could just skip that part, but multiple other chapters failed to grab me.</description></item><item><title>The Cyclist and His Shadow</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cyclist-and-his-shadow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cyclist-and-his-shadow/</guid><description>I like how right away, in the forward, Thomazeau François is pitting this book against [[books/the rider|The Rider]] as the seminal classic of cycling literature. I arched a skeptical eyebrow, and… was in total agreement by like, chapter 3.
Brilliant. Insane. Philosophical. Spiritual. Erotic. I read it during the nearly-hallucinatory six hours of Milan—San Remo and feel like bits of it have embedded in my brain like gravel, because I think of it every time I watch a race.</description></item><item><title>The Rider</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rider/</guid><description>My dear friend Karen made sure I got this book for an October gift, and since pro cycling is currently trying to do a nine month season in two months, including three grand tours, why not pile on some more and make this my cycling read of the (Covid-shortened) season?</description></item><item><title>Ducks</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ducks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ducks/</guid><description>Reading this alongside a friend who grew up in Alberta around the oil sands… oof. (Who has also been an internet friend since back in the livejournal/Hark! A Vagrant era.) It’s universal by being so specific. It’s also more dystopian than some dystopias I’ve read, yet done with nuance and empathy.</description></item><item><title>What My Bones Know</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-my-bones-know/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-my-bones-know/</guid><description>Incredible memoir. One of the best books I’ve read about healing from abuse, dysfunction, and trauma. So much to relate to on every page (and not just because she had the same Jimmy Eat World song as a lifeline in the early aughts).
It’s heartbreaking and eye-opening that her upbringing (Asian, middle-class, immigrant; raised in what she correctly calls the wreckage of America’s brutal proxy wars against communism) is almost a 1:1 overlap with what was going on behind the scenes for almost everyone I knew growing up (white, middle-class, evangelical; basically the inheritors of the “American dream”).</description></item><item><title>One Day I’ll Grow Up and Be a Beautiful Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</guid><description>Nonfiction memoir about a mother raising her autistic, transgender daughter and the New Hampshire town that puts their family through hell. It’s harrowing and heartbreaking, a survival guide (barely? hopefully?) about weathering the eye of the current political storm.a I’m always looking for books I can recommend to well-meaning people who want to see past the transphobic headlines, and this one goes on the list.</description></item></channel></rss>