<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>trauma-therapy on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/trauma-therapy/</link><description>Recent content in trauma-therapy on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/trauma-therapy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gideon the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</guid><description>WOULD HAVE HARROWHARK’S BABIES.
I mean, it’s a good thing I like nice people in real life, because in fiction, Harrowhark is 10000% my type.
And just, 10/10 on working through your Catholic upbringing by writing meme-filled fic about blood sacrifice and redemption and necromancy and lesbian saints and cavaliers.</description></item><item><title>Harrow the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</guid><description>Amount of times this book made me cry: [redacted]. It is a sum equal to or only slightly less than the amount of times it made me cackle, gasp, and yelp.
“I cannot behold that apocalypse, Harrow. I think you are one of the only Lyctors who can really and truly understand apocalypse… It is not a death of fire.</description></item><item><title>Bitter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</guid><description>Is this even better than [[books/pet|Pet]]? Holy crap, I think so. The struggle. The hope. The tenderness. It knocked me sideways. I love it.
Bitter had learned it was better to be stoic, to be a blank and unfeeling wall, because if you were entirely armor and no underbelly, then they couldn’t stab you in the soft places.</description></item><item><title>Nona the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</guid><description>Verdict still stands after book three: would have Harrowhark’s babies.
The end of [[books/gideon the ninth|Gideon]] had some pacing things, the start of [[books/harrow the ninth|Harrow]] had some pacing things; Nona was the one I barreled through in 1.5 days because I could not put the book down.</description></item><item><title>A Woman Is No Man</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</guid><description>We need more books by Palestinian and Arab authors. I intend to read more by Etaf Rum. But it pains me to say… I think this could have been a (powerful) short story. The structure and even dialogue is very repetitive, in a way that I’m sure is meant to illustrate the cyclical and generational cycle of abuse, but instead means you could skim chapters and not miss anything.</description></item><item><title>Evil Eye</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</guid><description>This is why I wanted to read more Etaf Rum. This is the book I knew she had in her. It’s just as brilliant and damning a portrait of a toxic marriage as [[books/liars|Liars]] was, with the added generational trauma and displacement of a Palestinian family.</description></item><item><title>Blackouts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</guid><description>All the different layers of meaning to the title—the blackouts our narrator experiences due to PTSD, the blackouts of Juan and his fading memory, the failure of institutional memory, the queer erasure from history, the literal blackouts of the pages of the book. It feels like a work of art, not just a novel.</description></item><item><title>Liars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liars/</guid><description>Brilliant, merciless, couldn’t put it down. Jane marries John (Bridges, but might as well be Doe, for all the universality implied), and misery ensues as John exploits his masculine privilege and his own insecurities to make Jane’s life hell.
Written as autofiction with a dash of crime fiction, it’s an autopsy of a 21st century marriage between two (eventually wealthy) white straight people, who are best placed to reap the benefits of modern feminism and equality, and instead expose the grotesque flaws and inequalities.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>Is This Autism?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/is-this-autism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/is-this-autism/</guid><description>Once again I have read my way up from beginner to clinical level on a subject in the space of a year. I’m going to make a declarative statement that this is currently the best resource out there, full stop, on ASD and the myriad of ways it presents.</description></item><item><title>The Autistic Survival Guide to Therapy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autistic-survival-guide-to-therapy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autistic-survival-guide-to-therapy/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ducks</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ducks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ducks/</guid><description>Reading this alongside a friend who grew up in Alberta around the oil sands… oof. (Who has also been an internet friend since back in the livejournal/Hark! A Vagrant era.) It’s universal by being so specific. It’s also more dystopian than some dystopias I’ve read, yet done with nuance and empathy.</description></item><item><title>Clear and Muddy Loss of Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</guid><description>This is just what I was in the mood for, a 300+ chapter, 4000 page sapphic slow burn court intrigue. The prose (and/or translation?) is more functional than beautiful on a sentence level, but on a plot level, with the overall character arcs, QJMX has some mad skill.</description></item><item><title>Exodus 20</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:55:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</guid><description>If you’re gonna write monster kink, make it a biblically accurate angel. And throw in some searing social/political/theological commentary. This was excellent.</description></item><item><title>Everyone in This Room Will Someday Be Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:21:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</guid><description>This is the most strongly coded [[notes/autism|autistic]] protagonist I’ve read. Especially of the female, high-masking, chronic burnout variety, and undiagnosed. (Or rather, insufficiently diagnosed with anxiety and depression.) The unconscious stimming! Chronic sensory overload! The shutdowns! The meltdowns! The masking!
I feel like I am operating my body like it’s a vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Among Others</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</guid><description>“[[notes/bibliotropic|Bibliotropic]],” Hugh said. “Like sunflowers are heliotropic, they naturally turn towards the sun. We naturally turn towards the bookshop.”
Where do I begin? What is this book about? Books, yes. A love of books and of libraries. Books as lifeline and language. It’s about a girl growing up, and witches and fairies and boarding schools and grief and Wales and loneliness even amongst those with whom you might belong.</description></item><item><title>Interesting Facts about Space</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</guid><description>Me [page 1]: I’m worried I read too much about [[notes/autism|ASD]] into [[books/everyone in this room will someday be dead|Everyone in This Room Will Someday be Dead]]. This time I’m gonna look for all the ways it’s not autism. I will counteract my bias.
Me [page 20]: This is autism.</description></item><item><title>The Body Keeps the Score</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-body-keeps-the-score/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-body-keeps-the-score/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What My Bones Know</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-my-bones-know/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-my-bones-know/</guid><description>Incredible memoir. One of the best books I’ve read about healing from abuse, dysfunction, and trauma. So much to relate to on every page (and not just because she had the same Jimmy Eat World song as a lifeline in the early aughts).
It’s heartbreaking and eye-opening that her upbringing (Asian, middle-class, immigrant; raised in what she correctly calls the wreckage of America’s brutal proxy wars against communism) is almost a 1:1 overlap with what was going on behind the scenes for almost everyone I knew growing up (white, middle-class, evangelical; basically the inheritors of the “American dream”).</description></item><item><title>Camp Damascus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</guid><description>I had to wait until I was in a good headspace to handle this. Ruth, an autistic devout Christian on the cusp of adulthood, begins to realize everything in her life is not as it seems, not even herself. Cue the horror of religious trauma and conversion therapy camps, right at home with the traditional trappings of the horror genre.</description></item><item><title>One Day I’ll Grow Up and Be a Beautiful Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</guid><description>Nonfiction memoir about a mother raising her autistic, transgender daughter and the New Hampshire town that puts their family through hell. A harrowing and heartbreaking survival guide (barely? hopefully?) about weathering the eye of the current political storm. I’m always looking for books I can recommend to well-meaning people who want to see past the transphobic headlines, and this one goes on the list.</description></item></channel></rss>