<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>science on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/science/</link><description>Recent content in science on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Physicists are the poets of the scientific world</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/physicists-are-the-poets-of-the-scientific-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/physicists-are-the-poets-of-the-scientific-world/</guid><description>Physicists are the poets of the scientific world, more playful and less hidebound creatures than, say, biologists—once you can embrace alternate universes, dark matter, and quantum physics, it’s not much of a leap for other things.
Curiously, it’s largely physicists who have proved receptive to such ideas.</description></item><item><title>The external world is as much you as your own body</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-external-world-is-as-much-you-as-your-own-body/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-external-world-is-as-much-you-as-your-own-body/</guid><description>Any good scientist knows that what you call the external world is as much you as your own body. Your skin doesn’t actually separate you from the world—it’s a bridge through which the world flows into you, and you flow into the world. You’re just like a whirlpool.</description></item><item><title>Cognitive biases don’t prove we’re bad at thinking</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cognitive-biases-dont-prove-were-bad-at-thinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cognitive-biases-dont-prove-were-bad-at-thinking/</guid><description>Instead of illustrating how stupid people are, cognitive biases actually show how much work our brain is doing to make us good at thinking. Visual illusions can fool the eye with clever tricks, and cognitive illusions can do the same, helping us understand how the mind works and how the mind breaks.</description></item></channel></rss>