<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>philosophy on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in philosophy on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The concept of lila and cosmic playfulness</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-concept-of-lila-and-cosmic-playfulness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-concept-of-lila-and-cosmic-playfulness/</guid><description>In Hinduism, the concept of lila is that all of life—indeed, the cosmos—is an expression of divine, cosmic playfulness.
Lila (or leela) can be loosely translated as “divine play”. The concept of lila asserts that creation, instead of being an objective for achieving any purpose, is rather an outcome of the playful nature of the divine.</description></item><item><title>At every level we are a web of interdependencies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/at-every-level-we-are-a-web-of-interdependencies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/at-every-level-we-are-a-web-of-interdependencies/</guid><description>When we talk about being inseparable from the universe, or an animistic view of the world, it’s not uniformity, conformity, or a primordial soup where everything is nothing and nothing is everything. From the macro to the micro, it’s very much a web of interdependencies.</description></item><item><title>Be like a cat and let go of yourself</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/be-like-a-cat-and-let-go-of-yourself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/be-like-a-cat-and-let-go-of-yourself/</guid><description>The more relaxed you are, the more flexible you are, the more lightly you land.
When a cat falls out of a tree, it lets go of itself. The cat becomes completely relaxed, and lands lightly on the ground. But if a cat were about to fall out of a tree and suddenly make up its mind that it didn’t want to fall, it would become tense and rigid, and would be just a bag of broken bones upon landing.</description></item><item><title>Naturalistic fallacy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/naturalistic-fallacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/naturalistic-fallacy/</guid><description>Naturalistic fallacy is the assumption that whatever is natural is good, and vice versa. It’s far too easily based on cherry-picking and nonsense, and is not a solid foundation for ethics.
In [[books/perv|Perv]], [[authors/jesse bering|Jesse Bering]] points out that we jump too quickly to the naturalistic fallacy in pursuit of LGBTQ rights:</description></item><item><title>The external world is as much you as your own body</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-external-world-is-as-much-you-as-your-own-body/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-external-world-is-as-much-you-as-your-own-body/</guid><description>Any good scientist knows that what you call the external world is as much you as your own body. Your skin doesn’t actually separate you from the world—it’s a bridge through which the world flows into you, and you flow into the world. You’re just like a whirlpool.</description></item><item><title>We are both a wave and a particle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-both-a-wave-and-a-particle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-both-a-wave-and-a-particle/</guid><description>We cannot be separate from the universe any more than an apple can grow separate from an apple tree, or a wave can exist without the ocean.
You and I are as continuous with the physical universe as a wave is continuous with the ocean.</description></item><item><title>We are the process of the universe</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-the-process-of-the-universe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-the-process-of-the-universe/</guid><description>We are not the result of evolution, or the big bang, or a consequence of the physical universe, we are the process of it. That we are separate is an illusion we’ve invented ourselves.
If there was a big bang at the beginning of time, you are not something that is the result of that explosion at the end of the process.</description></item><item><title>We are wiggles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-wiggles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-wiggles/</guid><description>The physical world is wiggly as all get-out! We are the ones who try to box things in with our concrete categories and straight lines.
See, the physical world is wiggly. Clouds, mountains, trees, people—everything is wiggly. It’s only when human beings get working on things that they build buildings in straight lines and try to make the world unwiggly.</description></item><item><title>The earth grows people</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-earth-grows-people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-earth-grows-people/</guid><description>The earth grows people the way an apple grows apple trees. The earth is not infested with living organisms—we are are symptomatic of the earth, which is symptomatic of the universe.
If there is any such thing as intelligence or love or beauty, you find it in other people.</description></item><item><title>Taoism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/taoism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/taoism/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Animism is a dynamic, relational structure</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/animism-is-a-dynamic-relational-structure/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 14:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/animism-is-a-dynamic-relational-structure/</guid><description>Animism is a belief in the “animation of all nature” (E. B. Tylor), where “the world and its various powers are neither good nor bad… but open, efficacious, and above all, relational.” (Graham Harvey)
Far from abolishing or preventing distinctions, then, this sort of animacy produces differences locally and interactively.</description></item><item><title>It’s difficult to control something that wiggles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/its-difficult-to-control-something-that-wiggles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/its-difficult-to-control-something-that-wiggles/</guid><description>It’s notoriously difficult to get control over something that wiggles. A fish, a cat, a worm, a snake—the more wiggly, the more fluid, the less it can be controlled, contained, or even measured.
When you want control over something that wiggles, it’s pretty difficult. A fish is extremely wiggly.</description></item></channel></rss>