<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>criminal-element on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/criminal-element/</link><description>Recent content in criminal-element on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/criminal-element/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Thief in the Night</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-thief-in-the-night/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-thief-in-the-night/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Love Remedy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:35:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</guid><description>I noped out hard at the kiss during a panic attack(!!!), and it never won me back. I did skim through the rest to find out whodunnit, which means I was annoyed by whodunnit (it’s just nonsensical based on the characterization within the book!), with bonus annoyance that there’s some minor kinkiness (yay blindfolds!</description></item><item><title>Too Like the Lightning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</guid><description>Of course I’m immediately starting all over again after [[books/perhaps the stars|Perhaps The Stars]]. Every time, tingling chills down my spine on page 254:
I am the window through which you watch the coming storm. He is the lightning.
I can ditto [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]], who says, “I love this book with the passionate love of an exploding supernova, but every book isn’t for everyone.</description></item><item><title>A Marvellous Light</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</guid><description>Fun Edwardian murder mystery. Fun world building. God save Edwin from the idiotic flower of English manhood.</description></item><item><title>Proper English</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</guid><description>It’s the House Party from Hell, and the first time I read it, I was like this is exhausting, it’s claustrophobic, not sure I can vibe with it—but then I read it again in 2020 and YES. It is a MOOD.</description></item><item><title>Prosperity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/prosperity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/prosperity/</guid><description>Adore it truly, deeply.</description></item><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>The Secret Lives of Country Gentlemen</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</guid><description>Update: Yep. [[books/a noblemans guide to seducing a scoundrel|Second book]] delivers the very necessary half of the whole. I adored it, and now I adore this one on re-read. Everything that just felt a slight step off pace the first time was solved with a deeper, closer read, and the addition of Luke’s story.</description></item><item><title>The Rat-Catcher’s Daughter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</guid><description>Very sweet and dare I say necessary before [[books/gilded cage|Gilded Cage]]. It has some pretty key context. And come on—that title.</description></item><item><title>Slippery Creatures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</guid><description>My favorite KJ Charles yet.
I should probably wait till the end of the trilogy to make declarative statements, but there’s WWI spies and bookshops and gentle friendship despite odds and this is as far into my wheelhouse as you can get until, like, sheep herding or Belgium is involved.</description></item><item><title>The Gentle Art of Fortune Hunting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-gentle-art-of-fortune-hunting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-gentle-art-of-fortune-hunting/</guid><description>So sweet! Will read again, because I felt I read it too quickly. (And kind of wanted way more of the roleplay/pretext stuff&amp;hellip;.)</description></item><item><title>A Restless Truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</guid><description>This was so close to being great. SO CLOSE. But overall, the book felt kind of like the menagerie on board the ship, let loose in all directions, refusing to be corralled. There were some structure/plot/writing choices that left me more stumped than dazzled. Maud’s and Violet’s POV seemed really interchangeable for the first half, which is&amp;hellip; not great when one is a supposedly scandalous, sardonic, shrewd actress and one is a sheltered, capricious, stubborn young girl.</description></item><item><title>Seven Surrenders</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</guid><description>There’s no way I can talk comprehensively about this series, so for now I’m just going to keep a running list of different things I notice each time I read them. This time (2/2023), it was how the many names for JEDD Mason echoes the [[notes/apophatic naming|apophatic naming]] of God, a classical theological strategy of the “negative” naming, an effort to call God by every time, thereby acknowledging and preserving God’s transcendence of all of them.</description></item><item><title>Think of England</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</guid><description>This is pulp with all the trappings—daring spies, dastardly villains, plots galore—and yet it’s so grounded in real emotion it hardly feels like pulp at all. Except for the part that’s so entertaining I devoured it in two days.
Great book. Great pairing. KJ Charles does it again.</description></item><item><title>Any Old Diamonds</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/any-old-diamonds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/any-old-diamonds/</guid><description>As KJC says: In which we stick it to a duke.
What [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] was to 2018, Any Old Diamonds is to 2019. It’s SO good. An instant favorite. I might have to re-read both to decide which one I like best, and if it’s too close to call, which only means I should read them a third and fourth time, I won’t mind a bit.</description></item><item><title>Bitter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</guid><description>Is this even better than [[books/pet|Pet]]? Holy crap, I think so. The struggle. The hope. The tenderness. It knocked me sideways. I love it.
Bitter had learned it was better to be stoic, to be a blank and unfeeling wall, because if you were entirely armor and no underbelly, then they couldn’t stab you in the soft places.</description></item><item><title>The Sugared Game</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</guid><description>The reason it takes me a week to read a book that I literally can’t put down is because I read it twice.
When I read [[books/slippery creatures|Slippery Creatures]], I wanted to say, this is what it looks like when an author levels up. I refrained, but I’m not going to wait til book three to say it: this is what it looks like when an author levels up.</description></item><item><title>A Nobleman’s Guide to Seducing a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>So I somehow didn’t even realize my preorder of the paperback arrived two weeks early (!!!), meaning I’ve already read this twice by the time I got the “book release day!” email this morning.
Oops.
Except not oops, because I needed the last two weeks with this book.</description></item><item><title>A Fashionable Indulgence</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</guid><description>Ditto [[books/a seditious affair|A Seditious Affair]]: first read this years ago; out of order then in order; its politics are even more relevant now. There is a refreshing lack of drama between Harry and Julius—their conflict is external—and I greatly appreciate a romance with the guts to do that.</description></item><item><title>A Power Unbound</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</guid><description>Here is my theory from [[books/a restless truth|book 2]]: the Blyths suit me best in small doses. Robin and Maud, respectively, were the most difficult parts of their own books for me. They’re just so young, energetic, athletic, upstanding, so shiny, so beautiful, so aggressively… “normal,” for lack of a better word, when I prefer crankiness and weariness and a bit of tarnish on the bronze these days.</description></item><item><title>The Duke at Hazard</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</guid><description>I have a few auto-buy (auto-preorder) authors, but KJ Charles is the only one where I drop everything to start reading the day a new book comes out. Here, that impatience is rewarded with a tender, slow-blooming romance-on-the-run between Daizell, a disgraced non-scoundrel scoundrel (he’s paying for the sins of his father), and Cassian, aka The Duke, aka Vernon Fortescue Cassian George de Vere Crosse, the fourth Duke of Severn, the Earl of Harmsford, Baron Crosse of Wotton, and Baron Vere, who’s incognito for a month to hunt down a thief and win a wager (he’s burdened with the premature inheritance of his father’s title).</description></item><item><title>The Will to Battle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</guid><description>Reader, I cried like Mycroft Canner. It’s very much the first half of a whole (third quarter of four?), and it needs [[books/perhaps the stars|the last book]] to be complete, but what a feat it is on its own.</description></item><item><title>Subtle Blood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</guid><description>I might have accidentally read Subtle Blood again, since I might have accidentally experienced a vivid dream of Will, Kim, Phoebe, and Maisie on a Parisian adventure (cameo by Teddy Molyneaux, of course), and upon waking, might have accidentally been distraught that that book wasn’t going to exist.</description></item><item><title>A Seditious Affair</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</guid><description>This was my first KJ Charles, purchased and read—I just looked it up—March 2017. I then read the whole series (out of order, of course), re-read this one in 2018, again in 2019, and somehow reviewed nary a one before 2020.
I feel so sentimental.</description></item><item><title>Perhaps the Stars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</guid><description>I still haven’t found the words to talk about this one. Maybe next year I will. It should be in the Smithsonian, or win the Nobel prize, or something, as one of humanity’s greatest achievements.</description></item><item><title>A Gentleman’s Position</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-gentlemans-position/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-gentlemans-position/</guid><description>It’s the favorite recurring KJ Charles theme: sometimes you just need a villain instead of a hero. See [[books/wanted a gentleman|Wanted, A Gentleman]] or [[books/the henchmen of zenda|Henchmen of Zenda]], et. al. My love language is elaborate schemes by crafty bastards, so you can guess how happy I was by the end.</description></item><item><title>How to Fall for a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>A thief and a private investigator team up to solve a theft, and the vibes are basically a case-of-the-week tv episode (think Charlie’s Angels, Remington Steele, White Collar, etc) playing historical dress-up. The plot is as straightforward as it gets—they search for a macguffin, they get a clue, they get another clue, they solve the case.</description></item><item><title>The Autobiography of Benvenuto Cellini</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autobiography-of-benvenuto-cellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autobiography-of-benvenuto-cellini/</guid><description>Necromancy, assassinations, prison breaks, poisonings, stabbings (so many stabbings!!), pranks on Michelangelo… dude lived a life. Come for the adventure, stay for the fascinating glimpse into Renaissance life and art. I read because [[authors/lois mcmaster bujold|Bujold]] based part of [[books/the spirit ring|The Spirit Ring]] on Cellini and said fact was stranger than fiction… she was not wrong.</description></item><item><title>Decameron</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/decameron/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/decameron/</guid><description>Hey, remember way back when there was this pandemic happening? This was good reading during it.</description></item><item><title>The Fox Wife</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</guid><description>Not the right choice to follow Nghi Vo’s [[books/the brides of high hill|fox-spirit tale]]. Atmospheric, but I feel talked down to and everything is over-explained. This is why I like sticking to genre for Asian fantasy instead of litfic. DNF @ pg 60. (I did flip through the rest because the hardcover had wide margins for sidenotes, but there were… barely any?</description></item><item><title>The Black Jersey</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</guid><description>It takes until page 280 for the main character to say, “I am an imbecile,” which is the truest thing in the book.
Oh boy. So many feelings. That are conflicted. Is this a book about cycling? Yes. Do I love cycling? Yes. Do I love books about cycling?</description></item><item><title>On the Fox Roads</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</guid><description>Nghi Vo can write [[books/the chosen and the beautiful|queer Jazz Age fanfic]] for me all day any day. (Also excellent: the Venn diagram of her Chinese and Vietnamese characters, the overlapping similarities and the differences.)</description></item><item><title>The Henchmen of Zenda</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-henchmen-of-zenda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-henchmen-of-zenda/</guid><description>When KJ Charles is on, she’s on. This book is all the things: fun, ridiculous, hilarious, swashbuckling, hot, FUN. The high pulp style suits her so well because she can pack the book full of joy and all the sneering and sniding she likes to write works because it’s comic and joyful.</description></item><item><title>The Price of Meat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</guid><description>Maybe don’t read this over lunch like I did? By which I mean, it’s fanfic of Sweeney Todd, it’s grisly horror, and it’s very good and effective, because KJ Charles. She can write anything from [[books/band sinister|Georgette Heyer homages]] to penny dreadfuls and it’s worth the ink.</description></item><item><title>Wanted, A Gentleman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</guid><description>She had me at “gothic novelist” and “lonely hearts columnist.” This is wonderful. I love it when Charles just unleashes her id.
Note: I’m including the epilogue Wanted, an Author, in which Corvin from [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] makes a cameo and Theo’s gay gothic erotica novel Jonathan: or The Struggles of Virtue is at the top of my list for books-within-a-book that I most need to read.</description></item><item><title>Unfit to Print</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unfit-to-print/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unfit-to-print/</guid><description>Print shop feels! Plus the Victorian porn trade! And yes to showing this side of British colonialism, even if that could stand to be fleshed out a bit.</description></item><item><title>A Governess’s Guide to Passion and Peril</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-governesss-guide-to-passion-and-peril/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-governesss-guide-to-passion-and-peril/</guid><description>The fourth in a series, and I read at least one of the first three during the fugue state years when my dad’s health was failing, so I have only the haziest memory of it. That might mean I’m missing something, as it never felt explained in the text why the other women hadn’t come to Jane’s aid before now, nor why Jane’s feelings for Adrian would evolve beyond a schoolgirl crush.</description></item></channel></rss>