<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>war-is-hell on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/war-is-hell/</link><description>Recent content in war-is-hell on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/war-is-hell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Black Tides of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</guid><description>Note from my future self: this makes an excellent prequel, I should have started with [[books/the red threads of fortune|book 2]]!</description></item><item><title>Too Like the Lightning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</guid><description>Of course I’m immediately starting all over again after [[books/perhaps the stars|Perhaps The Stars]]. Every time, tingling chills down my spine on page 254:
I am the window through which you watch the coming storm. He is the lightning.
I can ditto [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]], who says, “I love this book with the passionate love of an exploding supernova, but every book isn’t for everyone.</description></item><item><title>What Moves the Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</guid><description>Just what I wanted for October: brilliant gothic fanfiction of The Fall of the House of Usher with even more fungi than Poe. Creepy and exquisite, and that’s not just the cover art.
(With a bonus Beatrix Potter relative, clever worldbuilding linguistics w/r/t gender, and a hat tip to Prisoner of Zenda!</description></item><item><title>A Thief in the Night</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-thief-in-the-night/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-thief-in-the-night/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Sorcerer of the Wildeeps</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sorcerer-of-the-wildeeps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sorcerer-of-the-wildeeps/</guid><description>Whoa. Masterful use of dialect and structure to deconstruct the traditional bounds of genre and narrative. The way the characters code-switch their way through multiple registers and languages—well-known and invented—is reflected in the way the novella flips through genres like a catalog, exposing the expectations and limitations of each.</description></item><item><title>The Secret Lives of Country Gentlemen</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</guid><description>Update: Yep. [[books/a noblemans guide to seducing a scoundrel|Second book]] delivers the very necessary half of the whole. I adored it, and now I adore this one on re-read. Everything that just felt a slight step off pace the first time was solved with a deeper, closer read, and the addition of Luke’s story.</description></item><item><title>Slippery Creatures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</guid><description>After the recent spate of lackluster histroms that were trying to do various spy and mystery related things, I was pining for Will Darling. Enter Chirp audiobooks with a well-timed deal on the series bundle, and before you could say Lord Arthur Aloysius Kimberly de Brabazon Secretan, I had the dulcet tones of Cornell Collins narrating my favorite KJ Charles competence porn.</description></item><item><title>Confounding Oaths</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/confounding-oaths/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/confounding-oaths/</guid><description>I was exactly in the mood for this. Cynical fairies and curses from the gods and a family in shambles. The romance is there, and quite lovely, but it’s off to one side, and that suits my mood too. The Caesar sisters and the Irregulars of the militia take up space on page, which makes me happy.</description></item><item><title>The Red Threads of Fortune</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</guid><description>This should have been book 1! Or I should have done my typical thing of reading out of order and started here! The one time I try to be responsible and read a series in order, this is what happens.
Technically, these are “twin novellas,” but IMO, Mokoya is the emotional core of the story, followed by Rider, and Akeha in [[books/the black tides of heaven|Black Tides]] is an interesting prequel.</description></item><item><title>Seven Surrenders</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</guid><description>There’s no way I can talk comprehensively about this series, so for now I’m just going to keep a running list of different things I notice each time I read them. This time (2/2023), it was how the many names for JEDD Mason echoes the [[notes/apophatic naming|apophatic naming]] of God, a classical theological strategy of the “negative” naming, an effort to call God by every time, thereby acknowledging and preserving God’s transcendence of all of them.</description></item><item><title>Think of England</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</guid><description>This is pulp with all the trappings—daring spies, dastardly villains, plots galore—and yet it’s so grounded in real emotion it hardly feels like pulp at all. Except for the part that’s so entertaining I devoured it in two days.
Great book. Great pairing. KJ Charles does it again.</description></item><item><title>Bitter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</guid><description>Is this even better than [[books/pet|Pet]]? Holy crap, I think so. The struggle. The hope. The tenderness. It knocked me sideways. I love it.
Bitter had learned it was better to be stoic, to be a blank and unfeeling wall, because if you were entirely armor and no underbelly, then they couldn’t stab you in the soft places.</description></item><item><title>The Sugared Game</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sugared-game/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sugared-game/</guid><description>Re-read 12/24.
Way back the first time I read it, I praised all the talk—long pages and chapters full of Will and Kim talking. That still stands, but I would also like to add praise for the long pages and chapters full of Will and Phoebe talking, and Will and Maisie talking.</description></item><item><title>A Nobleman’s Guide to Seducing a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>So I somehow didn’t even realize my preorder of the paperback arrived two weeks early (!!!), meaning I’ve already read this twice by the time I got the “book release day!” email this morning.
Oops.
Except not oops, because I needed the last two weeks with this book.</description></item><item><title>A Fashionable Indulgence</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</guid><description>Ditto [[books/a seditious affair|A Seditious Affair]]: first read this years ago; out of order then in order; its politics are even more relevant now. There is a refreshing lack of drama between Harry and Julius—their conflict is external—and I greatly appreciate a romance with the guts to do that.</description></item><item><title>The Will to Battle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</guid><description>Reader, I cried like Mycroft Canner. It’s very much the first half of a whole (third quarter of four?), and it needs [[books/perhaps the stars|the last book]] to be complete, but what a feat it is on its own.</description></item><item><title>The Hallowed Hunt</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</guid><description>Not the heights of Ista or Cazaril, but going backwards in this timeline instead of forwards is a choice I admire. I can see returning to this one as often as the two favorites, especially if those two get worn out by re-reading.</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 3</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Subtle Blood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</guid><description>I might have accidentally read Subtle Blood again, since I might have accidentally experienced a vivid dream of Will, Kim, Phoebe, and Maisie on a Parisian adventure (cameo by Teddy Molyneaux, of course), and upon waking, might have accidentally been distraught that that book wasn’t going to exist.</description></item><item><title>A Seditious Affair</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</guid><description>This was my first KJ Charles, purchased and read—I just looked it up—March 2017. I then read the whole series (out of order, of course), re-read this one in 2018, again in 2019, and somehow reviewed nary a one before 2020.
I feel so sentimental.</description></item><item><title>Perhaps the Stars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</guid><description>I still haven’t found the words to talk about this one. Maybe next year I will. It should be in the Smithsonian, or win the Nobel prize, or something, as one of humanity’s greatest achievements.</description></item><item><title>The Dispossessed</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dispossessed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dispossessed/</guid><description>Sublime. Carefully constructed, nuanced, warmly empathetic, passionately human, complex. If you want a rose-colored ideologue that purports to fix problems with simplistic utopias, look elsewhere. If you want an accounting of our society’s ills, and alternatives that are just as complicated and imperfect, you’re in the right place.</description></item><item><title>Propaganda Blitz</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/propaganda-blitz/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/propaganda-blitz/</guid><description>For years I’ve wanted a successor to [[books/manufacturing consent|Manufacturing Consent]] that is a bit more current and accessible — this might not exactly fill those shoes, but it comes pretty damn close.
See the helpful excerpt here: [[notes/anatomy of a propaganda blitz|anatomy of a propaganda blitz]]</description></item><item><title>Everyone Knows Your Mother Is a Witch</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:01:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</guid><description>Historical (fan)fiction of Katarina Kepler, Johannes Kepler’s mother, famously tried as a witch. It’s fantastic, the character work, the structure, the narrative voice(s), the exuberant black humor that becomes blacker and blacker as it follows the warp of history. An impressive example of what the genre can do, no boring litfic pretentiousness here.</description></item><item><title>China Mountain Zhang</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Forest of Noise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</guid><description>How do you write the unimaginable? How do you craft art from the horror? How do you count your loved ones, now dead, in lines of poems?
I read this twice, once fast, once slow, and let it break me. 50 years of occupation and apartheid.</description></item><item><title>Mother Night</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mother-night/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mother-night/</guid><description/></item><item><title>On Genocide</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-genocide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-genocide/</guid><description>Sartre in 1967:
When a peasant falls in his rice paddy, mowed down by a machine gun, every one of us is hit. The Vietnamese fight for all men and the American forces against all. Neither figuratively nor abstractly. And not only because genocide would be a crime universally condemned by international law, but because little by little the whole human race is being subjected to this genocidal blackmail piled on top of atomic blackmail, that is, to absolute, total war.</description></item><item><title>On Palestine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</guid><description>Many of the world’s problems are so intractable that it’s hard to think of ways even to take steps toward mitigating them.
The Israel-Palestine conflict is not one of these.
I admit I’ve fallen prey to the line, re: the occupation of Palestine, “it’s too complex to understand.</description></item><item><title>Slaughterhouse-Five</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slaughterhouse-five/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slaughterhouse-five/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ten Myths About Israel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ten-myths-about-israel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ten-myths-about-israel/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Lathe Of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-lathe-of-heaven/</guid><description>I can’t remember the last time I read a book with a truly passive protagonist, where his qualities are not his weakness, but his strength. He doesn’t change who he is. There is no lesson needed. He is the virtue, not the flaw. Le Guin stacks George Orr up against the passionate Huber who wants to save the world, and carefully and thoroughly makes the case for the former.</description></item><item><title>Dirty Wars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/dirty-wars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/dirty-wars/</guid><description>[Insert string of obscenities] at the things the United States has done. The best thing this book does is make it perfectly clear there isn’t right-wing or left-wing. It spans two crucial presidencies (Bush II and Obama), and the substantive difference is that the former worried how far they could push things and the latter did not care.</description></item><item><title>Pride and Prejudice</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pride-and-prejudice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pride-and-prejudice/</guid><description>Austen is so compulsively readable that I’ve already accomplished my re-read of Pride and Prejudice too. And don’t worry, I’m not about to be the killjoy that strips the romance from it this time. This novel is romantic, a true meeting of minds with the happiest ending Jane Austen has on offer.</description></item><item><title>A Lady for a Duke</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-lady-for-a-duke/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-lady-for-a-duke/</guid><description>Re-read 11/24. Drastic measures were needed after so many historical romance duds lately, especially with duke in the title. I wanted something full of sweeping romance on a foggy moor, angst and glory and tenderness. This was the safest bet possible.
I liked it the first time, but I loved it this time.</description></item><item><title>Manufacturing Consent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/manufacturing-consent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/manufacturing-consent/</guid><description>Infuriatingly and terrifyingly relevant. Like, up to this very day, where you couldn’t even update the book with current examples because there are too many to choose from. Venezuela, Syria, Iran. Ad infinitum. It’s all following the same script. Where you could argue the book is dated, that actually further proves its point, such as the west’s support and glorification of Putin thirty years ago when he fit their needs in a different way.</description></item><item><title>Persuasion</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/persuasion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/persuasion/</guid><description>Persuasion in context Since this was a re-read after [[books/jane austen the secret radical|Jane Austen, The Secret Radical]], I’m going to put my relevant highlights from that book here.
The references to Burney in Northanger Abbey date to the late 1790s or very early nineteenth century, certainly no later than 1802 or 1803, because in 1802 Burney traveled to France to assist her French husband in some family business, taking advantage of the short-lived cessation of hostilities between France and Britain.</description></item><item><title>The Charioteer</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-charioteer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-charioteer/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Last of the Wine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-last-of-the-wine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-last-of-the-wine/</guid><description>So very good. Here I was thinking the writing style kept me at a remove from the story and I wasn’t as invested as I could be, and then the last two chapters walloped me in the gut and I realized it had me at the emotional level after all.</description></item><item><title>The Autobiography of Benvenuto Cellini</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autobiography-of-benvenuto-cellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-autobiography-of-benvenuto-cellini/</guid><description>Necromancy, assassinations, prison breaks, poisonings, stabbings (so many stabbings!!), pranks on Michelangelo… dude lived a life. Come for the adventure, stay for the fascinating glimpse into Renaissance life and art. I read because [[authors/lois mcmaster bujold|Bujold]] based part of [[books/the spirit ring|The Spirit Ring]] on Cellini and said fact was stranger than fiction… she was not wrong.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</guid><description>A note on translation: I used Reynolds to compare, contrast, and fill in the gaps with the [[books/orlando furioso a new verse translation|Slavitt translation]]. Slavitt takes liberties, and Reynolds has merit, but I’ve got to say, for compulsive readability, and cheeky irreverence that feels like it honors the spirit of the original, Slavitt it is.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso: A New Verse Translation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</guid><description>Ariosto writing like AO3 was a thing in the sixteenth century. I love it. Fiendishly clever layers of satire; a story where anything goes.</description></item><item><title>The Cloven Viscount</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cloven-viscount/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cloven-viscount/</guid><description>Now this is how you do a fable. What a joy the language is, even in translation. Not to mention each character, good and bad alike, equal parts lovable and bizarre. [[books/the complete cosmicomics|Once again]], the only reason I’d want to have kids is to read them Calvino.</description></item><item><title>The Prince</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-prince/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-prince/</guid><description>Non-negotiable: read [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer’s]] five-part (plus?) series on Machiavelli. I’ll wait. She makes sense of the enigma, the real Machiavelli, neither lionized nor maligned. The brave thinker; the frightened statesman. Charismatic, unorthodox, forming a response to the Borgia tyranny, trying to save his beloved Florence, playing pranks on the monks, centuries ahead of his time.</description></item><item><title>The Road to San Giovanni</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-road-to-san-giovanni/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-road-to-san-giovanni/</guid><description>I have missed Calvino.</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item><item><title>Clear and Muddy Loss of Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</guid><description>This is just what I was in the mood for, a 300+ chapter, 4000 page sapphic slow burn court intrigue. The prose (and/or translation?) is more functional than beautiful on a sentence level, but on a plot level, with the overall character arcs, QJMX has some mad skill.</description></item><item><title>Gwen &amp; Art Are Not in Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</guid><description>I think it wobbled a smiiiidge on the landing, a few things felt abrupt and/or undercooked, not to mention the jarring tonal shift into violence, but the ride to get there was super fun. There’s some fade-to-black, hand-wavey, don’t-think-too-hard-about-this energy re: the whole premature-inheritance, fix-a-broken-system-from-the-inside plan, but it is YA, and I wasn’t expecting an [[books/bitter|Akwaeke Emezi-level thesis]] on the subject of institutional power.</description></item><item><title>Cat’s Cradle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/cats-cradle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/cats-cradle/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Great Gatsby</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-great-gatsby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-great-gatsby/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Word for World is Forest</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-word-for-world-is-forest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-word-for-world-is-forest/</guid><description>This is how I like a thinly-veiled parable to work, especially an anti-colonialism one.
(There’s barely any need for fiction; it’s Vietnam.)</description></item><item><title>The Right to Maim</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-right-to-maim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 14:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-right-to-maim/</guid><description>In The Right to Maim Jasbir K. Puar brings her pathbreaking work on the liberal state, sexuality, and biopolitics to bear on our understanding of disability. Drawing on a stunning array of theoretical and methodological frameworks, Puar uses the concept of “debility”—bodily injury and social exclusion brought on by economic and political factors—to disrupt the category of disability.</description></item><item><title>Giovanni’s Room</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</guid><description>Not everyone in book club was a fan, but I loved it, but it was brutal, but I’m glad I read it, but I’m glad I won’t be in a rush to read it again.
“Somebody,” said Jacques, “your father or mine, should have told us that not many people have ever died of love.</description></item></channel></rss>