<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>belief systems on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/belief-systems/</link><description>Recent content in belief systems on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 02:13:26 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/belief-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Core values</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/core-values/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/core-values/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Getting clear on your core values prevents manipulation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/getting-clear-on-your-core-values-prevents-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/getting-clear-on-your-core-values-prevents-manipulation/</guid><description>One of the most valuable things I learned in therapy is how to define my own core values and principles. Get very clear on what drives you, and what you believe in as a set of principles, not ideology, and then use that as your guide to navigate the world.</description></item><item><title>The three lies of power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</guid><description>For all the aspiring authoritarians wanting to “do the right thing” and force their good ideas on everyone, [[authors/adam mastroianni|Adam Mastroianni]] outlines the wildly delusional three lies of power:
The good guys will always have more power than the bad guys (ed note: I’d argue, the fact we even believe good guys vs.</description></item><item><title>All of us are embedded in our own safe “reality”</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-of-us-are-embedded-in-our-own-safe-reality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-of-us-are-embedded-in-our-own-safe-reality/</guid><description>All of us are embedded in our own safe “reality,” shaping what we see and know in ways of which we are completely unaware.
Many circumstances conspire to extinguish scientific discoveries, especially those that cause discomfort about our culture’s sacred norms. As a species, we cling to the familiar, comforting conformities of the mainstream.</description></item><item><title>Behaviorist theory proves retributive justice does not work</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/behaviorist-theory-proves-retributive-justice-does-not-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/behaviorist-theory-proves-retributive-justice-does-not-work/</guid><description>Behaviorism claims that the only thing powerful enough to spur people into action is the promise of reward or the fear of punishment.
The most widely understood theoretical model of how punishment works comes from behaviorist psychology, which looks at punishment as one kind of conditioning.</description></item><item><title>Disgust is a culture-bound syndrome</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/disgust-is-a-culture-bound-syndrome/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/disgust-is-a-culture-bound-syndrome/</guid><description>Symbolic disgust is subjective, not objective, and is a [[notes/pms and other pathologies are culture-bound syndromes|culture-bound syndrome]].
What induces the symbolic disgust response is defined by prevailing cultural forces. That’s to say, for the most part we’ve learned to morally loathe whatever it is that we’ve come to do; this information isn’t genetically inborn but socially acquired.</description></item><item><title>Our best defense against stupidity is diversity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-best-defense-against-stupidity-is-diversity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-best-defense-against-stupidity-is-diversity/</guid><description>Appealing as it is want an expert in charge, the last thing we need is a committee of enlightened despots ruling the world. Tyranny is still tyranny even when the tyrants have high IQs and the right diplomas on the wall.
In college, I knew this guy who was always talking about how the world should be ruled by a “panel of experts.</description></item><item><title>The indigenous attribution of agency</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-attribution-of-agency/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-attribution-of-agency/</guid><description>In the indigenous worldview, vegetal life is granted agency and even personhood.
Each creature is directly responsible for the well-being of many beings at many times, but not for all beings at all times, and these “overlap[ping] connections” sustain a community united not by its identity to itself, but by its complex, mobile, and interrelated differentiations.</description></item><item><title>The most hideous ideologies are the ones we believe without realizing it</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-most-hideous-ideologies-are-the-ones-we-believe-without-realizing-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-most-hideous-ideologies-are-the-ones-we-believe-without-realizing-it/</guid><description>Hey! Here’s a thought! Do not yearn for the authoritarian school of social change! Do not force your ideas on anyone else! 💀
I love people, but a lot of them—maybe most?—yearn for their side to acquire absolute power. They seem to believe in the authoritarian school of social change: the only way to create a better world is for a strong central actor to force it on everybody else.</description></item><item><title>Thinking people are stupid is the gateway drug to worse ideas</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-people-are-stupid-is-the-gateway-drug-to-worse-ideas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-people-are-stupid-is-the-gateway-drug-to-worse-ideas/</guid><description>I’m highly allergic to the idea that other people are fundamentally stupid. It’s one small, flimsy step away from dehumanizing people completely, and once anyone is dehumanized, that leads to a lot of worse ideas.
If we can go from “only kings and dukes could possibly become less stupid” to “anybody can become less stupid,” maybe we can make it all the way to “people aren’t fundamentally stupid to begin with.</description></item><item><title>Moral dumbfounding is not moral reasoning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-dumbfounding-is-not-moral-reasoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-dumbfounding-is-not-moral-reasoning/</guid><description>Moral judgement and moral reasoning are basically two different processes. People tend to have a knee-jerk reaction for what’s good or bad, often based more on cultural conditioning, prejudice, or gut feelings than any reasonable morality or ethics. When asked to elaborate, you get “moral dumbfounding,” moral reasoning made up ex-post facto to justify moral judgement.</description></item><item><title>Who is more deserving</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/who-is-more-deserving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/who-is-more-deserving/</guid><description>As if deserving meant anything. As if one could earn beauty, or life!
([[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula K. Le Guin]], [[books/the dispossessed|The Dispossessed]])
Over on Sluggish, Jesse Meadows is talking about people getting ruffled “ because everyone online is autistic now.” It’s just the latest hand-wringing over [[notes/autism|autism]] as an internet trend (or insert any “-ism as an internet trend”), and the key argument is that the right people aren’t getting what they deserve, while “fakers” are taking resources away.</description></item><item><title>The theology of capitalism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/theology-of-capitalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/theology-of-capitalism/</guid><description>We have mostly forgotten to be surprised that a street preacher’s followers discovered, several hundred years after his death, how to be a regimented multinational corporate enterprise. ([[books/pagans|Pagans]], [[authors/james o&amp;rsquo;donnell|James J. O’Donnell]])
In [[books/all about love|All About Love]], [[authors/bell hooks|bell hooks]] (via Erich Fromm) says the principle underlying capitalistic society and the principle of love are incompatible.</description></item><item><title>The myth of scarcity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/myth-of-scarcity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/myth-of-scarcity/</guid><description>Kinship societies were basically replaced by dominator societies because of the threat of scarcity—so of course capitalism is committed to maintaining that myth.</description></item><item><title>The capitalist notion of well-being</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-capitalist-notion-of-well-being/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-capitalist-notion-of-well-being/</guid><description>[[authors/bell hooks|bell hooks]] in [[books/all about love|All About Love]]:
I am talking here about the many prophets of doom who tell us that racism will never end, sexism is here to stay, the rich will never share their resources. We would all be surprised if we could enter their lives for a day.</description></item><item><title>Don’t pledge allegiance to any one ideology</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/dont-pledge-allegiance-to-any-one-ideology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/dont-pledge-allegiance-to-any-one-ideology/</guid><description>Make a patchwork quilt! That’s so much more fun, effective, and reliable than devoting yourself to any one ideology.
Ideology → purity → supremacy happens all the time. Or at best, you get tangled up in labels and abstractions, and the arguments thereof.
The closest ideologies to my own values are an overlapping hodgepodge of taoism, anarchism, and indigenous animism, with a lil’ sprinkling of socialism, etc.</description></item><item><title>Flow, don’t force</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/flow-dont-force/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/flow-dont-force/</guid><description>Those who would take over the world and manage it,
I see that they cannot grasp it;
for the world is a spiritual [神 shén] vessel
and cannot be forced.
Whoever forces it spoils it.
Whoever grasps it loses it. —[[authors/lao tzu|Lao Tzu]], 29</description></item></channel></rss>