<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>arc on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/arc/</link><description>Recent content in arc on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/arc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Something Extraordinary</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</guid><description>The high-strung Belle has left behind her heroine era, and the drama-prone Rufus has left behind his Sir Horley Comewithers era. Together they embark on the worst elopement kidnapping elopement in history (per Belle, it’s not vainglorious to claim that when it’s true), and what ensues is a meditation on friendship, love, sexuality, identity, self-discovery, society, and home in a way that only Alexis Hall can do it.</description></item><item><title>Abolish Rent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/abolish-rent/</guid><description>An enthusiastic and persuasive manifesto on housing rights as human rights. It’s encouraging to see such robust organizing among tenants across the country, and the practical template for how to expand it. The authors rightly quote [[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula Le Guin]]: our housing system is a human power—produced by people, not God or nature.</description></item><item><title>Country Queers</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/country-queers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/country-queers/</guid><description>A book after my little southern queer heart. Garringer crisscrosses the Bible Belt, collecting a scrapbook and oral history of various LGBTQ+ people living in the rural margins. The older interviewees—the elders who survived the AIDS crisis and more—are the best and most emotional part. It’s easy to get miffed when people act like the Brooklyn or San Francisco subcultures are the only ones that matter, or like gay and trans people don’t exist in the south except to be persecuted.</description></item><item><title>Goddess</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/goddess/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/goddess/</guid><description>Chapbooks and zines are an art form, the ideal container for poetry. I wanted more of this one, which is the indication of a good chapbook indeed.
ARC kindly provided by the publisher via NetGalley in exchange for an honest review.</description></item><item><title>Gothic Tales</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</guid><description>Turns out I’ve read most of these stories before, but it makes sense to repackage them here for their gothic themes and add a pleasing cover. My hope springs eternal, with each new edition, that Sade gets placed in his rightful political context, his radical philosophy that’s more dangerous than any pornography.</description></item><item><title>Griso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/griso/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/griso/</guid><description>A very brief tale of a unicorn searching for other unicorns, with each spread rendered in a different historical style—Tang dynasty murals, medieval illustrations, cave paintings, African art, surrealist art, and more. The color palette and visual cues make it more cohesive than you’d think. I’d happily have it on my own shelves or gift it to nieces and nephews, both for art and story alike.</description></item><item><title>I Cross-Dressed for the IRL Meetup</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-cross-dressed-for-the-irl-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-cross-dressed-for-the-irl-meetup/</guid><description>I love seeing what Japanese manga does with gender. [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer’s]] essay on anime and manga has some of the historical context for it, but you don’t need a history lesson to enjoy this fun volume. I particularly liked the seamless inclusion of a trans girl alongside the cross-dressing boys, highlighting the differences and similarities among the two, and the lack of moral panic surrounding cross-dressing and gender in general.</description></item><item><title>The Worst Duke in London</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-worst-duke-in-london/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-worst-duke-in-london/</guid><description>I’m not averse to anachronisms in my historicals ([[authors/alexis hall|Alexis Hall]], [[authors/lex croucher|Lex Croucher]], et al. can get away with ahistorical murder), but there is anachronistic, and then there is untethered from reality. This was the latter, and not in a fun way. The info-dumping, the choppy writing, the shallow girlboss feminism, the hypersexual internal monologues, the plentiful (and destitute) dukes,1 the chaotic plot and even more chaotic characters, all of it made me bail earlier than usual.</description></item><item><title>This Will Be Fun</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/this-will-be-fun/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/this-will-be-fun/</guid><description>[[authors/lex croucher|Lex Croucher]], this is not. This landed on the wrong side of cheesy for me, and whoever compared it to The Princess Bride should have to answer for themselves. It’s a second-chance romance twice over, with two different couples who seem better off apart (although the lesbian couple was marginally better).</description></item><item><title>Lessons from Cruising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</guid><description>Joke’s on me, because I picked up this ARC for the last story, a retelling of Billy Budd from Captain Vere’s point of view. I figured I’d sample the rest; instead I went down the buffet line and inhaled them all. Rarely do I like every story in a short story collection, but that’s what Goodman’s done to me.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>We the Gathered Heat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:23:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</guid><description>Superb. This is how to do an anthology, where the disparate voices are the point—how do we even define AAPI except as “the other,” non-white? Who is the “we” in question? To whom is that category useful? The poems are sorted into themes of “mourn,” “pronounce,” “fight,” “love,” each as powerful as the last.</description></item><item><title>Come Out, Come Out</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</guid><description>In the same niche as [[books/camp damascus|Camp Damascus]], the conversion-therapy-as-horror genre. Similarities abound, even down to the senior class quarry jumps, which doesn’t indicate any co-opting of plot points but simply how ubiquitous this experience is, the same script across rural America, where any deviation from the script means there will be Consequences.</description></item><item><title>Hot Earl Summer</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hot-earl-summer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hot-earl-summer/</guid><description>A goofy, over-the-top farce with the volume dialed up to 11. Which seems absurd to complain about, given how I just read and loved [[books/something extraordinary|Something Extraordinary]]—surely if anything is dialed up to 11 it’s the Tarletons. But [[authors/alexis hall|Alexis Hall]] grounds his farce with deep emotion and intimacy, using it to scratch away at the actual farce of a society that dictates such rigid, preposterous roles.</description></item><item><title>How to Fall for a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>A thief and a private investigator team up to solve a theft, and the vibes are basically a case-of-the-week tv episode (think Charlie’s Angels, Remington Steele, White Collar, etc) playing historical dress-up. The plot is as straightforward as it gets—they search for a macguffin, they get a clue, they get another clue, they solve the case.</description></item><item><title>The Palace of Eros</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-palace-of-eros/</guid><description>My adjectives for the prose: purple, dense, florid, bloated. It sounds like I’m describing a corpse. DNF @ 15% because none of it is connecting with me, not the first-person Psyche nor the third-person Eros, nor the prose that’s turgid to the point of hyperbole. (Did I just want the chance to deploy the word turgid?</description></item><item><title>Hanami</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hanami/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hanami/</guid><description>The art is beautiful! The story is stressful. I have known various people in my life where, let’s just say their enthusiasm for an idea exceeds their preparation for the reality of it. I’ve suffered the consequences of this (when it’s a parent), tried to mitigate the damage (when it’s a sibling), or offered consolation in the aftermath (when it’s a friend).</description></item><item><title>Our History Is the Future</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/our-history-is-the-future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/our-history-is-the-future/</guid><description>An excellent re-issue of a book that&amp;rsquo;s been on my to-read list since it first published in 2019. I&amp;rsquo;m glad it finally prompted me to get to it. It’s the history of two centuries of indigenous activism in the context of even broader indigenous exploitation and resistance, and it needs to be more widely known.</description></item><item><title>Experienced</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</guid><description>Bette gets dumped-but-not-dumped in truly shitty fashion by her girlfriend, who suggests she just needs more experience since she’s newly out as a lesbian. Commence a sex odyssey through the wilds of Bristol, aided by her first failed date of the odyssey, the kind and thoughtful Ruth.</description></item><item><title>I’ll Have What He’s Having</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</guid><description>I’m glad the term tonic masculinity has been making the rounds, because this feels like tonic masculinity of the highest order. David Curtis, sommelier, mistakes Farzan Alavi for a food critic, and what blooms in the wake of this mixup is a tender, sexy, heartfelt romance between two grown adults who have to deal with the obstacles that a grown-ass relationship entails.</description></item><item><title>I’m Sorry for My Loss</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/im-sorry-for-my-loss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/im-sorry-for-my-loss/</guid><description>I know a book is going to be good when it starts off with the way language limits or distorts our understanding of a subject. Recommended to absolutely anyone, with or without a uterus, with or without the intention to procreate. It’s ostensibly about pregnancy loss and miscarriage/stillbirth awareness, but that overlaps with many things—abortion, grief, medical misogyny, racial injustice, human rights.</description></item><item><title>One Day I’ll Grow Up and Be a Beautiful Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</guid><description>Nonfiction memoir about a mother raising her autistic, transgender daughter and the New Hampshire town that puts their family through hell. It’s harrowing and heartbreaking, a survival guide (barely? hopefully?) about weathering the eye of the current political storm.a I’m always looking for books I can recommend to well-meaning people who want to see past the transphobic headlines, and this one goes on the list.</description></item></channel></rss>