<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>historical-fiction on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/historical-fiction/</link><description>Recent content in historical-fiction on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/historical-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Affair of the Mysterious Letter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</guid><description>The only thing I’ve had brain space for this week is Alexis Hall, and I say that as the highest compliment. He brings so much heart, joy, and snark even when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery. Or should I say, especially when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery.</description></item><item><title>Blackouts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</guid><description>All the different layers of meaning to the title—the blackouts our narrator experiences due to PTSD, the blackouts of Juan and his fading memory, the failure of institutional memory, the queer erasure from history, the literal blackouts of the pages of the book. It feels like a work of art, not just a novel.</description></item><item><title>The Fox Wife</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</guid><description>Not the right choice to follow Nghi Vo’s [[books/the brides of high hill|fox-spirit tale]]. Atmospheric, but I feel talked down to and everything is over-explained. This is why I like sticking to genre for Asian fantasy instead of litfic. DNF @ pg 60. (I did flip through the rest because the hardcover had wide margins for sidenotes, but there were… barely any?</description></item><item><title>Everyone Knows Your Mother Is a Witch</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</guid><description>Historical (fan)fiction of Katarina Kepler, Johannes Kepler’s mother, famously tried as a witch. It’s fantastic, the character work, the structure, the narrative voice(s), the exuberant black humor that becomes blacker and blacker as it follows the warp of history. An impressive example of what the genre can do, no boring litfic pretentiousness here.</description></item><item><title>On the Fox Roads</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-the-fox-roads/</guid><description>Nghi Vo can write [[books/the chosen and the beautiful|queer Jazz Age fanfic]] for me all day any day. (Also excellent: the Venn diagram of her Chinese and Vietnamese characters, the overlapping similarities and the differences.)</description></item><item><title>Clear and Muddy Loss of Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</guid><description>This is just what I was in the mood for, a 300+ chapter, 4000 page sapphic slow burn court intrigue. The prose (and/or translation?) is more functional than beautiful on a sentence level, but on a plot level, with the overall character arcs, QJMX has some mad skill.</description></item><item><title>Reputation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</guid><description>Lex Croucher’s lols-per-page cannot be beat.
Weirdly, the only character I was meh on was the love interest, just because he’s too perfect. (My notes say “Col Brandon in a Henry Tilney body???”) I also would have been fine if this had swung more towards a coming-of-age instead of HEA romance, but I won’t hold that against it.</description></item></channel></rss>