<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>judaism on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/judaism/</link><description>Recent content in judaism on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/judaism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Think of England</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</guid><description>This is pulp with all the trappings—daring spies, dastardly villains, plots galore—and yet it’s so grounded in real emotion it hardly feels like pulp at all. Except for the part that’s so entertaining I devoured it in two days.
Great book. Great pairing. KJ Charles does it again.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>Jesus: Apocalyptic Prophet of the New Millennium</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jesus-apocalyptic-prophet-of-the-new-millennium/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 12:34:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/jesus-apocalyptic-prophet-of-the-new-millennium/</guid><description>What I wanted [[books/zealot|Zealot]] to be.</description></item><item><title>Pagans</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 12:34:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</guid><description>About as beautifully (and concisely) written as you can get for a history book. Fabulous stuff. Some fav lines:
—Augustus revived a thing that had barely been invented in his own time: “old-time religion,” rather like the nearly postmodern version of Christianity invented in nineteenth-century America and called “fundamentalism.</description></item><item><title>Zealot</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/zealot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/zealot/</guid><description>Great at painting a picture of 1st century Palestine. So many inaccuracies though! [[books/jesus apocalyptic prophet of the new millennium|Ehrman’s was better]].
Pull quotes Nowhere is any such thing written: not in the Law of Moses, not in the prophets, not in the Psalms. In the entire history of Jewish thought there is not a single line of scripture that says the messiah is to suffer, die, and rise again on the third day, which may explain why Jesus does not bother to cite any scripture to back up his incredible claim.</description></item></channel></rss>