<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>japan on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/japan/</link><description>Recent content in japan on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Too Like the Lightning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</guid><description>Of course I’m immediately starting all over again after [[books/perhaps the stars|Perhaps The Stars]]. Every time, tingling chills down my spine on page 254:
I am the window through which you watch the coming storm. He is the lightning.
I can ditto [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]], who says, “I love this book with the passionate love of an exploding supernova, but every book isn’t for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Seven Surrenders</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</guid><description>There’s no way I can talk comprehensively about this series, so for now I’m just going to keep a running list of different things I notice each time I read them. This time (2/2023), it was how the many names for JEDD Mason echoes the [[notes/apophatic naming|apophatic naming]] of God, a classical theological strategy of the “negative” naming, an effort to call God by every time, thereby acknowledging and preserving God’s transcendence of all of them.</description></item><item><title>The Will to Battle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</guid><description>Reader, I cried like Mycroft Canner. It’s very much the first half of a whole (third quarter of four?), and it needs [[books/perhaps the stars|the last book]] to be complete, but what a feat it is on its own.</description></item><item><title>Perhaps the Stars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</guid><description>I still haven’t found the words to talk about this one. Maybe next year I will. It should be in the Smithsonian, or win the Nobel prize, or something, as one of humanity’s greatest achievements.</description></item><item><title>I Cross-Dressed for the IRL Meetup</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-cross-dressed-for-the-irl-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-cross-dressed-for-the-irl-meetup/</guid><description>I love seeing what Japanese manga does with gender. [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer’s]] essay on anime and manga has some of the historical context for it, but you don’t need a history lesson to enjoy this fun volume. I particularly liked the seamless inclusion of a trans girl alongside the cross-dressing boys, highlighting the differences and similarities among the two, and the lack of moral panic surrounding cross-dressing and gender in general.</description></item><item><title>We the Gathered Heat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:23:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/we-the-gathered-heat/</guid><description>Superb. This is how to do an anthology, where the disparate voices are the point—how do we even define AAPI except as “the other,” non-white? Who is the “we” in question? To whom is that category useful? The poems are sorted into themes of “mourn,” “pronounce,” “fight,” “love,” each as powerful as the last.</description></item><item><title>Hanami</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hanami/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/hanami/</guid><description>The art is beautiful! The story is stressful. I have known various people in my life where, let’s just say their enthusiasm for an idea exceeds their preparation for the reality of it. I’ve suffered the consequences of this (when it’s a parent), tried to mitigate the damage (when it’s a sibling), or offered consolation in the aftermath (when it’s a friend).</description></item><item><title>The Fox Wife</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</guid><description>Not the right choice to follow Nghi Vo’s [[books/the brides of high hill|fox-spirit tale]]. Atmospheric, but I feel talked down to and everything is over-explained. This is why I like sticking to genre for Asian fantasy instead of litfic. DNF @ pg 60. (I did flip through the rest because the hardcover had wide margins for sidenotes, but there were… barely any?</description></item><item><title>Earthlings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earthlings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earthlings/</guid><description>You could put trigger warnings on this book for child abuse, incest, and cannibalism(!!), and still the anguish of being forced to conform to society—“The Factory”—at the expense of all well-being forms the core of the horror. Particularly how women are reduced to wombs like mechanical components.</description></item></channel></rss>