<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 02:13:26 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A system that observes itself can never observe all of itself</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/a-system-that-observes-itself-can-never-observe-all-of-itself/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/a-system-that-observes-itself-can-never-observe-all-of-itself/</guid><description>Spencer Brown’s point is that a system which observes itself can never observe all of itself, and that, therefore, as our telescopes become more powerful the universe must necessarily expand. If I am continuous with the universe, if the physics of my body is the same as the physics of everything else, then I have the same relation to the outside world as to that much of my own body which I can see.</description></item><item><title>Abandon the ancient impulse to control</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abandon-the-ancient-impulse-to-control/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abandon-the-ancient-impulse-to-control/</guid><description>If humanity is to survive into the future and move out of its psychopathy-enabling competition-based models into a collaborative relationship with all of humankind and with its entire ecosystem, that future will necessarily come with an abandonment of our ancient impulse to control. Our impulse to control nations, to control each other, to control life itself.</description></item><item><title>Anatomy of a propaganda blitz</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</guid><description>Copying this straight from [[books/propaganda blitz|Propaganda Blitz]] ([[authors/david edwards|David Edwards]] and [[authors/david cromwell|David Cromwell]]) because it’s immensely helpful to reference.
Propaganda blitzes are fast-moving attacks intended to inflict maximum damage in minimum time. They are:
based on allegations of dramatic new evidence communicated with high emotional intensity and moral outrage apparently supported by an informed corporate media/academic/expert consensus reinforced by damning condemnation of anyone daring even to question the apparent consensus often generated with fortuitous timing characterised by tragicomic moral dissonance Every one of these things, much less the concatenation of all of them, signals red flag, red flag, red flag.</description></item><item><title>Certain ends are best accomplished without the use of conscious means</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/certain-ends-are-best-accomplished-without-the-use-of-conscious-means/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/certain-ends-are-best-accomplished-without-the-use-of-conscious-means/</guid><description>Revisiting this right after re-reading [[books/the lathe of heaven|The Lathe of Heaven]] turns up a lot of resonances, especially re: conscious and subconscious. Instead of Haber’s typical “ends justify the means,” you have the concept of ends without means altogether.
All this can be interpreted as referring to the power of p’u—the capacity of the unconscious mind to do work.</description></item><item><title>Ideology cloaks power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ideology-cloaks-power/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ideology-cloaks-power/</guid><description>Superficially, the means by which power conceals itself is through stories. Its needs narratives — mainly about those who appear powerful — to create political and social dramas that distract us from thinking about deep power. But more fundamentally still, power depends on ideology. Ideology cloaks power – in a real sense, it is power — because it is the source of power’s invisibility.</description></item><item><title>Power exists only so long as we consent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-exists-only-so-long-as-we-consent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-exists-only-so-long-as-we-consent/</guid><description>Power is the structure of the thoughts we think we control, a framework for the ideologies we think we voted for, the values we think we choose to treasure, the horizon of imaginations we think we created. Power exists only so long as we consent to it through our blind obedience.</description></item><item><title>Power is both structural and ideological</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-is-both-structural-and-ideological/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-is-both-structural-and-ideological/</guid><description>Power always has an ideological shape and physical structures. It has both faces. It existed before capitalism, and will exist after it (if capitalism doesn’t kill us first). Human history has consisted of power consolidating and regenerating itself in new form over and over again — like the eponymous hero of the long-running British TV sci-fi series Doctor Who — as different groups have learnt how to harness it, usurp it and put it to self-interested use.</description></item><item><title>The indigenous attribution of agency</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-attribution-of-agency/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-attribution-of-agency/</guid><description>In the indigenous worldview, vegetal life is granted agency and even personhood, and is treated with respect and reverence accordingly.
Each creature is directly responsible for the well-being of many beings at many times, but not for all beings at all times, and these “overlap[ping] connections” sustain a community united not by its identity to itself, but by its complex, mobile, and interrelated differentiations.</description></item><item><title>The indigenous ways of knowing</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-ways-of-knowing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-ways-of-knowing/</guid><description>Native scholar Greg Cajete has written that in indigenous ways of knowing, ==we understand a thing only when we understand it with all four aspects of our being: mind, body, emotion, and spirit.== I came to understand quite sharply when I began my training as a scientist that science privileges only one, possibly two, of those ways of knowing: mind and body.</description></item><item><title>Transparency should be directly proportionate to power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/transparency-should-be-directly-proportionate-to-power/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/transparency-should-be-directly-proportionate-to-power/</guid><description>Western liberal democracy is when corporations and bankers place all blame on the government, the government places all blame on the electorate, and the electorate absorbs all the consequences of the corporations, bankers and government without ever even getting a vote on any of the major decisions those entities make.</description></item><item><title>We are both a wave and a particle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-both-a-wave-and-a-particle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-both-a-wave-and-a-particle/</guid><description>We cannot be separate from the universe any more than an apple can grow separate from an apple tree, or a ripple can exist without a pond.
You and I are as continuous with the physical universe as a wave is continuous with the ocean.</description></item><item><title>Any human power can be changed by human beings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/any-human-power-can-be-changed-by-human-beings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/any-human-power-can-be-changed-by-human-beings/</guid><description> We live in capitalism. Its power seems inescapable. So did the divine right of kings.
Any human power can be resisted and changed by human beings. —[[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula K. Le Guin]], National Book Awards Speech
see also: [[notes/the only thing keeping a crown on a king’s head is narrative|the only thing keeping a crown on a king’s head is narrative]], and [[notes/since it’s all narrative, anything is possible|since it’s all narrative, anything is possible]] see also: [[notes/we are making ourselves up as we go|we are making ourselves up as we go]] future: link to how we stay blind to the story of power</description></item><item><title>Censorship does not make the ideas we disagree with go away</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/censorship-does-not-make-the-ideas-we-disagree-with-go-away/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/censorship-does-not-make-the-ideas-we-disagree-with-go-away/</guid><description>It strikes me how much facing bad things we disagree with is like facing the “bad” emotions we refuse to acknowledge. What we can’t face doesn’t go away—it festers and comes out in much worse ways.
Curiosity is always the answer. Curiosity and addressing the root cause in a meaningful way.</description></item><item><title>Confusion is a crucible</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/confusion-is-a-crucible/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/confusion-is-a-crucible/</guid><description>On the whole radical acceptance front, even confusion—especially confusion—can be enormously helpful in our lives. It points to where the soil needs to be tilled, old ways dug up and new ways cultivated and planted.
The idea that confusion could have therapeutic value is powerful because it takes a human condition that’s generally thought to be negative and suggests that it could actually be a kind of crucible.</description></item><item><title>Create the conditions necessary for change</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/create-the-conditions-necessary-for-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/create-the-conditions-necessary-for-change/</guid><description>I’m toying with the idea of how you nurture the conditions for change, not forcing change itself. (Or insert the desired x here: peace, health, happiness, a better world, etc.)
You don’t stick a seed in hard-packed ground full of thistles and rocks, not provide water or light, and just sit there poking and urging it to grow.</description></item><item><title>Diversity provides stability</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/diversity-provides-stability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/diversity-provides-stability/</guid><description>In nature, diversity provides ecological stability. Monocropping/monoculture leads to a very precarious existence, prone to disease, collapse, and death. But the more diverse the ecosystem, the more robust and healthy it is.
Diversity provides security for ancient forests. Fungi are also dependent on very stable conditions and support other species underground, protecting them from complete collapse and ensuring one species of tree doesn’t dominate.</description></item><item><title>How to beat a manipulator</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-beat-a-manipulator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-beat-a-manipulator/</guid><description>Conveniently, the strategies for dealing with sociopathic manipulators are the exact same, whether it’s a partner, a parent, a pastor, or a plutocrat. 🙃
Get clear on your own will Watch where all the resources are going Watch actions, not their words Don’t try to out manipulate Apply the manipulator’s rules in reverse Here’s the key: simply reverse the pronouns.</description></item><item><title>How to detect manipulation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-detect-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-detect-manipulation/</guid><description>If you feel muddled, scrambled, disoriented, that’s a sign of psychological manipulation/distortion, or often downright abuse. If you feel clarity, even if it’s challenging and uncomfortable, you’re likely on to something true.
Note: to me this is different than feeling uncertain. Uncertainty is an honest and even necessary state, open to inquiry and reflection.</description></item><item><title>Human behavior is too complex to be predictable</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/human-behavior-is-too-complex-to-be-predictable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/human-behavior-is-too-complex-to-be-predictable/</guid><description>When we say that human behavior is unpredictable, we are right, because it is too complex to be predicted, especially by ourselves. Our intense sensation of internal liberty, as Spinoza acutely saw, comes from the fact that the ideas and images which we have of ourselves are much cruder and sketchier than the detailed complexity of what is happening within us.</description></item><item><title>Mute the narrative soundtrack for global politics</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mute-the-narrative-soundtrack-for-global-politics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mute-the-narrative-soundtrack-for-global-politics/</guid><description>Much like mindfulness helps cut through the internal noise, muting the narrative helps cut through the external noise.
Learn the art of perceiving life without the perceptual filter of narrative. Mentally “mute” the narrative soundtrack and watch where all the resources are going, where the weapons are moving to and coming from, who’s being killed and imprisoned etc, to get a clear picture of what’s going on in the world.</description></item><item><title>Nature is emergent and adaptive</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/nature-is-emergent-and-adaptive/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/nature-is-emergent-and-adaptive/</guid><description>From the macro to the micro, life is constantly creating options. Nature is not fixed and immutable, but emergent and adaptive.
Whether you take the planet as a whole, or the ecosystems at a smaller scale—a forest, a pond, a puddle—life is constantly creating options.</description></item><item><title>Nice guy fascism is still fascism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/nice-guy-fascism-is-still-fascism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/nice-guy-fascism-is-still-fascism/</guid><description>Funny how “changing the system from within” produces the same results as not even trying to change it at all.
I call Obama’s particular brand of establishment sycophancy Nice Guy Fascism. It’s just like regular fascism, enabling the brutal dominion of a few depraved and bloodthirsty tyrants, except you get to look like a nice guy while you’re participating in it.</description></item><item><title>Our best defense against stupidity is diversity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-best-defense-against-stupidity-is-diversity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-best-defense-against-stupidity-is-diversity/</guid><description>Appealing as it is want an expert in charge, the last thing we need is a committee of enlightened despots ruling the world. Nice guy tyranny is still tyranny, just like [[notes/nice guy fascism is still fascism|nice guy fascism is still fascism]].
In college, I knew this guy who was always talking about how the world should be ruled by a “panel of experts.</description></item><item><title>Retributive justice does not work</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/retributive-justice-does-not-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/retributive-justice-does-not-work/</guid><description>Behaviorism claims that the only thing powerful enough to spur people into action is the promise of reward or the fear of punishment.
The most widely understood theoretical model of how punishment works comes from behaviorist psychology, which looks at punishment as one kind of conditioning.</description></item><item><title>The most hideous ideologies are the ones we believe without realizing it</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-most-hideous-ideologies-are-the-ones-we-believe-without-realizing-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-most-hideous-ideologies-are-the-ones-we-believe-without-realizing-it/</guid><description>Hey! Here’s a thought! Do not yearn for the authoritarian school of social change! Do not force your ideas on anyone else! 💀
I love people, but a lot of them—maybe most?—yearn for their side to acquire absolute power. They seem to believe in the authoritarian school of social change: the only way to create a better world is for a strong central actor to force it on everybody else.</description></item><item><title>The three stages of gaslighting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-stages-of-gaslighting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-stages-of-gaslighting/</guid><description>Gaslighting is basically a step-by-step psychological process to manipulate and destabilize you. It’s repetitive information force-fed to you that builds up over time, undermining your faith in your own logic, reason, and judgement. It’s super hard to detect because it’s encoded on the subconscious “hard disk,” which isn’t overridden by the conscious “floppy disk.</description></item><item><title>Think in ecosystems, not systems</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/think-in-ecosystems-not-systems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/think-in-ecosystems-not-systems/</guid><description>When we want to change the system, we’re still thinking in terms of systems. That only leads to more authoritarianism, even if the despots briefly agree with us. ([[notes/nice guy fascism is still fascism|Nice guy fascism is still fascism]].) Instead, thinking in ecosystems changes both the question and the process entirely.</description></item><item><title>US exceptionalism is abusive narcissism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/us-exceptionalism-is-abusive-narcissism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/us-exceptionalism-is-abusive-narcissism/</guid><description>Exceptionalism has come to represent superiority in the minds and hearts of Americans, and belief in their economic, military and ideological supremacy is what has motivated successive US governments to shape the world in their “superior” image with no regard for the destruction left in the wake of their exceptional hegemony.</description></item><item><title>Abuse is best recognized by the effect it has on the abused</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-is-best-recognized-by-the-effect-it-has-on-the-abused/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-is-best-recognized-by-the-effect-it-has-on-the-abused/</guid><description>I’m just going to paraphrase and quote this whole bit from [[books/the dominance playbook|The Dominance Playbook]] by [[authors/anton fulmen|Anton Fulmen]], because HOW this this not foundational knowledge:
While there are people out there with malicious intentions, abuse can often happen when there’s no intent to harm.</description></item><item><title>All relationships involve power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-relationships-involve-power/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-relationships-involve-power/</guid><description>Every relationship involves a power exchange, and learning the dynamics of power exchanges can be key to navigating relationships in general—and I’d argue life in general. It gets a hell of a lot easier to spot abuse and control.
Just as all power relationships are relationships, all relationships also involve power.</description></item><item><title>Pleasure can be therapeutic</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pleasure-can-be-therapeutic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pleasure-can-be-therapeutic/</guid><description>In Who Gets to Medicate Me?, Jesse Meadows (@sluggish) interrogates the cultural, puritanical idea that pleasure is destructive.
Psychoactive drugs have direct effects on us, and sometimes those effects feel good, which can be helpful in itself. Puritanical thought and anti-drug propaganda have led us to think of pleasure as destructive, but pleasure can be therapeutic, too.</description></item><item><title>Self-censorship is primarily state censorship</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-censorship-is-primarily-state-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-censorship-is-primarily-state-censorship/</guid><description>State censorship shapes and causes self-censorship, directly and intentionally. To act like it’s primarily a civilian phenomenon is to perpetuate the illusion and miss the point entirely.
Hence, my biggest conclusion, the majority of real censorship is self-censorship, but the majority of self-censorship is intentionally cultivated by an outside power trying to cause that self-censorship to occur.</description></item><item><title>The holistic definition of trauma</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-holistic-definition-of-trauma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-holistic-definition-of-trauma/</guid><description>One of the most accurate definitions of trauma I’ve found is from [[books/chinese medicine for the mind|Chinese Medicine for the Mind]] ([[authors/nina cheng|Nina Cheng]]), which acknowledges that it involves many aspects of emotional, psychological, and physiological conditions.
The defining characteristics:
Overwhelms the nervous system Violates boundaries Disrupts relationality Severs connections Admits feelings of powerlessness Damages the sense of meaning Inhibits the sense of self Disrupts contact with the self Instigates or stimulates collapse/separation of yin and yang (dysregulation) Interestingly, I was just looking up TRE on the cptsdfoundation.</description></item><item><title>The three lies of power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</guid><description>For all the aspiring authoritarians wanting to “do the right thing” and force their good ideas on everyone, [[authors/adam mastroianni|Adam Mastroianni]] outlines the wildly delusional three lies of power:
The good guys will always have more power than the bad guys (ed note: I’d argue, the fact we even believe good guys vs.</description></item><item><title>To dominate is to destroy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/to-dominate-is-to-destroy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/to-dominate-is-to-destroy/</guid><description>The Taoists are saying, then, that seen as a whole the universe is a harmony or symbiosis of patterns which cannot exist without each other. However, when it is looked at section by section we find conflict. The biological world is a mutual eating society in which every species is the prey of another.</description></item><item><title>Tools for thinking about censorship</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/</guid><description>[[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]] has an excellent essay in Reactor Mag (formerly Tor) about the psychological and manipulative tactics of preventing free speech, and thus tools for thinking about free speech: https://reactormag.com/tools-for-thinking-about-censorship/
The whole thing is excellent and worth a read, but I wanted to copy down her five takeaways below:</description></item><item><title>At every level we are a web of interdependencies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/at-every-level-we-are-a-web-of-interdependencies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/at-every-level-we-are-a-web-of-interdependencies/</guid><description>When we talk about being inseparable from the universe, or an animistic view of the world, it’s not uniformity, conformity, or a primordial soup where everything is nothing and nothing is everything. From the macro to the micro, it’s very much a web of interdependencies.</description></item><item><title>Core values</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/core-values/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/core-values/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Emodiversity is a sign of well-being</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emodiversity-is-a-sign-of-well-being/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emodiversity-is-a-sign-of-well-being/</guid><description>Experiencing a broad range of emotions, aka “emodiversity,” is more significant to wellness than happiness. The more we feel, the less we resist feeling, which leads to states of chronic stress and inflammation.
In 2017, positive psychology researchers published findings that suggested emodiversity—which they defined as “the breadth and relative abundance of emotions that individuals experience”—is more significant to wellness than happiness.</description></item><item><title>Emotions are experienced individually and collectively</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotions-are-experienced-individually-and-collectively/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotions-are-experienced-individually-and-collectively/</guid><description>From [[books/tarot for change|Tarot for Change]], [[authors/jessica dore|Jessica Dore]]:
But with emotions, it’s not always clear who “owns” them. I’ve woken up heavy with the boulder of my grandmother’s grief on my chest, breathed deeply while sweating from the fire of my mother’s rage, and I could say, “That’s theirs, not mine,” if I wanted to, but what good would that do?</description></item><item><title>Getting clear on your core values prevents manipulation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/getting-clear-on-your-core-values-prevents-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/getting-clear-on-your-core-values-prevents-manipulation/</guid><description>One of the most valuable things I learned in therapy is how to define my own core values and principles. Get very clear on what drives you, and what you believe in as a set of principles, not ideology, and then use that as your guide to navigate the world.</description></item><item><title>Individuality is inseparable from community</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/individuality-is-inseparable-from-community/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/individuality-is-inseparable-from-community/</guid><description>It shouldn’t surprise me anymore that I keep running across taoism when reading about anarchism or indigenous animism, or running across anarchism/animism when reading about the tao. (But it still does, bc I wanna stay childlike like that ☺️)
The principle is that if everything is allowed to go its own way the harmony of the universe will be established, since every process in the world can “do its own thing” only in relation to all others.</description></item><item><title>Is fear of groupthink another pursuit of purity?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/is-fear-of-groupthink-another-pursuit-of-purity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/is-fear-of-groupthink-another-pursuit-of-purity/</guid><description>Is ridding yourself of all “groupthink” another pursuit of purity? Does the quest for purity only happen within the groupthink/ideology? Are there elements of “groupthink” that are merely the human traits as a communal species? Like censorship, there has never been some ideal state without it, only existing to various healthy or toxic degrees?</description></item><item><title>No organization is organic</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/no-organization-is-organic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/no-organization-is-organic/</guid><description>No organization, in the political and commercial sense of the word, is organic. Organizations, in this sense, are based on the following of linear rules and laws imposed from above—that is, of strung-out, serial, one-thing-at-a-time sequences of words and signs which can never grasp the complexity of nature, although nature is only “complex” in relation to the impossible task of translating it into these linear signs.</description></item><item><title>Nothing is all good or all bad, even black and white thinking</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/nothing-is-all-good-or-all-bad-even-black-and-white-thinking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/nothing-is-all-good-or-all-bad-even-black-and-white-thinking/</guid><description>The idea that nothing is all good or all bad is, paradoxically, is also true for “black-and-white” thinking. Sometimes the straightforward, yes-or-no, this-or-that way is beneficial.
I like how [[authors/jessica dore|Jessica Dore]] puts it in [[books/tarot for change|Tarot for Change]], referring to the ace of swords:</description></item><item><title>Purity and supremacy go hand-in-hand</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/purity-and-supremacy-go-hand-in-hand/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/purity-and-supremacy-go-hand-in-hand/</guid><description>This has been one of my private working theories for years, and the more I see confirms it. Any aspiration towards purity—be it spiritual, moral, ideological, cultural, political, on and on—leads to supremacy. The concept of purity means that impurity exists, so you’re drawing a line between the two, and placing yourself on the side that is elevated, superior, preferred.</description></item><item><title>Self-organizing systems of vast complexity are the way of the world</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-organizing-systems-of-vast-complexity-are-the-way-of-the-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-organizing-systems-of-vast-complexity-are-the-way-of-the-world/</guid><description>We get in trouble when we try to impose external, hierarchical order on ourselves—much like how monoculture fails to thrive, and instead entangled ecosystems are key.
If you think chaos is the only result of a non-hierarchal system, your own body disproves it. Try to get your mind to tell your lungs to breathe, your heart to beat, your stomach to digest, your skin to sweat, your colon to poop.</description></item><item><title>The boundary is a meeting place</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-boundary-is-a-meeting-place/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-boundary-is-a-meeting-place/</guid><description>Instead of only viewing a boundary as a limit, what if we also view it as a meeting place? Therefore the boundary is doubly necessary—to meet people where they are, we must be where we are, not overextending ourselves into places we don’t belong.
This happens internally too.</description></item><item><title>The importance of anger</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-importance-of-anger/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-importance-of-anger/</guid><description>From [[books/tarot for change|Tarot for Change]], [[authors/jessica dore|Jessica Dore]]:
Validating fury in ourselves and others isn’t simply a means to an end of making it go away—==if your goal is to squash it, you’re not really validating anything.== Evolutionary psychology researchers have suggested a thing called ==the recalibration theory of anger==, which suggests that anger evolved to help us increase our social bargaining power and ensure that we demand better deals for ourselves when we’ve either been slighted or might be again.</description></item><item><title>The principle of mutual arising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-principle-of-mutual-arising/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-principle-of-mutual-arising/</guid><description>It is basic to the Taoist view of the world that every thing-event (shì 事 or wù 物) is what it is only in relation to all others. The earth, and every tiniest thing upon it, inevitably “goes-with” the sun, moon, and stars. It needs them just as much as it needs, and consists of, its own elements.</description></item><item><title>The relationship abuse checklist</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-relationship-abuse-checklist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-relationship-abuse-checklist/</guid><description>In the years since I read it, I still haven’t come across a better relationship inventory than [[authors/anton fulmen|Anton Fulmen’s]] in [[books/the dominance playbook|The Dominance Playbook]]. (Leave it to the kink community to nail down the dynamics of abuse.) I reference it all the time, and what I like most is it applies to any interactions between people, not just sexual or romantic relationships.</description></item><item><title>“Complexity” is sometimes noise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/complexity-is-sometimes-noise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/complexity-is-sometimes-noise/</guid><description>Note to self: as someone who always strives to grasp complexity and nuance, recognize when that can be used against me, especially when it comes to global politics. Sometimes sorting the signal from the noise really does mean swiftly cutting through the bullshit, not skillfully dissecting an elaborate tangle.</description></item><item><title>Trust is a very simple thing</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/trust-is-a-very-simple-thing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:01:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/trust-is-a-very-simple-thing/</guid><description>I often hear the line now, “when someone shows you who they are, believe them.” It’s come up in therapy, it’s shared online a lot. I hope that means it’s becoming common knowledge, because it often really is that simple: trust is simple and usually very obvious.</description></item><item><title>We are making ourselves up as we go</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-making-ourselves-up-as-we-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:01:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-making-ourselves-up-as-we-go/</guid><description>The current cultural orthodoxy, often formulated or short-handed as “stay in your lane,” postulates that a writer ought to remain centered in their own community, to write from their own and their community’s experience: to stay home. But Ursula argued that those places, those points of origin, home and community, are themselves acts of the creative imagination.</description></item><item><title>All of us are embedded in our own safe “reality”</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-of-us-are-embedded-in-our-own-safe-reality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-of-us-are-embedded-in-our-own-safe-reality/</guid><description>All of us are embedded in our own safe “reality,” shaping what we see and know in ways of which we are completely unaware.
Many circumstances conspire to extinguish scientific discoveries, especially those that cause discomfort about our culture’s sacred norms. As a species, we cling to the familiar, comforting conformities of the mainstream.</description></item><item><title>An amateur is one who loves</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/an-amateur-is-one-who-loves/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/an-amateur-is-one-who-loves/</guid><description>A proposition: what if amateur could outrank professional in terms of our respect? We tend to use amateur pejoratively, to indicate the lack of skill, but the word in French means lover. If you think about it this way:
Amateur: one who loves
Professional: one who is financially obligated</description></item><item><title>Cooperation is a form of pleasure and play</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cooperation-is-a-form-of-pleasure-and-play/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cooperation-is-a-form-of-pleasure-and-play/</guid><description>An alternative school of Darwinism emerged in Russia emphasizing cooperation, not competition, as the driver of evolutionary change—see [[books/mutual aid|Mutual Aid]] by [[authors/pyotr kropotkin|Pyotr Kropotkin]]. It’s not just about cooperation as a means to an end though—Kropotkin posits that cooperation is a form of pleasure and social play in itself.</description></item><item><title>Could kinesiology explain the phenomenon of faith healing?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/could-kinesiology-explain-the-phenomenon-of-faith-healing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/could-kinesiology-explain-the-phenomenon-of-faith-healing/</guid><description>Can kinesiology—specifically the therapeutic practices of body talk, acupressure, emotional stress release, etc.—explain what’s occurring in many instances of faith healing?
In the Pentecostal tradition that I grew up in (and escaped from), faith healing often happens in a highly charged environment, with lots of prayer (meditation), and emotional catharsis.</description></item><item><title>Everything old is new again</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/everything-old-is-new-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/everything-old-is-new-again/</guid><description> [[notes/could kinesiology explain the phenomenon of faith healing|could kinesiology explain the phenomenon of faith healing?]] [[notes/modern science often repackages medieval categories|modern science often repackages medieval categories]] [[notes/the concept of lila and cosmic playfulness|the concept of lila and cosmic playfulness]] [[notes/ecclesiastes as a protest manifesto|ecclesiastes as a protest manifesto]]</description></item><item><title>Fear destroys curiosity and playfulness</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fear-destroys-curiosity-and-playfulness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fear-destroys-curiosity-and-playfulness/</guid><description>You cannot be curious and playful when you’re afraid. Any healthy individual and healthy society must be able to safely play and learn.
Fear destroys curiosity and playfulness. In order to have a healthy society we must raise children who can safely play and learn.</description></item><item><title>Fear is a natural reaction to moving closer to the truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fear-is-a-natural-reaction-to-moving-closer-to-the-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fear-is-a-natural-reaction-to-moving-closer-to-the-truth/</guid><description>It’s amazing how much we fear fear, when there is no more universal experience. If we can get that little bit of space between it, allow the fear to exist and listen to it, underneath that is something very soft and tender and honest, the core of what it means to be alive.</description></item><item><title>Physicists are the poets of the scientific world</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/physicists-are-the-poets-of-the-scientific-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/physicists-are-the-poets-of-the-scientific-world/</guid><description>Haha @ Graeber saying physicists are basically the poets, aka the anti-fundamentalists, of the scientific world, far more receptive to paradigm-shifting ideas. Ditto mathematicians? (*cough* [[authors/douglas hofstadter|Hofstadter]], anyone?)
Curiously, it’s largely physicists who have proved receptive to such ideas. (Also mathematicians— perhaps unsurprisingly, since Peirce and Whitehead themselves both began their careers as mathematicians.</description></item><item><title>The art of not reading is an important one</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-art-of-not-reading-is-an-important-one/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-art-of-not-reading-is-an-important-one/</guid><description>Ignoring what makes a great commotion is a good rule in more ways than one. See, Schopenhauer agrees!
The art of not reading is a very important one. It consists in not taking an interest in whatever may be engaging the attention of the general public at any particular time.</description></item><item><title>The concept of lila and cosmic playfulness</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-concept-of-lila-and-cosmic-playfulness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-concept-of-lila-and-cosmic-playfulness/</guid><description>In Hinduism, the concept of lila is that all of life—indeed, the cosmos—is an expression of divine, cosmic playfulness.
Lila (or leela) can be loosely translated as “divine play”. The concept of lila asserts that creation, instead of being an objective for achieving any purpose, is rather an outcome of the playful nature of the divine.</description></item><item><title>The human mind mistakes its opinions for truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-human-mind-mistakes-its-opinions-for-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-human-mind-mistakes-its-opinions-for-truth/</guid><description>I think of it like this: we’re always missing data. Our equations can never be perfect because, much like the cloud of probability in quantum physics, we can never have all the data. The people I trust most are the ones who know this, and act accordingly.</description></item><item><title>Thinking about symbiosis is itself a symbiotic phenomenon</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-about-symbiosis-is-itself-a-symbiotic-phenomenon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-about-symbiosis-is-itself-a-symbiotic-phenomenon/</guid><description>Just the complex process of thought—oxygen enters the bloodstream to be metabolized by mitochondria, etc.—means that thinking is itself a symbiotic event. (!!!)
Our brains themselves and the thought required to read this sentence, if my radical symbiogenesis theory is correct, were made possible by the protein microtubules that first evolved in bacteria.</description></item><item><title>We discount censorship when its motives are “good”</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-discount-censorship-when-its-motives-are-good/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-discount-censorship-when-its-motives-are-good/</guid><description>It doesn’t take much to persuade us that censorship is good, when it aligns with what we fear or who we want to protect from harm.
We tend instinctively to call things censorship primarily when we perceive those involved to have bad intentions. But we tend to excuse or discount censorious actions when we perceive the motives to be good.</description></item><item><title>We exist only in relationship to others</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-exist-only-in-relationship-to-others/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-exist-only-in-relationship-to-others/</guid><description>We cannot exist apart from each other. Everything is relative in the sense that my existence is not separate from yours.
We exist only in relationship to others. Our actions can be described only in their context. My existing requires you, and so forth. We are not separate, we define each other.</description></item><item><title>“Modern” science often repackages medieval categories</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/modern-science-often-repackages-medieval-categories/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/modern-science-often-repackages-medieval-categories/</guid><description>There is a longstanding tradition of borrowing older scientific or medical categories, merely updating the terminology but keeping the same (invalid) assertions.
When the nineteenth-century medicolegal term “homosexuality” was brought into official Catholic speech, it replaced the eleventh-century theological term “sodomy.” “Homosexuality” took the place of “sodomy” in the way a substitute teacher takes over a class.</description></item><item><title>All fiction is fanfiction</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-fiction-is-fanfiction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-fiction-is-fanfiction/</guid><description>You knooooow I will get on this soapbox all day long. All fiction is fanfiction. All art is fan art.
Long before we had the (very super recent modern) idea that a book = a discrete, permanent object, we had collective folk texts that spread precisely because people remixed and remade them.</description></item><item><title>All transmission is recreation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-transmission-is-recreation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-transmission-is-recreation/</guid><description>Heyo, just like copyright, the notion of faithful reproduction is a very modern notion. And I’m gonna add Western industrialized notion—surely many if not all indigenous cultures still see the transmission of stories as re-creation.
A storyteller is a spinner of yarns, and the internet’s founding metaphor is of a web.</description></item><item><title>Apophatic naming</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/apophatic-naming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/apophatic-naming/</guid><description>Apophatic naming, or negative naming, is the attempt to call a thing by so many names that its essential nature transcends all of them. It’s a practice “as old as philosophy itself,”1 and a central element of mysticism and early Christian thought.
I like the turn of phrase in this one: the Mystical Languages of Unsaying.</description></item><item><title>Be like a cat and let go of yourself</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/be-like-a-cat-and-let-go-of-yourself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/be-like-a-cat-and-let-go-of-yourself/</guid><description>The more relaxed you are, the more flexible you are, the more lightly you land.
When a cat falls out of a tree, it lets go of itself. The cat becomes completely relaxed, and lands lightly on the ground. But if a cat were about to fall out of a tree and suddenly make up its mind that it didn’t want to fall, it would become tense and rigid, and would be just a bag of broken bones upon landing.</description></item><item><title>Bisexuality might be erotic plasticity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bisexuality-might-be-erotic-plasticity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bisexuality-might-be-erotic-plasticity/</guid><description>More women tend to be bisexual, or fluid with how they label their sexuality. Some of the conflict between saying sexuality is a choice might be this erotic plasticity.
In fact, women in general are far more likely than men to report being bisexual. Tellingly, they’re also more likely to change their self-identification as straight or gay during their adult lives.</description></item><item><title>Both memes and needlework are collective folk texts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/both-memes-and-needlework-are-collective-folk-texts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/both-memes-and-needlework-are-collective-folk-texts/</guid><description>“Teks,” the root of “technology,” meant a treatise on an art, craft, or grammar, before the meaning transferred to mechanical arts and then to digital tech. The lineage back to arts and crafts is a compelling link between “text” and “textile,” where collective folk texts are remixed and remade endlessly.</description></item><item><title>Bottom-up processors are associative thinkers</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bottom-up-processors-are-associative-thinkers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bottom-up-processors-are-associative-thinkers/</guid><description>Top-down thinkers have a linear thought process, a deductive approach, a “concept-before-the-details” type brain.
Bottom-up thinkers have an associative thought process, an inductive approach, a “details-before-the-concept” type brain.
[[notes/autism|Autistic people]] tend to belong overwhelmingly to the second category.1
Instead of fitting new information into a preexisting box, contextualizing based on prior knowledge–or even constrained by prior knowledge–the autistic mind takes in a bombardment of details and sorts it into a comprehensible picture.</description></item><item><title>Censorship is often plural, private, and popular</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/real-censorship-is-often-plural-private-and-popular/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/real-censorship-is-often-plural-private-and-popular/</guid><description>When we only have one template for what censorship looks like—state-driven, authoritarian, Orwellian—we fail to see the myriad kinds of censorship that don’t resemble it.
Alarm bells go off the instant people see censorship which resembles Orwell, which creates a corresponding weakness or failure to observe when censorship begins that does not resemble Orwell.</description></item><item><title>Disgust is a culture-bound syndrome</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/disgust-is-a-culture-bound-syndrome/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/disgust-is-a-culture-bound-syndrome/</guid><description>Symbolic disgust is subjective, not objective, and is a [[notes/pms and other pathologies are culture-bound syndromes|culture-bound syndrome]].
What induces the symbolic disgust response is defined by prevailing cultural forces. That’s to say, for the most part we’ve learned to morally loathe whatever it is that we’ve come to do; this information isn’t genetically inborn but socially acquired.</description></item><item><title>Everything is fiction</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/everything-is-fiction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/everything-is-fiction/</guid><description>Lest we get so attached to our stories we can’t surrender them, remember: what we experience and the way we describe it is fiction. We are constantly editing, tweaking, cutting, rewriting our vast, chaotic narrative.
And I mean that—everything is fiction. When you tell yourself the story of your life, the story of your day, you edit and rewrite and weave a narrative out of a collection of random experiences and events.</description></item><item><title>Fanfiction is literature</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fanfiction-is-literature/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fanfiction-is-literature/</guid><description>Since Tumblr posts are disappearing faster than the Amazon rainforest, I want to archive this for posterity:
I think fanfiction is literature and literature, for the most part, is fanfiction, and that anyone that dismisses it simply on the grounds that it’s derivative knows fuck-all about literature and needs to get the hell off my lawn.</description></item><item><title>Forests disprove survival of the fittest</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/forests-disprove-survival-of-the-fittest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/forests-disprove-survival-of-the-fittest/</guid><description>In a forest, well-being depends on community and diversity. It’s not a race to the top for dominance, but a web of interdependencies, that depends on even the supposedly “weakest” trees for survival.
It’s not survival of the fittest—their well-being depends on community. When supposedly feeble trees disappear, the others lose as well.</description></item><item><title>Karass</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/karass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/karass/</guid><description>A group of people linked in a cosmically significant manner, even when superficial linkages are not evident.
Coined by [[authors/kurt vonnegut|Kurt Vonnegut]] in 1963, as a Bokononist term in the novel [[books/cats cradle|Cat’s Cradle]]. Other karass-related terms:
duprass – a karass of only two people, who almost always die within a week of each other.</description></item><item><title>Kink is the new vanilla</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/kink-is-the-new-vanilla/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/kink-is-the-new-vanilla/</guid><description>It’s funny, I’ve seen scattered comments lately, mostly on the r/romancelandia and r/ao3 subreddits, of people saying they prefer vanilla/chaste/closed door stories now because kink is basically the norm, so therefore predictable and boring.
Just like any sex scene, kink alone does not make it interesting or good—I’ve read absolutely dire representations of kink.</description></item><item><title>Language is a network</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/language-is-a-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/language-is-a-network/</guid><description>We are not tending language like a garden—its order is emerging from the chaos in a natural way.
When we thought of language like a book, we thought of it as an unruly mess of words that had to be kept in order, like a Victorian gardener constantly retrimming the hedges into spirals and globes.</description></item><item><title>Mosaic novel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mosaic-novel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mosaic-novel/</guid><description>[[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]], in the foreward for [[books/china mountain zhang|China Mountain Zhang]], discusses the difference between books of interconnected short stories vs. mosaic novels.
A normal novel tells a story by going straightforwardly at it, maybe with different points of view, maybe braided, but clearly going down one road of story.</description></item><item><title>Naturalistic fallacy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/naturalistic-fallacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/naturalistic-fallacy/</guid><description>Naturalistic fallacy is the assumption that whatever is natural is good, and vice versa. It’s far too easily based on cherry-picking and nonsense, and is not a solid foundation for ethics.
In [[books/perv|Perv]], [[authors/jesse bering|Jesse Bering]] points out that we jump too quickly to the naturalistic fallacy in pursuit of LGBTQ rights:</description></item><item><title>Our sense of the erotic is more plastic than we think</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-sense-of-the-erotic-is-more-plastic-than-we-think/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-sense-of-the-erotic-is-more-plastic-than-we-think/</guid><description>How fluid is our sense of the erotic? Like neurological plasticity, probably a lot more fluid than we think.
Whether it involves livestock or people, this sexual-imprinting process (in which a highly circumscribed set of erotic targets is stamped early into the individual’s brain) appears to be a decidedly male characteristic.</description></item><item><title>Play could be the basis of physical reality</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-could-be-the-basis-of-physical-reality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-could-be-the-basis-of-physical-reality/</guid><description>The principle of play repeats so often in nature, it’s worth asking whether it’s the basis of physical reality. That’s not as wild an assertion as it seems, and even more plausible and less inconsistent than our image of a mindless robotic universe.
I don’t deny that what I’ve presented so far is a savage simplification of very complicated issues.</description></item><item><title>Play is not an anomaly</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-is-not-an-anomaly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-is-not-an-anomaly/</guid><description>What if we treated play as our starting point? Not as an anomaly, but a principle to every self-organizing system?
What would happen if we proceeded from the reverse perspective and agreed to treat play not as some peculiar anomaly, but as our starting point, a principle already present not just in lobsters and indeed all living creatures, but also on every level where we find what physicists, chemists, and biologists refer to as “self-organizing systems”?</description></item><item><title>PMS and other pathologies are culture-bound syndromes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pms-and-other-pathologies-are-culture-bound-syndromes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pms-and-other-pathologies-are-culture-bound-syndromes/</guid><description>Look, I’m gonna side eye any opinion on menstruation authored by a man, but the essay Is PMS Real? by Frank Bures offers a fascinating glimpse at culture-bound syndromes:1
The phenomenon of so-called culture-bound syndromes, which more recently have come to be known as “cultural syndromes,” or sometimes, “cultural idioms of distress.</description></item><item><title>Puzzle-book worldbuilding</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/puzzle-book-worldbuilding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/puzzle-book-worldbuilding/</guid><description>What I call puzzle-book worldbuilding is one of my favorite things to read. It’s maddening, it’s challenging. It’s delightful. It’s a heady rush of satisfaction when the pieces start to click. It’s completely different from worldbuilding that stays dense, illogical, and nonsensical. A lazy author not even bothering to build a puzzle is detectable at first glance from the author you won’t be able to understand until the second read.</description></item><item><title>Social media is the third place</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/social-media-is-the-third-place/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/social-media-is-the-third-place/</guid><description>Thinking about public and semipublic posting on social media sites as [[notes/the necessity of third places|third places]] can provide a way of thinking about [[notes/enshittification|the responsibility of a platform to its residents]]: your local bartenders or baristas don’t generally interfere with your conversations, but they do reserve the right to kick people out if they’re disturbing other patrons, and this makes the space better as a whole.</description></item><item><title>The external world is as much you as your own body</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-external-world-is-as-much-you-as-your-own-body/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-external-world-is-as-much-you-as-your-own-body/</guid><description>Any good scientist knows that what you call the external world is as much you as your own body. Your skin doesn’t actually separate you from the world—it’s a bridge through which the world flows into you, and you flow into the world. You’re just like a whirlpool.</description></item><item><title>The limits of the individual are porous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-limits-of-the-individual-are-porous/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-limits-of-the-individual-are-porous/</guid><description>As a fan of pro cycling, one of the most amazing things is watching the peloton guide along the tarmac at breathtaking speeds, a living organism that is unquestionably more than the sum of its parts.1
Its cohesion is so real that the limits of the individual are porous.</description></item><item><title>The Untamed recap: meme version pt. 1</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-i/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-i/</guid><description>Episode recap of The Untamed, via memes and shitposts only.1 100% accurate content guaranteed 💀
[ part 1, [[notes/cql meme post ii|part 2]], [[notes/cql meme post iii|part 3]], [[notes/cql meme post iv|part 4]], [[notes/cql meme post v|part 5]] ]
![[images/cql-meme-0.jpg]]
Episode 1 ![[images/cql-meme-1-1.jpg]]
![[images/cql-meme-1-2.jpg]]</description></item><item><title>The Untamed recap: meme version pt. 2</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-ii/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-ii/</guid><description>Episodes 11–20, slaughter tortoises → basically just lots of slaughter (Angst City!!)
[ [[notes/cql meme post i|part 1]], part 2, [[notes/cql meme post iii|part 3]], [[notes/cql meme post iv|part 4]], [[notes/cql meme post v|part 5]] ]
![[images/cql-meme-0-5.jpg]]
Episode 11 ![[images/cql-meme-11-1.jpg]]
![[images/cql-meme-11-2.jpg]]
![[images/cql-meme-11-8.jpg]]
![[images/cql-meme-11-9.jpg]]
![[images/cql-meme-11-10.jpg]]</description></item><item><title>The Untamed recap: meme version pt. 3</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-iii/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-iii/</guid><description>Episodes 21–30, Sunshot campaign → setting up camp in the Burial Mounds. i.e. we’re piiiining like a whole pine tree forest full of sap up in here
[ [[notes/cql meme post i|part 1]], [[notes/cql meme post ii|part 2]], part 3, [[notes/cql meme post iv|part 4]], [[notes/cql meme post v|part 5]] ]</description></item><item><title>The Untamed recap: meme version pt. 4</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-iv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-iv/</guid><description>Episodes 31–40, FLASHBACK ENDS! Major Character Deaths (plural) → Major Character Resurrection (singular); 16 years later, murder mystery road trip
[ [[notes/cql meme post i|part 1]], [[notes/cql meme post ii|part 2]], [[notes/cql meme post iii|part 3]], part 4, [[notes/cql meme post v|part 5]] ]
![[images/cql-meme-0-3.jpg]]</description></item><item><title>The Untamed recap: meme version pt. 5</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-v/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cql-meme-post-v/</guid><description>Episodes 41–50 aka the reckoning aka THE END (in which censorship tries to pretend they don’t bone down and get married but THEY DO)
[ [[notes/cql meme post i|part 1]], [[notes/cql meme post ii|part 2]], [[notes/cql meme post iii|part 3]], [[notes/cql meme post iv|part 4]], part 5 ]</description></item><item><title>Thinking people are stupid is the gateway drug to worse ideas</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-people-are-stupid-is-the-gateway-drug-to-worse-ideas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-people-are-stupid-is-the-gateway-drug-to-worse-ideas/</guid><description>I’m highly allergic to the idea that other people are fundamentally stupid. It’s one small, flimsy step away from dehumanizing people completely, and once anyone is dehumanized, that leads to a lot of worse ideas.
If we can go from “only kings and dukes could possibly become less stupid” to “anybody can become less stupid,” maybe we can make it all the way to “people aren’t fundamentally stupid to begin with.</description></item><item><title>We are collaborative compound organisms</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-collaborative-compound-organisms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-collaborative-compound-organisms/</guid><description>Humans are not solitary beings, but collaborative compound organisms, coordinating the world together.
Yes, we are beginning to encounter ourselves—not always comfortably or pleasantly—as multi-species beings already partaking in timescales that are fabulously more complex than the onwards driving version of history many of us still imagine ourselves to inhabit.</description></item><item><title>We are doing exactly what the fish are doing</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-doing-exactly-what-the-fish-are-doing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-doing-exactly-what-the-fish-are-doing/</guid><description>[[authors/david graeber|David Graeber]] says that when he taught at Yale, he would assign a reading of the following Taoist story, offering an automatic “A” to any student who could tell him why the last line made sense. (None ever succeeded.)
Zhuangzi and Huizi were strolling on a bridge over the River Hao, when the former observed, “See how the minnows dart between the rocks!</description></item><item><title>Conservation of novelty</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/conservation-of-novelty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/conservation-of-novelty/</guid><description>We are the inheritors of all the complexity that proceeded us.
Each stage of advancement into novelty, into complexity, into concrescence, has proceeded more quickly than the phase which preceded it. The universe is in a state of asymptotic acceleration of some sort.</description></item><item><title>The righting reflex</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-righting-reflex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:09:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-righting-reflex/</guid><description>From [[books/tarot for change|Tarot for Change]], [[authors/jessica dore|Jessica Dore]]:
The primary task in all healing relationships—such as that between a therapist and client—is to listen deeply. Conversely, traumatic relationships are ones in which people consistently deny, overlook, and avoid each other’s truths.
I first learned of exquisite empathy as a graduate student seeking ways to cope with the overwhelming grief and anguish I was bearing witness to as an intern at a community mental health agency in an under-resourced community.</description></item><item><title>Moral dumbfounding is not moral reasoning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-dumbfounding-is-not-moral-reasoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-dumbfounding-is-not-moral-reasoning/</guid><description>Moral judgement and moral reasoning are basically two different processes. People tend to have a knee-jerk reaction for what’s good or bad, often based more on cultural conditioning, prejudice, or gut feelings than any reasonable morality or ethics. When asked to elaborate, you get “moral dumbfounding,” moral reasoning made up ex-post facto to justify moral judgement.</description></item><item><title>Moral panics and mass hysteria</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-panics-and-mass-hysteria/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/moral-panics-and-mass-hysteria/</guid><description>Imma start collecting moral panics from the past so our current ones sound less wild. Moral of the story: humans will moral panic over just about anything 💀
The pig-man hunts of New Haven Courtesy of [[authors/jesse bering|Jesse Bering]] in his book [[books/perv|Perv]]:
You’ve heard of the witch hunts in Salem, but I’m guessing you’re not as familiar with the pig-man hunts of New Haven.</description></item><item><title>The science of pro cycling race numbers</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pro-cycling-race-numbers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/pro-cycling-race-numbers/</guid><description>Here I am, once again trying to explain the arcane logic of race numbers, and the internet is surprisingly unhelpful, offering up only one or two insufficient links before trying to help me print my own race number, pin my own race number, or sign up for triathlons.</description></item><item><title>Dull elves</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/dull-elves/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:13:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/dull-elves/</guid><description>I’m going to reference this sooner or later, so I want the full citation. In a letter to her sister Cassandra, circa the publication of [[books/pride and prejudice|Pride and Prejudice]], [[authors/jane austen|Jane Austen]] said the following about printer’s errors she’d found in the text:
“There are a few Typical errors—&amp;amp; a ‘said he’ or a ‘said she’ would sometimes make the Dialogue more immediately clear.</description></item><item><title>On firearms, trust and historical accuracy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/on-firearms-trust-and-historical-accuracy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/on-firearms-trust-and-historical-accuracy/</guid><description>There’s a scene in [[books/a governess’s guide to passion and peril|A Governess&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Passion and Peril]] that has stuck in my mind, and I want to write through it to figure out why it’s niggling at me. (Spoilers abound, beware.)
Set-up: near the end of the book, Jane and Adrian, among others, are confronting Payne, the murderer, who is about to murder another of their party by making him appear to commit suicide (forced at gunpoint to jump out a window).</description></item><item><title>How do draw good</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-do-draw-good/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 22:15:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-do-draw-good/</guid><description>Basically the only art advice you need, by (I think) @bontext on tumblr:
![[images/howdodrawgood.jpg]]
How do write good I’ve modified it for writing as follows:
fill 14 note book bad stuff is good stuff bc you made stuff do you like sparkle???? write sparkle write what make your heart do the smiley emote member to drink lotsa aqua or else bad time d not stress friend all is well your work is hot like potato crisps don’t let anyone piss on your good mood amigo if they do eat them</description></item><item><title>Enshittification</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/enshittification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/enshittification/</guid><description>Cory Doctorow on the enshittification of TikTok:
Here is how platforms die: first, they are good to their users; then they abuse their users to make things better for their business customers; finally, they abuse those business customers to claw back all the value for themselves.</description></item><item><title>Phatic phrases</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/phatic-phrases/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:44:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/phatic-phrases/</guid><description>Phatic phrases are the phrases that follow a well-worn script, and as long as you don’t miss the beat, the words themselves don’t matter.
For example:
Hi!
What’s up?
Fine, how are you?
Not much.
Each person is responding to questions that weren’t asked, but the script is so familiar and the beats so ingrained that nobody notices.</description></item><item><title>The necessity of third places</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-necessity-of-third-places/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:44:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-necessity-of-third-places/</guid><description>Ray Oldenberg coined the term “third place” in 1989 to describe our social centers. In the OG definition, the first place is home, the second place is work. The third place is a shared place to socialize that’s neither home nor work, distinguished by conversation and [[notes/play gives meaning to life|playfulness]], familiar faces but no formal membership, freedom to come and go as you please, home away from home.</description></item><item><title>Bibliotropic</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bibliotropic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:23:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/bibliotropic/</guid><description>To leans towards a book as flowers leans toward the sun.
I’m guessing [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]] didn’t coin this one so much as borrow it, but most of the top results in google reference [[books/among others|her use of it]], or at least the SFF community.</description></item><item><title>We are the process of the universe</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-the-process-of-the-universe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-the-process-of-the-universe/</guid><description>We are not the result of evolution, or the big bang, or a consequence of the physical universe, we are the process of it. That we are separate is an illusion we’ve invented ourselves.
If there was a big bang at the beginning of time, you are not something that is the result of that explosion at the end of the process.</description></item><item><title>We are wiggles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-wiggles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-wiggles/</guid><description>The physical world is wiggly as all get-out! We are the ones who try to box things in with our concrete categories and straight lines.
See, the physical world is wiggly. Clouds, mountains, trees, people—everything is wiggly. It’s only when human beings get working on things that they build buildings in straight lines and try to make the world unwiggly.</description></item><item><title>What’s the point if we can’t have fun?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/whats-the-point-if-we-cant-have-fun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/whats-the-point-if-we-cant-have-fun/</guid><description>In the essay What’s the point if we can’t have fun?, [[authors/david graeber|David Graeber]] argues that we’re foolish for focusing only on rational explanations and economic terms in animal behavior, and for undervaluing play.
Why do animals play? Well, why shouldn’t they? The real question is: Why does the existence of action carried out for the sheer pleasure of acting, the exertion of powers for the sheer pleasure of exerting them, strike us as mysterious?</description></item><item><title>Who is more deserving</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/who-is-more-deserving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/who-is-more-deserving/</guid><description>As if deserving meant anything. As if one could earn beauty, or life!
([[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula K. Le Guin]], [[books/the dispossessed|The Dispossessed]])
Over on Sluggish, Jesse Meadows is talking about people getting ruffled “ because everyone online is autistic now.” It’s just the latest hand-wringing over [[notes/autism|autism]] as an internet trend (or insert any “-ism as an internet trend”), and the key argument is that the right people aren’t getting what they deserve, while “fakers” are taking resources away.</description></item><item><title>The earth grows people</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-earth-grows-people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-earth-grows-people/</guid><description>The earth grows people the way an apple grows apple trees. The earth is not infested with living organisms—we are are symptomatic of the earth, which is symptomatic of the universe.
If there is any such thing as intelligence or love or beauty, you find it in other people.</description></item><item><title>Vorfreude</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vorfreude/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vorfreude/</guid><description>The German word vorfruede has no English equivalent. It comes from the words vor (“before”) and Freude (“joy”) and means something along the lines of “joyful anticipation.”
Often “vorfreude” is characterized as childish anticipation. It also includes the tension, impatience, and curiosity of anticipating an event.</description></item><item><title>Vocateur</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vocateur/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/vocateur/</guid><description>Ha @ [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]] describing herself as a vocateur reader on the Ex Urbe Ad Astra podcast! Totally fits because as much as I love her as an author ([[books/lent|Lent]]! [[books/among others|Among Others]]!), I always say Jo is my favorite reader.
I was trying to find out if [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]] coined vocateur in the [[series/terra ignota|Terra Ignota]] series, and the results of just a cursory google search all give her credit for the term.</description></item><item><title>The internet is a rhizome</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-internet-is-a-rhizome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-internet-is-a-rhizome/</guid><description>The internet is not a textbook, or even a wiki, or any kind of single, linear, finite entity. The internet is a rhizome.
When we thought of language as a book, we thought of it as linear and finite. A book can only have so many pages, so you have to decide what to keep in, what to fence out, and how to order what remains.</description></item><item><title>The theology of capitalism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/theology-of-capitalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/theology-of-capitalism/</guid><description>We have mostly forgotten to be surprised that a street preacher’s followers discovered, several hundred years after his death, how to be a regimented multinational corporate enterprise. ([[books/pagans|Pagans]], [[authors/james o&amp;rsquo;donnell|James J. O’Donnell]])
In [[books/all about love|All About Love]], [[authors/bell hooks|bell hooks]] (via Erich Fromm) says the principle underlying capitalistic society and the principle of love are incompatible.</description></item><item><title>The trust checklist</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-trust-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-trust-checklist/</guid><description>Trust is more of a cognitive assessment than an emotion. Distrust is when you feel “what is important to me is not safe with this person.” That lack of safety makes authenticity and vulnerability difficult for fear of betrayal (rightly so!).
In [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]], [[authors/brené brown|Brené Brown]] lists seven specific trustworthy behaviors:</description></item><item><title>The Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-carrier-bag-theory-of-fiction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-carrier-bag-theory-of-fiction/</guid><description>by [[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula K. Le Guin]]
Ed. note: just me copying and annotating this text in full, it’s that brilliant.
In the temperate and tropical regions where it appears that hominids evolved into human beings, the principal food of the species was vegetable.</description></item><item><title>The curse of Latin-y grammar</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-curse-of-latin-y-grammar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-curse-of-latin-y-grammar/</guid><description>The Latin-worshipping tradition is responsible for the grammar elitism of infinitive splitting, proposition ending, and the singular “they.”
Robert Lowth, who wrote a widely used English grammar in 1792, passed an aesthetic judgment on the sentence-ending preposition (it wasn’t Latin-y enough), and later grammarians elevated this preference to a full-on ban.</description></item><item><title>Taoism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/taoism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/taoism/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rhizomatic thinking is non-hierarchal and relational</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/rhizomatic-thinking-is-non-hierarchal-and-relational/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/rhizomatic-thinking-is-non-hierarchal-and-relational/</guid><description>The rhizome was adopted as a philosophical concept to describe a process of existence and growth with no clear hierarchy or single central point of origin. It doesn’t start from anywhere or end anywhere; it grows from everywhere, can reproduce from any node, and has no center, which makes it difficult to uproot or destroy.</description></item><item><title>Science fiction futures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/science-fiction-futures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/science-fiction-futures/</guid><description>I would call our work to change the world “science fictional behavior”—being concerned with the way our actions and beliefs now, today, will shape the future, tomorrow, the next generations.
Science fiction is simply a way to practice the future together. I suspect that is what many of you are up to, practicing futures together, practicing justice together, living into new stories.</description></item><item><title>Play gives meaning to life</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-gives-meaning-to-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/play-gives-meaning-to-life/</guid><description>Almost all mammals play, and many other animals can’t resist. It’s the most intelligent animals that exhibit the most playful behavior. Domesticated animals play their whole lives.
Play gives meaning to life, wrote the Dutch historian Johan Huizinga back in 1938. He christened us homo ludens—‘playing man.</description></item><item><title>Playfulness vs. epistemic traps</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/playfulness-vs-epistemic-traps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/playfulness-vs-epistemic-traps/</guid><description>A pre-print by C. Thi Nguyen, full download here.</description></item><item><title>Multiple intelligence theory</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/multiple-intelligence-theory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/multiple-intelligence-theory/</guid><description>Howard Gardner first outlined his theory in his 1983 book Frames of Mind, where he suggested that all people have different kinds of intelligence.
He proposed that there are eight intelligences, and has suggested the possible addition of a ninth known as “existentialist intelligence.”
Linguistic intelligence—a deep-rooted understanding and nuanced use of language, a proficiency that goes beyond fluency.</description></item><item><title>Mitfreude</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mitfreude/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mitfreude/</guid><description>Mitfreude is feeling joy in another’s joy. The opposite of schadenfreude, where pleasure is derived from another’s misfortune.
Coined by Nietzsche in 1878,1 it originates in the German language, mit (“with”) + Freude (“joy”).
First encountered in [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]]’s essay on anime and manga, A Mitfreude of Anime and Manga’s Relationship with Anglophone Science Fiction), where she defines it as the joy of sharing joy with friends.</description></item><item><title>Memes and social movements</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/memes-and-social-movements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/memes-and-social-movements/</guid><description>[[authors/gretchen mcculloch|Gretchen McCulloch]], [[books/because internet|Because Internet]]:
“Why do games like FarmVille and Pokémon Go periodically sweep social media? In a previous decade, games like gin rummy and pool, which are conducive to lively conversation, were characteristic of third places. Oldenburg also points out how ==third places have been essential to forming the kinds of large, loose-knit social groups that are the core of new social movements==, such as the agora in ancient Greek democracy, taverns around the American Revolution, and coffeeshops during the Age of Enlightenment, which parallels how Twitter was used for the Arab Spring or the Black Lives Matter protests.</description></item><item><title>Linguistic play as a writing exercise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/linguistic-play-as-a-writing-exercise/</guid><description>[[authors/gretchen mcculloch|Gretchen McCulloch]], [[books/because internet|Because Internet]]:
I’ve taken up this sense of linguistic play as a writing exercise, especially when I’ve just read a bunch of academic papers and I’m having trouble shaking my thoughts free of Nominalization Accumulation Enunciation Contamination. Instead, I draft in Peak Internet Style, with no capitalization or punctuation, using acronyms and creative respelling to write my way through the muddle, rather than stopping when I don’t know how to articulate something or trying to sort through form and content at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Institutional betrayal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</guid><description>Institutional betrayal is when an institution causes harm (by action or inaction) to anyone who trusts or depends on them. Red flags include strict membership requirements (the military, elite sports), prestige or power differentials (caregivers v. patients, clergy v. parishioners), and rigid priorities, like extreme efforts to protect the reputation of the organization.</description></item><item><title>Humanitas/humus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/humanitas-humus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/humanitas-humus/</guid><description>Humanitas in Latin comes first and properly from humando, meaning ‘burying, burial’, itself from humus, meaning ‘earth’ or ‘soil.’ In burial, the human body becomes a component of the earth, returned as dust to dust—inhumed, restored to humility, rendered humble.
[[books/underland|Underland]], [[authors/robert macfarlane|Robert Macfarlane]]</description></item><item><title>Glimmering</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/glimmering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/glimmering/</guid><description>The opposite of a trigger. A little glimmering of affirmation.
First encountered on IG, @tialevings and others</description></item><item><title>Emergence occurs at a certain level of complexity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emergence-occurs-at-a-certain-level-of-complexity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emergence-occurs-at-a-certain-level-of-complexity/</guid><description>Faced with the puzzle of how life might emerge from dead matter or how conscious beings might evolve from microbes, philosophers of science have developed the theory of emergence.
The argument here is that once a certain level of complexity is reached, there is a kind of qualitative leap where completely new sorts of physical laws can “emerge”—ones that are premised on, but cannot be reduced to, what came before.</description></item><item><title>Emotional identification</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotional-identification/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotional-identification/</guid><description>Broadly speaking, we experience three different kinds of emotions in our brains: reactive, routine, and reflective emotions.
Reactive emotions are primitive, hardwired, and innate emotions, such as fear and defensive rage, produced in response to a perceived threat. They energize us for fight-and-flight and live in our limbic system.</description></item><item><title>The Chinese word for endurance</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/endurance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/endurance/</guid><description>In [[books/what my bones know|What My Bones Know]], [[authors/stephanie foo|Stephanie Foo]] says:
It made perfect sense to me later in life when I discovered that the Chinese word for endurance is simply the word knife on top of the word heart. You walk around with a knife in your heart.</description></item><item><title>Debility and disability justice</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/debility-is-the-denial-of-disability-rights-altogether/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/debility-is-the-denial-of-disability-rights-altogether/</guid><description>In [[books/the right to maim|The Right to Maim]], [[authors/jasbir puar|Jasbir Puar]] uses the concept of “debility”—bodily injury and social exclusion brought on by economic and political factors—to disrupt the category of disability and the neoliberal concept of disability justice.
Puar uses the term debilitation to describe what happens to Mohammed and so many others in Gaza that our neoliberal frame of disability rights can’t capture.</description></item><item><title>Calliphony</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/calliphony/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 14:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/calliphony/</guid><description>Calliphony is the as-of-yet uncoined and obviously absent opposite of the well-known adjective cacophony (which is currently notably lacking in any other accurately or articulately quotable antithesis).1
Roots come from the Greek words calli and caco, meaning ‘beautiful’ and ‘ugly’ when used to preface nouns.</description></item><item><title>Compersion</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/compersion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/compersion/</guid><description>Vicarious joy, experiencing pleasure because of another person’s pleasure. Basically the opposite of jealousy.
Coined by the Kerista Community in the 1970s, probably following the model of dispersion, so that use specifically applies to polyamorous relationships, the pleasure of your partner experiencing pleasure with someone else.</description></item><item><title>Common enemy intimacy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/common-enemy-intimacy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/common-enemy-intimacy/</guid><description>Via [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]]:
What’s really fascinating is that hate is actually fueled by our need for connection. I call this common enemy intimacy. I may not know anything about you, but we hate the same people and that creates a counterfeit bond and a sense of belonging.</description></item><item><title>The Buddhist concept of near enemies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/buddhist-concept-of-near-enemies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/buddhist-concept-of-near-enemies/</guid><description>via [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]]:
The Buddhist concept of near enemies: “Near enemies are states that appear similar to the desired quality but actually undermine it. Far enemies are the opposite of what we are trying to achieve. For example, a near enemy of loving-kindness is sentimentality—similar but different.</description></item><item><title>Deep time decenters the human</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/deep-time-decenters-the-human/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/deep-time-decenters-the-human/</guid><description>Deep time, coined by [[authors/john mcphee|John McPhee]] in [[books/annals of the former world|Basin and Range]], is a concept of geological time so vast it completely annihilates the scale of human history.
Numbers do not seem to work well with regard to deep time. Any number above a couple of thousand years—fifty thousand, fifty million—will with nearly equal effect awe the imagination to the point of paralysis.</description></item><item><title>Naft</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/naft/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/naft/</guid><description>Naft (نفت in Persian) is a naturally occurring petroleum (naphtha), often a flammable mix used in war such as Greek fire—a highly flammable substance of unknown composition first used by the Greeks of Constantinople in the 7th century C.E. to set fire to enemy ships.1</description></item><item><title>Despair is a state of repair</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/despair-is-a-state-of-repair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/despair-is-a-state-of-repair/</guid><description>[[authors/brené brown|Brené Brown]] puts despair as a synonym with hopelessness in [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]], so I’m going to go with [[authors/david whyte|David Whyte’s]] take on it instead. (Whyte and Brown, lol.)
((Note: maybe what I classify as despair would be more what Brown describes as anguish?</description></item><item><title>Autism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/autism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/autism/</guid><description>I like this terminology: high masking, not high functioning. I think I first heard it via Megan Ness?</description></item><item><title>The myth of scarcity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/myth-of-scarcity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/myth-of-scarcity/</guid><description>Kinship societies were basically replaced by dominator societies because of the threat of scarcity—so of course capitalism is committed to maintaining that myth.</description></item><item><title>Seasonal time</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/seasonal-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/seasonal-time/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ecclesiastes as a protest manifesto</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ecclesiastes-as-a-protest-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ecclesiastes-as-a-protest-manifesto/</guid><description>No wonder Ecclesiastes has long been my favorite part of Hebrew scripture (along with Song of Songs, Esther, and… nope, just those three I think.) This little gem dropped in the entry on Encyclopedia Brittanica:
The book reflects the ideas of one who questioned the doctrine of retributive justice associated with wisdom theology.</description></item><item><title>Our greatest responsibility is to be good ancestors</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-greatest-responsibility-is-to-be-good-ancestors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/our-greatest-responsibility-is-to-be-good-ancestors/</guid><description>Jonas Salk, the mid-20th-century virologist, coined the question-turned-maxim, “ Are We Being Good Ancestors?” He called it humanity’s greatest responsibility, and said that we are not only a product of evolution, but its instruments as well.
If we want to be good ancestors, we should show future generations how we coped with an age of great change and great crises.</description></item><item><title>Crypsis</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/crypsis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/crypsis/</guid><description>Concealment. In biology, it’s the ability of an organism to avoid observation.
Also, interestingly enough: it’s a term used in the seventeenth century to designate Christ’s possession of divine omnipotence and divine omniscience, with conscious restraint in the use of them.
First encountered in [[books/following the water|Following the Water]] by [[authors/david m carroll|David M.</description></item><item><title>Animism is a dynamic, relational structure</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/animism-is-a-dynamic-relational-structure/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 14:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/animism-is-a-dynamic-relational-structure/</guid><description>Animism is a belief in the “animation of all nature” (E. B. Tylor), where “the world and its various powers are neither good nor bad… but open, efficacious, and above all, relational.” (Graham Harvey)
Far from abolishing or preventing distinctions, then, this sort of animacy produces differences locally and interactively.</description></item><item><title>Creativity should have fallow days too</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/creativity-should-have-fallow-days-too/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/creativity-should-have-fallow-days-too/</guid><description>Austin Kleon has written for years about the creative process of chain smoking. It’s never resonated with me; I can’t be that person of work every day even while a project is in progress. It ebbs and flows like the tide, days of rampant blooming interspersed with the fallow days of rootwork, day dreaming, glorious nothingness.</description></item><item><title>The capitalist notion of well-being</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-capitalist-notion-of-well-being/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-capitalist-notion-of-well-being/</guid><description>[[authors/bell hooks|bell hooks]] in [[books/all about love|All About Love]]:
I am talking here about the many prophets of doom who tell us that racism will never end, sexism is here to stay, the rich will never share their resources. We would all be surprised if we could enter their lives for a day.</description></item><item><title>English Poor Laws</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/english-poor-laws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 15:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/english-poor-laws/</guid><description>English Poor Laws: Historical Precedents of Tax-Supported Relief for the Poor:
In 1601, England was experiencing a severe economic depression, with large scale unemployment and widespread famine. Queen Elizabeth proclaimed a set of laws designed to maintain order and contribute to the general good of the kingdom: the English Poor Laws.</description></item><item><title>Healthy stories are fluid, not fixed</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/healthy-stories-are-fluid-not-fixed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/healthy-stories-are-fluid-not-fixed/</guid><description>We often forget that our storytelling is rooted in millennia of oral tradition. Collaborative, mutable, fluid, living narratives that changed to suit different ecosystems and social scenarios.
Written tales are more “permanent,” but they have a harder time evolving. So we’ve traded (a false sense of) permanence for the complex and evolving (and communal) narrative lifeforms.</description></item><item><title>AI exposes the hierarchy of intelligence</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ai-exposes-the-hierarchy-of-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ai-exposes-the-hierarchy-of-intelligence/</guid><description>These were back to back in my feed: Mandy Brown on the smokescreen of AI and our narratives (it’s masking the real story; we need to re-think our hierarchy of intelligence), then Austin Kleon on AI as intern (appeasing our need to be the superior intelligence?</description></item><item><title>Concepts of time</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/concepts-of-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/concepts-of-time/</guid><description>The Greeks had two different conceptions of time: chronos (quantitative, linear) and kairos (qualitative, nonlinear).
Ancient Indians had a similar conception of time: kala (quantitative) and ritu (qualitative).
[[notes/deep time decenters the human|Deep time]] (also called geological time, cosmological time, or radiological time) involves the time scale of geologic events, which is incomparably vast compared to the time scale of human history.</description></item><item><title>Manifest Destiny</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/manifest-destiny/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 0223 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/manifest-destiny/</guid><description>Manifest Destiny, an event of Westward Expansion from the Wild West
In the 19th century US, Manifest Destiny was a belief that was widely held that the destiny of American settlers was to expand and move across the continent to spread their traditions and their institutions, while at the same time ==enlightening more primitive nations==.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-radical-idea-that-people-arent-stupid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-radical-idea-that-people-arent-stupid/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A social construct doesn’t mean it’s not real</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/a-social-construct-doesnt-mean-its-not-real/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/a-social-construct-doesnt-mean-its-not-real/</guid><description>Our “real” experiences, symptoms, and syndromes—individually or collectively—can be mental as well as physical.
The subtext of these critiques is that PMS is “socially constructed,” meaning it’s an imaginary condition foisted on women by society, which is another way of saying PMS is “not real.</description></item><item><title>Abuse isn’t just pathological, it’s political</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-isnt-just-pathological-its-political/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-isnt-just-pathological-its-political/</guid><description>Red flag for anything rationalizing “this is just the way things are,” or framing a problem as an individual one instead of a collective one. (Or worse, putting the onus on the victim instead of the offender.)
Feminists know about power. Specifically, they know a lot about unequal power relationships; how they are systematically used, and how they are rationalised or explained away as ‘just the way things are’.</description></item><item><title>Choosing the familiar doesn’t take you somewhere new</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/choosing-the-familiar-doesnt-take-you-somewhere-new/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/choosing-the-familiar-doesnt-take-you-somewhere-new/</guid><description>When you’re stuck or encountering an obstacle: choosing the least familiar path is the best way forward. Going with what feels safe can keep you stuck in that loop. Forging new terrain, scary as it is, is the way to get somewhere better.
Oftentimes, you might feel that you’re stuck between a rock and hard place—there are two sets of unpleasant feelings, one on either side, that you’re having to choose between.</description></item><item><title>Cognitive biases don’t prove we’re bad at thinking</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cognitive-biases-dont-prove-were-bad-at-thinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/cognitive-biases-dont-prove-were-bad-at-thinking/</guid><description>Instead of illustrating how stupid people are, cognitive biases actually show how much work our brain is doing to make us good at thinking. Visual illusions can fool the eye with clever tricks, and cognitive illusions can do the same, helping us understand how the mind works and how the mind breaks.</description></item><item><title>Don’t pledge allegiance to any one ideology</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/dont-pledge-allegiance-to-any-one-ideology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/dont-pledge-allegiance-to-any-one-ideology/</guid><description>Make a patchwork quilt! That’s so much more fun, effective, and reliable than devoting yourself to any one ideology.
Ideology → purity → supremacy happens all the time. Or at best, you get tangled up in labels and abstractions, and the arguments thereof.
The closest ideologies to my own values are an overlapping hodgepodge of taoism, anarchism, and indigenous animism, with a lil’ sprinkling of socialism, etc.</description></item><item><title>Fascism can’t survive long term</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fascism-cant-survive-long-term/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/fascism-cant-survive-long-term/</guid><description>How’s this for a shower thought: fascism keeps arising because fascism keeps getting defeated. It can’t survive long-term because it enforces so much conformity that it collapses. Diversity is stability.
previously: every ecologist knows that [[notes/diversity provides stability|diversity provides stability]] see also: [[notes/think in ecosystems, not systems|think in ecosystems, not systems]] (systems = authoritarian hierarchy, ecosystems = diversity and decentralized collaboration)</description></item><item><title>Flow, don’t force</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/flow-dont-force/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/flow-dont-force/</guid><description>Those who would take over the world and manage it,
I see that they cannot grasp it;
for the world is a spiritual [神 shén] vessel
and cannot be forced.
Whoever forces it spoils it.
Whoever grasps it loses it. —[[authors/lao tzu|Lao Tzu]], 29</description></item><item><title>It happens when it’s time</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/it-happens-when-its-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/it-happens-when-its-time/</guid><description>Generally when someone leaves an abusive relationship it happens for the same reason flowers bloom: because it was time. Something just shifts, and suddenly you’re seeing things you weren’t seeing before. You start noticing patterns, noticing manipulations, noticing the malice in the abuser’s face that you’d previously compartmentalized away from seeing.</description></item><item><title>It’s difficult to control something that wiggles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/its-difficult-to-control-something-that-wiggles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/its-difficult-to-control-something-that-wiggles/</guid><description>It’s notoriously difficult to get control over something that wiggles. A fish, a cat, a worm, a snake—the more wiggly, the more fluid, the less it can be controlled, contained, or even measured.
When you want control over something that wiggles, it’s pretty difficult. A fish is extremely wiggly.</description></item><item><title>It’s useless work that darkens the heart</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/its-useless-work-that-darkens-the-heart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/its-useless-work-that-darkens-the-heart/</guid><description>In [[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula K. Le Guin’s]] [[books/the dispossessed|The Dispossessed]], the leader of the anarchist colony on Anarres says:
A child free from the guilt of ownership and the burden of economic competition will grow up with the will to do what needs doing and the capacity for joy in doing it.</description></item><item><title>Noticing the block means you’re ready to do the work</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/noticing-the-block-means-youre-ready-to-do-the-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/noticing-the-block-means-youre-ready-to-do-the-work/</guid><description>Everything is a clue, or a key to unpick the lock. If you’re stuck, trapped, blocked, confused, that in itself means you’re already working on it.
Like so: the fact that you’ve even identified something as a block means movement is happening. When you hit a wall, that’s literally only happening because you’re trying to move energy in a different direction, walk through a new doorway, or dig a new tunnel.</description></item><item><title>People aren’t stupid</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/people-arent-stupid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/people-arent-stupid/</guid><description>Why are we so quick to dismiss other people as stupid? (While at the same time being impressed by a very, very limited, exorbitantly inefficient so-called artificial intelligence?) Humans perform astounding feats of intelligence just by existing every day, so who benefits when we bash ourselves and others for stupidity?</description></item><item><title>People bluff the opposite of the hand they’re holding</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/people-bluff-the-opposite-of-the-hand-theyre-holding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/people-bluff-the-opposite-of-the-hand-theyre-holding/</guid><description>People tend to bluff the opposite of whatever hand they’re holding; newbies do it in poker, and everyone does it with their ego. Conservatives are afraid of everything, so they posture as hypermasculine tough guys. Liberals are bootlickers who act like heroes of social justice.</description></item><item><title>Power doesn’t need facts or evidence, just narrative and ideology</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-doesnt-need-facts-or-evidence-just-narrative-and-ideology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-doesnt-need-facts-or-evidence-just-narrative-and-ideology/</guid><description>Power doesn’t need facts or evidence, even when its claims are self-evidently disruptive to the democratic process. It exists chiefly in the realm of narrative and ideology. This is a story, just like Corbyn’s “antisemitism crisis”, that is made true simply through repetition.
Because power is power, its narratives can defy the most elementary rules of logic.</description></item><item><title>Since it’s all narrative, anything is possible</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/since-its-all-narrative-anything-is-possible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/since-its-all-narrative-anything-is-possible/</guid><description>Because here’s the thing: since it’s all narrative, anything is possible. Those who see this have the ability to plunge toward health and human thriving without any regard for the made-up reasons why such a thing is impossible, and plant seeds of light which sprout in unprecedented directions that never could have been predicted by someone plugged into to establishment how-it-is stories.</description></item><item><title>The only thing keeping a crown on a king’s head is narrative</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-only-thing-keeping-a-crown-on-a-kings-head-is-narrative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-only-thing-keeping-a-crown-on-a-kings-head-is-narrative/</guid><description>This is why there have been book burnings, heretic burnings, and executions for mocking the emperor throughout history: ==ideas which differ from the dominant narratives about what power is, how money works, who should be in charge and so on are threatening to a ruler’s power in the exact same way that an assassin’s dagger is.</description></item><item><title>We’ve had the right to adapt longer than we’ve had the right to prevent copying</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/weve-had-the-right-to-adapt-longer-than-weve-had-the-right-to-prevent-copying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/weve-had-the-right-to-adapt-longer-than-weve-had-the-right-to-prevent-copying/</guid><description>Basically the printing press introduced the notion of copyright, but we’ve had the right to adapt for ages and ages.
Our modern, Western notion that authorship should be solo and original is comparatively young and culturally bound, dating back only to after we had the ability to make faithful and exact copies at a mass scale.</description></item><item><title>You’re only powerless if you stand alone</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/youre-only-powerless-if-you-stand-alone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/youre-only-powerless-if-you-stand-alone/</guid><description>We’ve all got a grain of sand’s worth of influence over our world. The historically unprecedented democratization of information and our ability to network and communicate like never before has given us all a grain of sand’s worth of power to open eyes and win hearts and minds over to a more revolutionary worldview.</description></item></channel></rss>