<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>St Martin’s Griffin on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/publishers/st-martins-griffin/</link><description>Recent content in St Martin’s Griffin on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/publishers/st-martins-griffin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Earl Crush</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earl-crush/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/earl-crush/</guid><description>Listen, I’ve just about sworn off m/f romance after so many recent flops, but this one snuck in under the wire, as I was already committed to the ARC. It’s good! Not amazing, but good, in the fulfilled-the-brief, let’s-not-overthink-it kind of way I’ve been looking for [[digest/books of august ’24|since August]].</description></item><item><title>Late Bloomer</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/late-bloomer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/late-bloomer/</guid><description>In a way, it’s not the author’s fault that this book let me down. If you have characters named Pepper and Opal, set the book in NC, and give the front cover major Bess and George vibes, there’s no way I can restrain my imagination or my expectations.</description></item><item><title>How to Fall for a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>A thief and a private investigator team up to solve a theft, and the vibes are basically a case-of-the-week tv episode (think Charlie’s Angels, Remington Steele, White Collar, etc) playing historical dress-up. The plot is as straightforward as it gets—they search for a macguffin, they get a clue, they get another clue, they solve the case.</description></item><item><title>Trouble</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/trouble/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/trouble/</guid><description>Perfection. I knew Lex Croucher could do it. Each standalone entry in this not-quite-series has been good, better, best. This one is THE BEST. In Emily, Croucher has written the prickly heroine of my dreams, who isn’t required to sand down any sharp edges for plot or relationship reasons.</description></item><item><title>Infamous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/infamous/</guid><description>This ending was the EXACT ENDING I’ve wanted to see for SO LONG. (Unapologetic all caps.) It took us ages to get there (more on that in a sec) but once we did? CHEF’S KISS.
Spoilery: %%it’s an f/f romance, and one half of the pair is affianced, to an amazing man, who’s gay, and they are going to use their marriage to give themselves and their true partners a safe harbor from society, and they go through with their marriage, and it’s just beautifully done, and… sniff I have a lot of feelings about friendships and healthy communication and unconventional choices and that kind of love.</description></item><item><title>Reputation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/reputation/</guid><description>Lex Croucher’s lols-per-page cannot be beat.
Weirdly, the only character I was meh on was the love interest, just because he’s too perfect. (My notes say “Col Brandon in a Henry Tilney body???”) I also would have been fine if this had swung more towards a coming-of-age instead of HEA romance, but I won’t hold that against it.</description></item></channel></rss>