<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>too-many-dukes on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/too-many-dukes/</link><description>Recent content in too-many-dukes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 14:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/too-many-dukes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Something Fabulous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</guid><description>So far the theme of the year is romances that I read and then re-read right away and install on my best-of-year list (best-of-ever list too, in the case of Something Fabulous, which more than lives up to its name).
A few notes:
We’re starting to see the books written during the pandemic where authors are writing what they WANT, not what they SHOULD.</description></item><item><title>Any Old Diamonds</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/any-old-diamonds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/any-old-diamonds/</guid><description>As KJC says: In which we stick it to a duke.
What [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] was to 2018, Any Old Diamonds is to 2019. It’s SO good. An instant favorite. I might have to re-read both to decide which one I like best, and if it’s too close to call, which only means I should read them a third and fourth time, I won’t mind a bit.</description></item><item><title>Something Spectacular</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</guid><description>You couldn’t write your own story in the margins of someone else’s.
I want to write something long and complex about the concept of family in this book (the Tarletons enfolding Valentine and Sir Horley and Periwinkle and practically every other stray into their own little world; the stitched-together warmth of the Delanceys’ parenting, wrapped around Peggy like a quilt; that spectacular ending of creating a new family when convention says it’s impossible).</description></item><item><title>The Duke at Hazard</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</guid><description>I have a few auto-buy (auto-preorder) authors, but KJ Charles is the only one where I drop everything to start reading the day a new book comes out. Here, that impatience is rewarded with a tender, slow-blooming romance-on-the-run between Daizell, a disgraced non-scoundrel scoundrel (he’s paying for the sins of his father), and Cassian, aka The Duke, aka Vernon Fortescue Cassian George de Vere Crosse, the fourth Duke of Severn, the Earl of Harmsford, Baron Crosse of Wotton, and Baron Vere, who’s incognito for a month to hunt down a thief and win a wager (he’s burdened with the premature inheritance of his father’s title).</description></item><item><title>The Duchess War</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duchess-war/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 22:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duchess-war/</guid><description>Finally I didn’t bounce off a Courtney Milan! Granted, the Norfolk Southern disaster had me in the mood to read about labor organizing, and that part worked for me better than the romance.
(In theory, I liked Minnie and Robert together, but they didn’t make me feel it, you know.</description></item></channel></rss>