<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>young-adult on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/young-adult/</link><description>Recent content in young-adult on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/young-adult/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pet/</guid><description>A YA book that discusses [[authors/hannah arendt|Hannah Arendt]] and [[books/the origins of totalitarianism|the banality of evil]] in the introduction, then goes on to drop some biblically accurate angels? YES PLEASE.</description></item><item><title>Bitter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</guid><description>Is this even better than [[books/pet|Pet]]? Holy crap, I think so. The struggle. The hope. The tenderness. It knocked me sideways. I love it.
Bitter had learned it was better to be stoic, to be a blank and unfeeling wall, because if you were entirely armor and no underbelly, then they couldn’t stab you in the soft places.</description></item><item><title>Amazing Asia</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/amazing-asia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/amazing-asia/</guid><description>The “explain it like I’m 5” primer that more people beyond the age of 5 could appreciate. It’s more thorough, interesting, and engaging than what got taught in school, that’s for sure.
ARC kindly provided by the publisher via NetGalley in exchange for an honest review.</description></item><item><title>Minor Mage</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/minor-mage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/minor-mage/</guid><description>Oliver was already on his knees, but he bowed his head, feeling complicated things he didn’t know how to deal with. When kindness came from murdered ghosts and lost pigs, and the adults that were supposed to help you were monsters that walked like men… What was he supposed to do?</description></item><item><title>Among Others</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</guid><description>“[[notes/bibliotropic|Bibliotropic]],” Hugh said. “Like sunflowers are heliotropic, they naturally turn towards the sun. We naturally turn towards the bookshop.”
Where do I begin? What is this book about? Books, yes. A love of books and of libraries. Books as lifeline and language. It’s about a girl growing up, and witches and fairies and boarding schools and grief and Wales and loneliness even amongst those with whom you might belong.</description></item><item><title>Come Out, Come Out</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</guid><description>In the same niche as [[books/camp damascus|Camp Damascus]], the conversion-therapy-as-horror genre. Similarities abound, even down to the senior class quarry jumps, which doesn’t indicate any co-opting of plot points but simply how ubiquitous this experience is, the same script across rural America, where any deviation from the script means there will be Consequences.</description></item><item><title>Lunar New Year Love Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lunar-new-year-love-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lunar-new-year-love-story/</guid><description>What I loved: the cultural stuff, especially lion dancing, and the nuance about the Asian diaspora (Vietnamese, Chinese, and Korean all represented).
What I wasn’t expecting: Lunar New Year actually plays a small part in the story; it’s much more focused on Valentine’s Day and Catholicism.</description></item><item><title>The Magic Fish</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-magic-fish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-magic-fish/</guid><description>Wow. Absolutely lovely. Destroyed me in the best way.
And just on a visual level, what Nguyen does with the coloring for the different timelines, and the extensive notes on historical fashion and mythological context in the afterword make me appreciate it even more.</description></item><item><title>Gwen &amp; Art Are Not in Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gwen-and-art-are-not-in-love/</guid><description>I think it wobbled a smiiiidge on the landing, a few things felt abrupt and/or undercooked, not to mention the jarring tonal shift into violence, but the ride to get there was super fun. There’s some fade-to-black, hand-wavey, don’t-think-too-hard-about-this energy re: the whole premature-inheritance, fix-a-broken-system-from-the-inside plan, but it is YA, and I wasn’t expecting an [[books/bitter|Akwaeke Emezi-level thesis]] on the subject of institutional power.</description></item></channel></rss>