<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>abuse on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/abuse/</link><description>Recent content in abuse on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/abuse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to detect manipulation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-detect-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/how-to-detect-manipulation/</guid><description>If you feel muddled, scrambled, disoriented, that’s a sign of psychological manipulation/distortion, or often downright abuse. If you feel clarity, even if it’s challenging and uncomfortable, you’re likely on to something true.
Note: to me this is different than feeling uncertain. Uncertainty is an honest and even necessary state, open to inquiry and reflection.</description></item><item><title>The holistic definition of trauma</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-holistic-definition-of-trauma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-holistic-definition-of-trauma/</guid><description>One of the most accurate definitions of trauma I’ve found is from [[books/chinese medicine for the mind|Chinese Medicine for the Mind]] ([[authors/nina cheng|Nina Cheng]]), which acknowledges that it involves many aspects of emotional, psychological, and physiological conditions.
The defining characteristics:
Overwhelms the nervous system Violates boundaries Disrupts relationality Severs connections Admits feelings of powerlessness Damages the sense of meaning Inhibits the sense of self Disrupts contact with the self Instigates or stimulates collapse/separation of yin and yang (dysregulation) Interestingly, I was just looking up TRE on the cptsdfoundation.</description></item><item><title>The relationship abuse checklist</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-relationship-abuse-checklist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-relationship-abuse-checklist/</guid><description>In the years since I read it, I still haven’t come across a better relationship inventory than [[authors/anton fulmen|Anton Fulmen’s]] in [[books/the dominance playbook|The Dominance Playbook]]. (Leave it to the kink community to nail down the dynamics of abuse.) I reference it all the time, and what I like most is it applies to any interactions between people, not just sexual or romantic relationships.</description></item><item><title>Institutional betrayal</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/institutional-betrayal/</guid><description>Institutional betrayal is when an institution causes harm (by action or inaction) to anyone who trusts or depends on them. Red flags include strict membership requirements (the military, elite sports), prestige or power differentials (caregivers v. patients, clergy v. parishioners), and rigid priorities, like extreme efforts to protect the reputation of the organization.</description></item><item><title>Abuse isn’t just pathological, it’s political</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-isnt-just-pathological-its-political/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-isnt-just-pathological-its-political/</guid><description>Red flag for anything rationalizing “this is just the way things are,” or framing a problem as an individual one instead of a collective one. (Or worse, putting the onus on the victim instead of the offender.)
Feminists know about power. Specifically, they know a lot about unequal power relationships; how they are systematically used, and how they are rationalised or explained away as ‘just the way things are’.</description></item></channel></rss>