<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>contemporary-romance on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/contemporary-romance/</link><description>Recent content in contemporary-romance on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/contemporary-romance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Bang a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-bang-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-bang-a-billionaire/</guid><description>Ugh, billionaires! I love Arden as much as I ugh Caspian. Which I think is the point at this point. Fifty Shades of Gray fanfic at its finest.</description></item><item><title>Rosaline Palmer Takes the Cake</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rosaline-palmer-takes-the-cake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rosaline-palmer-takes-the-cake/</guid><description>I laughed. I cried. I have a therapist now. How many books can do that, AND homage the hell out of the Great British Bake Off?
Rosaline Palmer does take the cake.</description></item><item><title>10 Things That Never Happened</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</guid><description>It’s about grief and melancholy and connection and hope; it hit me so hard in the feels I cried through the last chapters. Outstanding use of the cheesy amnesia trope, a worthy homage to While You Were Sleeping. (Sam is absolutely the British Sandra Bullock.)</description></item><item><title>Boyfriend Material</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/boyfriend-material/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/boyfriend-material/</guid><description>I’m doing a reading challenge for the local library and need “a book that became a movie” for bingo, and how I wish this book qualified because, if Hollywood knew what they were doing, it should be optioned and filmed before I finish this sentence.</description></item><item><title>Delilah Green Doesn’t Care</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/delilah-green-doesnt-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/delilah-green-doesnt-care/</guid><description>One of those books where the friendships ALMOST outshine the romance. ALMOST. Everybody has arcs and character growth, even the exes; everybody contributes their piece of misunderstanding and conflict resolution to the plot. It’s like a big group hug from best friends, messy and comforting and silly and necessary.</description></item><item><title>Glitterland</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/glitterland/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/glitterland/</guid><description>Give me any book where the hero is not conventional hero material, and is devalued by the world, and is the best person in the world anyway, and is unashamed to be themselves, and makes molehills out of mountains because they love freely and completely. I cried through the whole end because I am a marshmallow with a weakness for glitter pirates from Essex.</description></item><item><title>How to Blow It with a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-blow-it-with-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-blow-it-with-a-billionaire/</guid><description>It’s a testament to Hall’s writing that I’m still enjoying a series where my primary thought is: Arden! Ditch Caspian!</description></item><item><title>Paris Daillencourt is About to Crumble</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</guid><description>Once again Alexis Hall takes away the book I thought I wanted and replaces it with the book I actually need.
Reading this at the same time as [[books/the body keeps the score|The Body Keeps the Score]], though, just means I’m peeking between the lines of all the parental neglect and trauma and thinking, dearest Paris, get thee to some somatic therapy, medication is just a start.</description></item><item><title>Husband Material</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/husband-material/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/husband-material/</guid><description>Choosing to interrogate the state of matrimony, I should have expected nothing less from Alexis Hall. I had to read this twice to really like it, because I am so urgggggh about weddings, and I needed the ending spoiled to get fully on board:
%%THEY DITCHED THEIR OWN WEDDING AT THE ALTAR WOOHOOO%%</description></item><item><title>Waiting for the Flood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/waiting-for-the-flood/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/waiting-for-the-flood/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Astrid Parker Doesn’t Fail</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/astrid-parker-doesnt-fail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/astrid-parker-doesnt-fail/</guid><description>Look, realistically, the destiny stuff did not work for me. They’ve known each other a handful of weeks; saying, “I really, really like you, we’re both hot messes, let’s try to make this work” would have been much more my speed.
But. I love Astrid Parker SO MUCH.</description></item><item><title>How to Belong with a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-belong-with-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-belong-with-a-billionaire/</guid><description>If there’s an author who could get me to love books with billionaire in the title, it’s Alexis Hall. Just like if there’s an author who could get me to love books with duke in the title, it’s going to be Alexis Hall’s [[books/a lady for a duke|upcoming historical romance]].</description></item><item><title>Chasing the Light</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/chasing-the-light/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/chasing-the-light/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Iris Kelly Doesn’t Date</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iris-kelly-doesnt-date/</guid><description>Yes to the gender-bending production of Much Ado About Nothing; yes to practice dating and sex lessons. Beyond that, the plot was a hot mess for me, trying to both validate Iris’s singledom yet ultimately get her in a relationship. I appreciate that Blake acknowledged the difficulty of walking that tightrope, and it is a rom-com—of course it’s gonna be an HEA.</description></item><item><title>You Made a Fool of Death with Your Beauty</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/you-made-a-fool-of-death-with-your-beauty/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/you-made-a-fool-of-death-with-your-beauty/</guid><description>Re-read. The widowed Feyi hooks up with a stranger, then dates his best friend Nasir, then falls in love with Nasir’s father, and none of that sentence captures the raw transcendence of this novel. It makes me not just cry, but weep, multiple times—not (only) because of the grief but because of the way it vibrates with life, with pain, with joy, with every raw emotion.</description></item><item><title>Looking for Group</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/looking-for-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/looking-for-group/</guid><description>Very nearly chaste because there’s a different love language, and that makes it one of the most romantic books I’ve read.</description></item><item><title>Spokes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spokes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spokes/</guid><description>Nooooo. I thought I had finally found the holy grail, cycling fiction (nay, romance!) that gets the cycling facts correct. The dedication is to Wouter Weylandt(!), there’s a glossary of French terms and race classifications, and four pages in she’s name-dropping Garmin-Sharp and Fausto Coppi. My expectations, below sea level, started to gain elevation.</description></item><item><title>Emma of 83rd Street</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:43:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/emma-of-83rd-street/</guid><description>[[books/emma|Emma]] is my favorite [[authors/jane austen|Austen]], and arguably the most difficult to modernize without losing the spirit of the story.1 I don’t envy any author who attempts it, but this one lost me in the weeds, with pacing that seems twice the length of Austen with half the page count.</description></item><item><title>Experienced</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/experienced/</guid><description>Bette gets dumped-but-not-dumped in truly shitty fashion by her girlfriend, who suggests she just needs more experience since she’s newly out as a lesbian. Commence a sex odyssey through the wilds of Bristol, aided by her first failed date of the odyssey, the kind and thoughtful Ruth.</description></item><item><title>Racing to You</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</guid><description>“Has someone written a romance about pro cycling?” was something I wondered last week. And voila, this book.
It actually:
Has some legit knowledge of cycling! Addresses doping as a plot point Addresses the extremely monastic and high-pressure lifestyle Gets the team dynamic! Has real races like Paris-Nice!</description></item><item><title>Lunar New Year Love Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lunar-new-year-love-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lunar-new-year-love-story/</guid><description>What I loved: the cultural stuff, especially lion dancing, and the nuance about the Asian diaspora (Vietnamese, Chinese, and Korean all represented).
What I wasn’t expecting: Lunar New Year actually plays a small part in the story; it’s much more focused on Valentine’s Day and Catholicism.</description></item><item><title>Kiss Her Once for Me</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:40:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</guid><description>Tried this one again, hoping I had one more festive read in me for the year, but there are just sooo many things that bug me right away. It’s gonna be one of those books where shitty systemic poverty gets magically fixed for one [pretty young white] woman by the power of romance with a [manipulative gaslighting] millionaire, isn’t it?</description></item><item><title>I’ll Have What He’s Having</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</guid><description>I’m glad the term tonic masculinity has been making the rounds, because this feels like tonic masculinity of the highest order. David Curtis, sommelier, mistakes Farzan Alavi for a food critic, and what blooms in the wake of this mixup is a tender, sexy, heartfelt romance between two grown adults who have to deal with the obstacles that a grown-ass relationship entails.</description></item></channel></rss>