<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>literary on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/literary/</link><description>Recent content in literary on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/genres/literary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Green Equinox</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-green-equinox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-green-equinox/</guid><description>Sometimes you’re just in the mood for moody, queer af British novels with all the fraught gender politics and literary melodrama of the 1970’s. What can I say! So odd and compelling, like a fever dream. (Often literally, as there is an outbreak of typhoid that infects the course of the story.</description></item><item><title>A Woman Is No Man</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</guid><description>We need more books by Palestinian and Arab authors. I intend to read more by Etaf Rum. But it pains me to say… I think this could have been a (powerful) short story. The structure and even dialogue is very repetitive, in a way that I’m sure is meant to illustrate the cyclical and generational cycle of abuse, but instead means you could skim chapters and not miss anything.</description></item><item><title>Blackouts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</guid><description>All the different layers of meaning to the title—the blackouts our narrator experiences due to PTSD, the blackouts of Juan and his fading memory, the failure of institutional memory, the queer erasure from history, the literal blackouts of the pages of the book. It feels like a work of art, not just a novel.</description></item><item><title>Everyone in This Room Will Someday Be Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</guid><description>This is the most strongly coded [[notes/autism|autistic]] protagonist I’ve read. Especially of the female, high-masking, chronic burnout variety, and undiagnosed. (Or rather, insufficiently diagnosed with anxiety and depression.) The unconscious stimming! Chronic sensory overload! The shutdowns! The meltdowns! The masking!
I feel like I am operating my body like it’s a vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Everyone Knows Your Mother Is a Witch</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-knows-your-mother-is-a-witch/</guid><description>Historical (fan)fiction of Katarina Kepler, Johannes Kepler’s mother, famously tried as a witch. It’s fantastic, the character work, the structure, the narrative voice(s), the exuberant black humor that becomes blacker and blacker as it follows the warp of history. An impressive example of what the genre can do, no boring litfic pretentiousness here.</description></item><item><title>Evil Eye</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</guid><description>This is why I wanted to read more Etaf Rum. This is the book I knew she had in her. It’s just as brilliant and damning a portrait of a toxic marriage as [[books/liars|Liars]] was, with the added generational trauma and displacement of a Palestinian family.</description></item><item><title>Giovanni’s Room</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</guid><description>Not everyone in book club was a fan, but I loved it, but it was brutal, but I’m glad I read it, but I’m glad I won’t be in a rush to read it again.
“Somebody,” said Jacques, “your father or mine, should have told us that not many people have ever died of love.</description></item><item><title>Home Remedies</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/home-remedies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/home-remedies/</guid><description>A collection of short stories, of which my favorite (of course it is, since diving is my favorite sport of the summer Olympics) is the pair of Olympic-level divers, trained to be each other’s shadow, one in unrequited love with the other. Sharp writing, skillful stories of China and its diaspora.</description></item><item><title>Interesting Facts about Space</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</guid><description>Me [page 1]: I’m worried I read too much about [[notes/autism|ASD]] into [[books/everyone in this room will someday be dead|Everyone in This Room Will Someday be Dead]]. This time I’m gonna look for all the ways it’s not autism. I will counteract my bias.
Me [page 20]: This is autism.</description></item><item><title>Lesley Castle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lesley-castle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lesley-castle/</guid><description>I like the goodreads review that says “So you think you are a writer. Read this slim volume and weep.” Austen did this at sixteen, and it’s unpardonably good for any writer, much less someone that young. The one fault of the slim volume is that it is indeed slim.</description></item><item><title>Lessons from Cruising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</guid><description>Joke’s on me, because I picked up this ARC for the last story, a retelling of Billy Budd from Captain Vere’s point of view. I figured I’d sample the rest; instead I went down the buffet line and inhaled them all. Rarely do I like every story in a short story collection, but that’s what Goodman’s done to me.</description></item><item><title>Liars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liars/</guid><description>Brilliant, merciless, couldn’t put it down. Jane marries John (Bridges, but might as well be Doe, for all the universality implied), and misery ensues as John exploits his masculine privilege and his own insecurities to make Jane’s life hell.
Written as autofiction with a dash of crime fiction, it’s an autopsy of a 21st century marriage between two (eventually wealthy) white straight people, who are best placed to reap the benefits of modern feminism and equality, and instead expose the grotesque flaws and inequalities.</description></item><item><title>Margo’s Got Money Troubles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</guid><description>20-year-old Margo sleeps with her professor, gets pregnant, keeps the baby, and discovers what a capitalist hellscape the U.S. is for mothers of all stripes, but particularly the unwed. Creating porn online becomes the only ethical way to survive, and this searing social commentary is wrapped up with so much humor and heart the book practically explodes with it.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>The Fox Wife</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</guid><description>Not the right choice to follow Nghi Vo’s [[books/the brides of high hill|fox-spirit tale]]. Atmospheric, but I feel talked down to and everything is over-explained. This is why I like sticking to genre for Asian fantasy instead of litfic. DNF @ pg 60. (I did flip through the rest because the hardcover had wide margins for sidenotes, but there were… barely any?</description></item></channel></rss>