<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HarperCollins on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/publishers/harpercollins/</link><description>Recent content in HarperCollins on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 15:40:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/publishers/harpercollins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Curse of Chalion</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-curse-of-chalion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-curse-of-chalion/</guid><description>It’s been easier lately for me to review the books I don’t like than the ones I do, because the ones I do, it’s just love, love, love. And it’s often difficult to articulate why.
This is one of the above. I just loved the… gentleness of it.</description></item><item><title>Paladin of Souls</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</guid><description>Magnificent. I didn’t think Bujold could top Cazaril as a character, and she does. Illvin and beloved Ista. Such a rich, full, scarred world she’s created. It spoke to me deeply, even more than the first. I cried. I felt joy-struck. Cursed, bitter Ista is also blessed, beloved Ista.</description></item><item><title>The Hallowed Hunt</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hallowed-hunt/</guid><description>Not the heights of Ista or Cazaril, but going backwards in this timeline instead of forwards is a choice I admire. I can see returning to this one as often as the two favorites, especially if those two get worn out by re-reading.</description></item><item><title>The Hidden Life of Trees</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hidden-life-of-trees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-hidden-life-of-trees/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Woman Is No Man</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</guid><description>We need more books by Palestinian and Arab authors. I intend to read more by Etaf Rum. But it pains me to say… I think this could have been a (powerful) short story. The structure and even dialogue is very repetitive, in a way that I’m sure is meant to illustrate the cyclical and generational cycle of abuse, but instead means you could skim chapters and not miss anything.</description></item><item><title>All About Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/all-about-love/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/all-about-love/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Always Coming Home</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/always-coming-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/always-coming-home/</guid><description>I’ve been saving this one because [[notes/the carrier bag theory of fiction|the Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction]] has been such a foundational text for me, and this is where Ursula, more than ever, puts that theory to practice.
As Shruti Swamy says in the introduction, what is on offer here is a profoundly different way of looking, seeing, even thinking.</description></item><item><title>Evil Eye</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/evil-eye/</guid><description>This is why I wanted to read more Etaf Rum. This is the book I knew she had in her. It’s just as brilliant and damning a portrait of a toxic marriage as [[books/liars|Liars]] was, with the added generational trauma and displacement of a Palestinian family.</description></item><item><title>If On A Winter’s Night A Traveler</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/if-on-a-winters-night-a-traveler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/if-on-a-winters-night-a-traveler/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Invisible Cities</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/invisible-cities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/invisible-cities/</guid><description>Still my least favorite Calvino, strange as that may seem when many people rank it his best. Let’s take it for granted that I’m weird and they’re right. It suffers more this time from [[books/kalpa imperial|Kalpa Imperial]], which has much the same vision but with people included.</description></item><item><title>Margo’s Got Money Troubles</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/margos-got-money-troubles/</guid><description>20-year-old Margo sleeps with her professor, gets pregnant, keeps the baby, and discovers what a capitalist hellscape the U.S. is for mothers of all stripes, but particularly the unwed. Creating porn online becomes the only ethical way to survive, and this searing social commentary is wrapped up with so much humor and heart the book practically explodes with it.</description></item><item><title>Pagans</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pagans/</guid><description>About as beautifully (and concisely) written as you can get for a history book. Fabulous stuff. Some fav lines:
—Augustus revived a thing that had barely been invented in his own time: “old-time religion,” rather like the nearly postmodern version of Christianity invented in nineteenth-century America and called “fundamentalism.</description></item><item><title>Tao Te Ching: A New English Version</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tao-te-ching-a-new-english-version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tao-te-ching-a-new-english-version/</guid><description>Since I had [[books/tao te ching|Ursula K. Le Guin’s translation]] on hand, I picked up Stephen Mitchell’s as well. Reading them side by side: Mitchell’s version is what we expect spiritual texts to be; Le Guin’s is what spiritual texts should be.
In the introduction, he says he played with the text, but there’s very little playfulness involved.</description></item></channel></rss>