<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>transgender on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/transgender/</link><description>Recent content in transgender on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/transgender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Moves the Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/what-moves-the-dead/</guid><description>Just what I wanted for October: brilliant gothic fanfiction of The Fall of the House of Usher with even more fungi than Poe. Creepy and exquisite, and that’s not just the cover art.
(With a bonus Beatrix Potter relative, clever worldbuilding linguistics w/r/t gender, and a hat tip to Prisoner of Zenda!</description></item><item><title>Pet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pet/</guid><description>A YA book that discusses [[authors/hannah arendt|Hannah Arendt]] and [[books/the origins of totalitarianism|the banality of evil]] in the introduction, then goes on to drop some biblically accurate angels? YES PLEASE.</description></item><item><title>The Rat-Catcher’s Daughter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</guid><description>Very sweet and dare I say necessary before [[books/gilded cage|Gilded Cage]]. It has some pretty key context. And come on—that title.</description></item><item><title>A Lady for a Duke</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-lady-for-a-duke/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-lady-for-a-duke/</guid><description>Re-read 11/24. Drastic measures were needed after so many historical romance duds lately, especially with duke in the title. I wanted something full of sweeping romance on a foggy moor, angst and glory and tenderness. This was the safest bet possible.
I liked it the first time, but I loved it this time.</description></item><item><title>Country Queers</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/country-queers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/country-queers/</guid><description>A book after my little southern queer heart. Garringer crisscrosses the Bible Belt, collecting a scrapbook and oral history of various LGBTQ+ people living in the rural margins. The older interviewees—the elders who survived the AIDS crisis and more—are the best and most emotional part. It’s easy to get miffed when people act like the Brooklyn or San Francisco subcultures are the only ones that matter, or like gay and trans people don’t exist in the south except to be persecuted.</description></item><item><title>I Cross-Dressed for the IRL Meetup</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-cross-dressed-for-the-irl-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/i-cross-dressed-for-the-irl-meetup/</guid><description>I love seeing what Japanese manga does with gender. [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer’s]] essay on anime and manga has some of the historical context for it, but you don’t need a history lesson to enjoy this fun volume. I particularly liked the seamless inclusion of a trans girl alongside the cross-dressing boys, highlighting the differences and similarities among the two, and the lack of moral panic surrounding cross-dressing and gender in general.</description></item><item><title>The Affair of the Mysterious Letter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</guid><description>The only thing I’ve had brain space for this week is Alexis Hall, and I say that as the highest compliment. He brings so much heart, joy, and snark even when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery. Or should I say, especially when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery.</description></item><item><title>Three Kings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</guid><description>Another for my collection of killer opening lines:
Ethan Shaw carried two knives, one for lilies, the other for veins.
And the book just gets better and better from there. It counters all my usual problems with cozy witchy books, and sometimes cozy fantasy in general, not to mention the fraught subject of fertility.</description></item><item><title>Exodus 20</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:55:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</guid><description>If you’re gonna write monster kink, make it a biblically accurate angel. And throw in some searing social/political/theological commentary. This was excellent.</description></item><item><title>One Day I’ll Grow Up and Be a Beautiful Woman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/one-day-ill-grow-up-and-be-a-beautiful-woman/</guid><description>Nonfiction memoir about a mother raising her autistic, transgender daughter and the New Hampshire town that puts their family through hell. It’s harrowing and heartbreaking, a survival guide (barely? hopefully?) about weathering the eye of the current political storm.a I’m always looking for books I can recommend to well-meaning people who want to see past the transphobic headlines, and this one goes on the list.</description></item></channel></rss>