<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>taoism on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/taoism/</link><description>Recent content in taoism on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/taoism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Be like a cat and let go of yourself</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/be-like-a-cat-and-let-go-of-yourself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/be-like-a-cat-and-let-go-of-yourself/</guid><description>The more relaxed you are, the more flexible you are, the more lightly you land.
When a cat falls out of a tree, it lets go of itself. The cat becomes completely relaxed, and lands lightly on the ground. But if a cat were about to fall out of a tree and suddenly make up its mind that it didn’t want to fall, it would become tense and rigid, and would be just a bag of broken bones upon landing.</description></item><item><title>The three lies of power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-three-lies-of-power/</guid><description>For all the aspiring authoritarians wanting to “do the right thing” and force their good ideas on everyone, [[authors/adam mastroianni|Adam Mastroianni]] outlines the wildly delusional three lies of power:
The good guys will always have more power than the bad guys (ed note: I’d argue, the fact we even believe good guys vs.</description></item><item><title>We are doing exactly what the fish are doing</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-doing-exactly-what-the-fish-are-doing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-doing-exactly-what-the-fish-are-doing/</guid><description>[[authors/david graeber|David Graeber]] says that when he taught at Yale, he would assign a reading of the following Taoist story, offering an automatic “A” to any student who could tell him why the last line made sense. (None ever succeeded.)
Zhuangzi and Huizi were strolling on a bridge over the River Hao, when the former observed, “See how the minnows dart between the rocks!</description></item></channel></rss>