<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>taoism on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/taoism/</link><description>Recent content in taoism on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/taoism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>To dominate is to destroy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/to-dominate-is-to-destroy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/to-dominate-is-to-destroy/</guid><description>The Taoists are saying, then, that seen as a whole the universe is a harmony or symbiosis of patterns which cannot exist without each other. However, when it is looked at section by section we find conflict. The biological world is a mutual eating society in which every species is the prey of another.</description></item><item><title>Individuality is inseparable from community</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/individuality-is-inseparable-from-community/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/individuality-is-inseparable-from-community/</guid><description>It shouldn’t surprise me anymore that I keep running across taoism when reading about anarchism or indigenous animism, or running across anarchism/animism when reading about the tao. (But it still does, bc I wanna stay childlike like that ☺️)
The principle is that if everything is allowed to go its own way the harmony of the universe will be established, since every process in the world can “do its own thing” only in relation to all others.</description></item><item><title>No organization is organic</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/no-organization-is-organic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/no-organization-is-organic/</guid><description>No organization, in the political and commercial sense of the word, is organic. Organizations, in this sense, are based on the following of linear rules and laws imposed from above—that is, of strung-out, serial, one-thing-at-a-time sequences of words and signs which can never grasp the complexity of nature, although nature is only “complex” in relation to the impossible task of translating it into these linear signs.</description></item><item><title>The principle of mutual arising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-principle-of-mutual-arising/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-principle-of-mutual-arising/</guid><description>It is basic to the Taoist view of the world that every thing-event (shì 事 or wù 物) is what it is only in relation to all others. The earth, and every tiniest thing upon it, inevitably “goes-with” the sun, moon, and stars. It needs them just as much as it needs, and consists of, its own elements.</description></item><item><title>Be like a cat and let go of yourself</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/be-like-a-cat-and-let-go-of-yourself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/be-like-a-cat-and-let-go-of-yourself/</guid><description>The more relaxed you are, the more flexible you are, the more lightly you land.
When a cat falls out of a tree, it lets go of itself. The cat becomes completely relaxed, and lands lightly on the ground. But if a cat were about to fall out of a tree and suddenly make up its mind that it didn’t want to fall, it would become tense and rigid, and would be just a bag of broken bones upon landing.</description></item><item><title>We are doing exactly what the fish are doing</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-doing-exactly-what-the-fish-are-doing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-doing-exactly-what-the-fish-are-doing/</guid><description>[[authors/david graeber|David Graeber]] says that when he taught at Yale, he would assign a reading of the following Taoist story, offering an automatic “A” to any student who could tell him why the last line made sense. (None ever succeeded.)
Zhuangzi and Huizi were strolling on a bridge over the River Hao, when the former observed, “See how the minnows dart between the rocks!</description></item></channel></rss>