<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>multiverse on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/multiverse/</link><description>Recent content in multiverse on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/multiverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beneath the Rising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/beneath-the-rising/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/beneath-the-rising/</guid><description>The coincidence of snagging this series on sale1 the night before I finished [[books/rakesfall|Rakesfall]], where [[authors/vajra chandrasekera|Vajra Chandrasekera]] names Premee Mohamed in his acknowledgments.
Indeed, it plays on similar themes, albeit in an entirely different style. Here we’ve got an action-adventure race across the continents when Johnny, young super-genius inventor/do-gooder in a kind of Greta Thurnberg mold, accidentally creates such a powerful clean energy reactor that it warps space and time and calls up eldritch gods from the deep… which she knows full well because she’s made a deal with those same gods to exchange her mortality for the fame and brains to save the world.</description></item><item><title>Ficciones</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ficciones/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ficciones/</guid><description>Borges is up to some delightful fuckery, playing with form, inventing books and authors and universes that are just as, to paraphrase, contaminated with fiction as our own history of the world. The stories are brief and vertiginous, mind-boggling and often cheeky. An undisputed masterpiece, even if I’m still partial to [[authors/italo calvino|Calvino]], even if Calvino himself would disagree with me (per his essay on Borges in [[books/six memos for the next millennium|Six Memos for the Next Millennium]]).</description></item><item><title>I’ll Miss Myself</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-miss-myself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-miss-myself/</guid><description>Ahhhhh I love finding an author where one story is SO good that I immediately acquire a new favorite author. In the span of a couple hours I’ve read his other short stories on Uncanny Mag, and started the audiobook for [[books/someone you can build a nest in|Someone You Can Build a Nest In]].</description></item></channel></rss>