<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vampiric-activity on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/vampiric-activity/</link><description>Recent content in vampiric-activity on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/vampiric-activity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iron &amp; Velvet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</guid><description>I have now done each of these in print (well, ebook, as print is sadly out of print) and each of these in audio, and all other vampire books can check themselves at the door. All other PI noirs too, for that matter.
“Yes, I was a faery-blooded, thirty-something PI with trust issues and a drinking problem, and she was a bloodthirsty undead nun with a pudding fixation, but I honestly thought we were in with a chance.</description></item><item><title>Shadows &amp; Dreams</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</guid><description>I’m almost sad I did this in audio because there are SO MANY lines I would have copy-pasted. Except the audio is SO GOOD I am not sad. I will just read it again in words-on-page form to copy-paste lines, and it will be no trial.</description></item><item><title>Fire &amp; Water</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Smoke &amp; Ashes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>In Perpetuity</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/in-perpetuity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/in-perpetuity/</guid><description>Melancholy little novella about vampires stuck out of time in our modern world, besieged by the violent noises and smells as civilization encroaches upon them. The author has written other autistic characters; it seems like he has first hand experience of the nerve-wracking world of sensory overload to render it so accurately.</description></item><item><title>The Affair of the Mysterious Letter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-affair-of-the-mysterious-letter/</guid><description>The only thing I’ve had brain space for this week is Alexis Hall, and I say that as the highest compliment. He brings so much heart, joy, and snark even when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery. Or should I say, especially when he’s writing Sherlock Holmes fanfic with jilted vampires and witch kings and interstellar chicanery.</description></item><item><title>Carmilla</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 15:13:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/carmilla/</guid><description>I suppose I should be talking about the book, but Megan Follows does the audio, so my actual takeaway is: my Megan Follows crush has not abated after 25 years. The absolute perfect choice of narrator for a gothic, queer, melodramatic, erotically-charged tale.
![[images/megan-follows-aogg.gif]]
Note: I borrowed the audiobook from the library, but I’ve marked this Lanternfish Press edition because I also sought it out solely for the Carmen Maria Machado foreword, which is excellent and should not be missed.</description></item><item><title>Fledgling</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fledgling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fledgling/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Dragon Waiting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dragon-waiting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dragon-waiting/</guid><description>“The Velvet Underground of novels,” as Scott Lynch says in the introduction. This book is a masterwork. If I ever mix up my history on the Medicis, the War of the Roses, and the Byzantine Empire, it’s probably because I’ve misremembered this fiction as fact. It’s a fascinating thought experiment, imagining how the trajectory of history would look different (or not) if Julian the Apostate had had a long, successful rule.</description></item></channel></rss>