<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>life-and-death on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/life-and-death/</link><description>Recent content in life-and-death on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/life-and-death/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>10 Things That Never Happened</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</guid><description>It’s about grief and melancholy and connection and hope; it hit me so hard in the feels I cried through the last chapters. Outstanding use of the cheesy amnesia trope, a worthy homage to While You Were Sleeping. (Sam is absolutely the British Sandra Bullock.)</description></item><item><title>The Curse of Chalion</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-curse-of-chalion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-curse-of-chalion/</guid><description>It’s been easier lately for me to review the books I don’t like than the ones I do, because the ones I do, it’s just love, love, love. And it’s often difficult to articulate why.
This is one of the above. I just loved the… gentleness of it.</description></item><item><title>Inferno</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/inferno/</guid><description>So good to read this while steeped in Florentine history. These are real people and real places, not just an abstract Lewis-esque allegory. Now I wish I knew Italian to read his terza rima original, especially since I’ve had to dig through the Longfellow to see what’s underneath.</description></item><item><title>A Thief in the Night</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-thief-in-the-night/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-thief-in-the-night/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 1</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-1/</guid><description>Back when I first read this, only the first Seven Seas volume had come out in the US. I thought I could just dip my toe in, get the gist, no harm done. I’d only read [[books/heaven official’s blessing vol 1|one other xianxia]] at that point and it was by the same author, so I’d just read others in the meantime to have more points of comparison by the time I got around to evaluating MDZS as a whole.</description></item><item><title>The Black Tides of Heaven</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-tides-of-heaven/</guid><description>Note from my future self: this makes an excellent prequel, I should have started with [[books/the red threads of fortune|book 2]]!</description></item><item><title>Too Like the Lightning</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/too-like-the-lightning/</guid><description>Of course I’m immediately starting all over again after [[books/perhaps the stars|Perhaps The Stars]]. Every time, tingling chills down my spine on page 254:
I am the window through which you watch the coming storm. He is the lightning.
I can ditto [[authors/jo walton|Jo Walton]], who says, “I love this book with the passionate love of an exploding supernova, but every book isn’t for everyone.</description></item><item><title>A Marvellous Light</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</guid><description>Fun Edwardian murder mystery. Fun world building. God save Edwin from the idiotic flower of English manhood.</description></item><item><title>Proper English</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</guid><description>It’s the House Party from Hell, and the first time I read it, I was like this is exhausting, it’s claustrophobic, not sure I can vibe with it—but then I read it again in 2020 and YES. It is a MOOD.</description></item><item><title>Gideon the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gideon-the-ninth/</guid><description>WOULD HAVE HARROWHARK’S BABIES.
I mean, it’s a good thing I like nice people in real life, because in fiction, Harrowhark is 10000% my type.
And just, 10/10 on working through your Catholic upbringing by writing meme-filled fic about blood sacrifice and redemption and necromancy and lesbian saints and cavaliers.</description></item><item><title>Shadow &amp; Claw</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadow-claw/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadow-claw/</guid><description>I think a series that has its own [[books/lexicon urthus|lexicon]] counts for the ultimate feat of [[notes/puzzle-book worldbuilding|puzzle-book worldbuilding]].</description></item><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>The Sorcerer of the Wildeeps</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sorcerer-of-the-wildeeps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-sorcerer-of-the-wildeeps/</guid><description>Whoa. Masterful use of dialect and structure to deconstruct the traditional bounds of genre and narrative. The way the characters code-switch their way through multiple registers and languages—well-known and invented—is reflected in the way the novella flips through genres like a catalog, exposing the expectations and limitations of each.</description></item><item><title>Pet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/pet/</guid><description>A YA book that discusses [[authors/hannah arendt|Hannah Arendt]] and [[books/the origins of totalitarianism|the banality of evil]] in the introduction, then goes on to drop some biblically accurate angels? YES PLEASE.</description></item><item><title>The Secret Lives of Country Gentlemen</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</guid><description>Update: Yep. [[books/a noblemans guide to seducing a scoundrel|Second book]] delivers the very necessary half of the whole. I adored it, and now I adore this one on re-read. Everything that just felt a slight step off pace the first time was solved with a deeper, closer read, and the addition of Luke’s story.</description></item><item><title>Slippery Creatures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</guid><description>My favorite KJ Charles yet.
I should probably wait till the end of the trilogy to make declarative statements, but there’s WWI spies and bookshops and gentle friendship despite odds and this is as far into my wheelhouse as you can get until, like, sheep herding or Belgium is involved.</description></item><item><title>Heaven Official’s Blessing Vol 1</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/heaven-officials-blessing-vol-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/heaven-officials-blessing-vol-1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Liberty &amp; Other Stories</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liberty-and-other-stories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liberty-and-other-stories/</guid><description>I did not think I could love the [[series/prosperityverse|Prosperityverse]] more, BUT I DO.</description></item><item><title>Paladin of Souls</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladin-of-souls/</guid><description>Magnificent. I didn’t think Bujold could top Cazaril as a character, and she does. Illvin and beloved Ista. Such a rich, full, scarred world she’s created. It spoke to me deeply, even more than the first. I cried. I felt joy-struck. Cursed, bitter Ista is also blessed, beloved Ista.</description></item><item><title>Purgatorio</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/purgatorio/</guid><description>Reading this alongside Guido Ruggiero’s [[books/the renaissance in italy|The Renaissance in Italy]] is A+ recommended. Once again, vastly more interesting than my first exposure, where school curriculum wanted it read like it was Pilgrim’s Progress. I needed the Bondanella introduction back then to dispense with the nonsense: “Such allegorical abstractions are simply not what Dante’s great poem is all about.</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 2</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Red Threads of Fortune</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:15:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-red-threads-of-fortune/</guid><description>This should have been book 1! Or I should have done my typical thing of reading out of order and started here! The one time I try to be responsible and read a series in order, this is what happens.
Technically, these are “twin novellas,” but IMO, Mokoya is the emotional core of the story, followed by Rider, and Akeha in [[books/the black tides of heaven|Black Tides]] is an interesting prequel.</description></item><item><title>A Restless Truth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-restless-truth/</guid><description>This was so close to being great. SO CLOSE. But overall, the book felt kind of like the menagerie on board the ship, let loose in all directions, refusing to be corralled. There were some structure/plot/writing choices that left me more stumped than dazzled. Maud’s and Violet’s POV seemed really interchangeable for the first half, which is&amp;hellip; not great when one is a supposedly scandalous, sardonic, shrewd actress and one is a sheltered, capricious, stubborn young girl.</description></item><item><title>The Tombs of Atuan</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-tombs-of-atuan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 15:47:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-tombs-of-atuan/</guid><description>The funny thing is, I sometimes resist reading Ursula K. Le Guin. Because I know I’ll have to stop, and do nothing else, and absorb through my pores, and not read any of the other ten or twelve things I might have read that week, and just camp out in her world as long as I can.</description></item><item><title>Husband Material</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/husband-material/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/husband-material/</guid><description>Choosing to interrogate the state of matrimony, I should have expected nothing less from Alexis Hall. I had to read this twice to really like it, because I am so urgggggh about weddings, and I needed the ending spoiled to get fully on board:
%%THEY DITCHED THEIR OWN WEDDING AT THE ALTAR WOOHOOO%%</description></item><item><title>Sword &amp; Citadel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sword-citadel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sword-citadel/</guid><description>Ugh, my [[notes/puzzle-book worldbuilding|puzzle-loving brain]] absolutely loved this. Even all the places where it was like, Gene, your Roman Catholicism is showing. And when apparently such brilliant flights of imagination can’t imagine a different role for women in the universe.
But the brilliant ideas were brilliant, and the execution thereof.</description></item><item><title>Seven Surrenders</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/seven-surrenders/</guid><description>There’s no way I can talk comprehensively about this series, so for now I’m just going to keep a running list of different things I notice each time I read them. This time (2/2023), it was how the many names for JEDD Mason echoes the [[notes/apophatic naming|apophatic naming]] of God, a classical theological strategy of the “negative” naming, an effort to call God by every time, thereby acknowledging and preserving God’s transcendence of all of them.</description></item><item><title>Harrow the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/harrow-the-ninth/</guid><description>Amount of times this book made me cry: [redacted]. It is a sum equal to or only slightly less than the amount of times it made me cackle, gasp, and yelp.
“I cannot behold that apocalypse, Harrow. I think you are one of the only Lyctors who can really and truly understand apocalypse… It is not a death of fire.</description></item><item><title>Think of England</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</guid><description>This is pulp with all the trappings—daring spies, dastardly villains, plots galore—and yet it’s so grounded in real emotion it hardly feels like pulp at all. Except for the part that’s so entertaining I devoured it in two days.
Great book. Great pairing. KJ Charles does it again.</description></item><item><title>Bitter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/bitter/</guid><description>Is this even better than [[books/pet|Pet]]? Holy crap, I think so. The struggle. The hope. The tenderness. It knocked me sideways. I love it.
Bitter had learned it was better to be stoic, to be a blank and unfeeling wall, because if you were entirely armor and no underbelly, then they couldn’t stab you in the soft places.</description></item><item><title>The Sugared Game</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</guid><description>The reason it takes me a week to read a book that I literally can’t put down is because I read it twice.
When I read [[books/slippery creatures|Slippery Creatures]], I wanted to say, this is what it looks like when an author levels up. I refrained, but I’m not going to wait til book three to say it: this is what it looks like when an author levels up.</description></item><item><title>A Nobleman’s Guide to Seducing a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>So I somehow didn’t even realize my preorder of the paperback arrived two weeks early (!!!), meaning I’ve already read this twice by the time I got the “book release day!” email this morning.
Oops.
Except not oops, because I needed the last two weeks with this book.</description></item><item><title>A Fashionable Indulgence</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</guid><description>Ditto [[books/a seditious affair|A Seditious Affair]]: first read this years ago; out of order then in order; its politics are even more relevant now. There is a refreshing lack of drama between Harry and Julius—their conflict is external—and I greatly appreciate a romance with the guts to do that.</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Strength</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-strength/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-strength/</guid><description>Oof, it pains me to say I had a tough time with this one. There was so much I liked—mainly CLARA—but it’s so unnecessarily long. Like at least a hundred pages too long because there’s so much repetition and angst and constant unresolved horniness. I love a road trip, I don’t mind a slow burn done right, but here the slow burn veers perilously close to miscommunication.</description></item><item><title>Fire &amp; Water</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Paradiso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paradiso/</guid><description>My dilemma since the early years of Sunday school: hell is more interesting than paradise. Thus, true to form, though I wanted to be contrary, [[books/inferno|Inferno]] is more interesting than any amount of heavenly light (so bright! so much dancing!), but get to that last line and you can’t help but feel the awe and poetry of it:</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 3</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Will to Battle</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-will-to-battle/</guid><description>Reader, I cried like Mycroft Canner. It’s very much the first half of a whole (third quarter of four?), and it needs [[books/perhaps the stars|the last book]] to be complete, but what a feat it is on its own.</description></item><item><title>Nona the Ninth</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nona-the-ninth/</guid><description>Verdict still stands after book three: would have Harrowhark’s babies.
The end of [[books/gideon the ninth|Gideon]] had some pacing things, the start of [[books/harrow the ninth|Harrow]] had some pacing things; Nona was the one I barreled through in 1.5 days because I could not put the book down.</description></item><item><title>Subtle Blood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</guid><description>I might have accidentally read Subtle Blood again, since I might have accidentally experienced a vivid dream of Will, Kim, Phoebe, and Maisie on a Parisian adventure (cameo by Teddy Molyneaux, of course), and upon waking, might have accidentally been distraught that that book wasn’t going to exist.</description></item><item><title>A Seditious Affair</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</guid><description>This was my first KJ Charles, purchased and read—I just looked it up—March 2017. I then read the whole series (out of order, of course), re-read this one in 2018, again in 2019, and somehow reviewed nary a one before 2020.
I feel so sentimental.</description></item><item><title>Paladin’s Hope</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-hope/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paladins-hope/</guid><description>Not me, caught up in the spookiness more than the romance. The romance was still solid, though. The audiobooks remain excellent.</description></item><item><title>Smoke &amp; Ashes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mammoths at the Gates</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mammoths-at-the-gates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:35:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/mammoths-at-the-gates/</guid><description>Our beloved cleric Chih returns home to the Singing Hills monastery, only to find (spoiler alert) mammoths at the gates, an imperial delegation come to collect one of their own. A lovely mediation on grief, change, and love, through a plot revealed as always in the layers and sediment of myth.</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 4</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-4/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Left Hand of Darkness</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid><description>Imperfect and still utterly perfect. Favorite always.
The David Mitchell foreword
Picture if you will reading this book when it was published, 1969, the year of Stonewall
Gender, sex, romance, desire, power, nationalism, oppression… they’re all just stories we tell ourselves. And we can tell different stories if we choose.</description></item><item><title>Perhaps the Stars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perhaps-the-stars/</guid><description>I still haven’t found the words to talk about this one. Maybe next year I will. It should be in the Smithsonian, or win the Nobel prize, or something, as one of humanity’s greatest achievements.</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 5</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-5/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Dispossessed</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dispossessed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dispossessed/</guid><description>Sublime. Carefully constructed, nuanced, warmly empathetic, passionately human, complex. If you want a rose-colored ideologue that purports to fix problems with simplistic utopias, look elsewhere. If you want an accounting of our society’s ills, and alternatives that are just as complicated and imperfect, you’re in the right place.</description></item><item><title>A Sorceress Comes to Call</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-sorceress-comes-to-call/</guid><description>I’m here all day long for T. Kingfisher’s aging, aching protagonists, with bad knees and big hearts and a well-honed sense of doom. The plot is a very loose retelling of The Goose Girl, minus princesses and kings and plus a conniving, murderous, sorceress mother. Evangeline, aka Doom, is determined to marry herself and her trapped, obedient daughter to the highest bidders in proper Regency-esque fashion, plans thwarted when she encounters a squire’s spinster sister who sees her for exactly who she is.</description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/nettle-and-bone/</guid><description>So this is everything a fairy tale should be. The only thing that didn’t work for me 100% was the romance side plot, but it was very sweet nonetheless, and I do understand that’s a common ingredient in fairy tales, and that for most it would be necessary.</description></item><item><title>Among Others</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/among-others/</guid><description>“[[notes/bibliotropic|Bibliotropic]],” Hugh said. “Like sunflowers are heliotropic, they naturally turn towards the sun. We naturally turn towards the bookshop.”
Where do I begin? What is this book about? Books, yes. A love of books and of libraries. Books as lifeline and language. It’s about a girl growing up, and witches and fairies and boarding schools and grief and Wales and loneliness even amongst those with whom you might belong.</description></item><item><title>Murder Most Actual</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/murder-most-actual/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/murder-most-actual/</guid><description>Speaking of [[books/proper english|sapphic murder house mysteries]], Alexis Hall has the contemporary version on lock.
There are few things I like more than an established relationship romance—so very difficult to do well—and here it’s a marriage very naturally on the rocks for very relatable, natural reasons, just the living of life and complexities that ensue.</description></item><item><title>Spokes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spokes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spokes/</guid><description>Nooooo. I thought I had finally found the holy grail, cycling fiction (nay, romance!) that gets the cycling facts correct. The dedication is to Wouter Weylandt(!), there’s a glossary of French terms and race classifications, and four pages in she’s name-dropping Garmin-Sharp and Fausto Coppi. My expectations, below sea level, started to gain elevation.</description></item><item><title>The Last of the Wine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-last-of-the-wine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-last-of-the-wine/</guid><description>So very good. Here I was thinking the writing style kept me at a remove from the story and I wasn’t as invested as I could be, and then the last two chapters walloped me in the gut and I realized it had me at the emotional level after all.</description></item><item><title>A Woman Is No Man</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-woman-is-no-man/</guid><description>We need more books by Palestinian and Arab authors. I intend to read more by Etaf Rum. But it pains me to say… I think this could have been a (powerful) short story. The structure and even dialogue is very repetitive, in a way that I’m sure is meant to illustrate the cyclical and generational cycle of abuse, but instead means you could skim chapters and not miss anything.</description></item><item><title>Come Out, Come Out</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</guid><description>In the same niche as [[books/camp damascus|Camp Damascus]], the conversion-therapy-as-horror genre. Similarities abound, even down to the senior class quarry jumps, which doesn’t indicate any co-opting of plot points but simply how ubiquitous this experience is, the same script across rural America, where any deviation from the script means there will be Consequences.</description></item><item><title>The Spirit Ring</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-spirit-ring/</guid><description>Sometimes when things connect, they really connect. I picked this up because I was ready for another Bujold, and this is what the library had, and what is right there when I open it up? Renaissance Italy! Borgias, Florentines; Sforzas, Medicis; Guelphs and Ghibellines.
Three true things: it’s a gem in the rough; Thur is my boy; every Bujold, even vintage Bujold, is the best Bujold.</description></item><item><title>Lent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:55:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lent/</guid><description>It seems like every year there’s a book that I want to beg people to read because I struggle to describe it, and it’s nothing like what they’d expect. This year, it’s this book.
It’s beautiful. It’s delightful and unusual and quietly profound. It’s a master class in plot.</description></item><item><title>Decameron</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/decameron/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/decameron/</guid><description>Hey, remember way back when there was this pandemic happening? This was good reading during it.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso/</guid><description>A note on translation: I used Reynolds to compare, contrast, and fill in the gaps with the [[books/orlando furioso a new verse translation|Slavitt translation]]. Slavitt takes liberties, and Reynolds has merit, but I’ve got to say, for compulsive readability, and cheeky irreverence that feels like it honors the spirit of the original, Slavitt it is.</description></item><item><title>Orlando Furioso: A New Verse Translation</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/orlando-furioso-a-new-verse-translation/</guid><description>Ariosto writing like AO3 was a thing in the sixteenth century. I love it. Fiendishly clever layers of satire; a story where anything goes.</description></item><item><title>Spear</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Road to San Giovanni</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-road-to-san-giovanni/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-road-to-san-giovanni/</guid><description>I have missed Calvino.</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/thornhedge/</guid><description>Aaaah the greenteeth! Toadling! A knight to the rescue that I don’t want to punch in the throat! But the GREENTEETH!
Pull quotes Another fairy might have played up their status as exiled healer, demanded special treatment and catering to their every whim. But Toadling tried to be helpful and stammered when she was nervous and had beautiful, worried eyes in a homely face.</description></item><item><title>Blackouts</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/blackouts/</guid><description>All the different layers of meaning to the title—the blackouts our narrator experiences due to PTSD, the blackouts of Juan and his fading memory, the failure of institutional memory, the queer erasure from history, the literal blackouts of the pages of the book. It feels like a work of art, not just a novel.</description></item><item><title>The Fox Wife</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-fox-wife/</guid><description>Not the right choice to follow Nghi Vo’s [[books/the brides of high hill|fox-spirit tale]]. Atmospheric, but I feel talked down to and everything is over-explained. This is why I like sticking to genre for Asian fantasy instead of litfic. DNF @ pg 60. (I did flip through the rest because the hardcover had wide margins for sidenotes, but there were… barely any?</description></item><item><title>Yellowface</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/yellowface/</guid><description>After witnessing the accidental death of her frenemy Athena Liu, failed author June Hayward refashions herself as Juniper Song and steals Athena’s posthumous masterpiece to pass it off as her own. Cue white woman tears, as she’s victimized and vilified by the consequences of her own egregious actions.</description></item><item><title>The Black Jersey</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</guid><description>It takes until page 280 for the main character to say, “I am an imbecile,” which is the truest thing in the book.
Oh boy. So many feelings. That are conflicted. Is this a book about cycling? Yes. Do I love cycling? Yes. Do I love books about cycling?</description></item><item><title>The Saint of Bright Doors</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-saint-of-bright-doors/</guid><description>Gobsmacked at how good this is, without even the caveat of “for a first novel.” Fetter, the feral only child of a messiah, trained by his mother as assassin, destined to commit matricide and fratricide, navigates a dystopian Sri Lanka far too recognizable in the present.</description></item><item><title>Clear and Muddy Loss of Love</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/clear-and-muddy-loss-of-love/</guid><description>This is just what I was in the mood for, a 300+ chapter, 4000 page sapphic slow burn court intrigue. The prose (and/or translation?) is more functional than beautiful on a sentence level, but on a plot level, with the overall character arcs, QJMX has some mad skill.</description></item><item><title>The Chosen and the Beautiful</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-chosen-and-the-beautiful/</guid><description>As someone who has long loved [[authors/f scott fitzgerald|F. Scott Fitzgerald]]’s writing, despite his depressing and often problematic deal, this [[books/the great gatsby|Gatsby]] retelling vis-à-vis a Vietnamese Jordan Baker is exquisite. Absolutely true to the spirit of the original, while absolutely its own fantastical, queer, eerie, spectacular thing.</description></item><item><title>The Magic Fish</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-magic-fish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 15:55:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-magic-fish/</guid><description>Wow. Absolutely lovely. Destroyed me in the best way.
And just on a visual level, what Nguyen does with the coloring for the different timelines, and the extensive notes on historical fashion and mythological context in the afterword make me appreciate it even more.</description></item><item><title>Three Kings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/three-kings/</guid><description>Another for my collection of killer opening lines:
Ethan Shaw carried two knives, one for lilies, the other for veins.
And the book just gets better and better from there. It counters all my usual problems with cozy witchy books, and sometimes cozy fantasy in general, not to mention the fraught subject of fertility.</description></item><item><title>Everyone in This Room Will Someday Be Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:21:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</guid><description>This is the most strongly coded [[notes/autism|autistic]] protagonist I’ve read. Especially of the female, high-masking, chronic burnout variety, and undiagnosed. (Or rather, insufficiently diagnosed with anxiety and depression.) The unconscious stimming! Chronic sensory overload! The shutdowns! The meltdowns! The masking!
I feel like I am operating my body like it’s a vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Aspects</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/aspects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/aspects/</guid><description>The poignancy of having this one cut off, incomplete. What a feat it would have been. What a feat it still is. The [[notes/puzzle-book worldbuilding|worldbuilding]] is out of this world.</description></item><item><title>China Mountain Zhang</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/china-mountain-zhang/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Interesting Facts about Space</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</guid><description>Me [page 1]: I’m worried I read too much about [[notes/autism|ASD]] into [[books/everyone in this room will someday be dead|Everyone in This Room Will Someday be Dead]]. This time I’m gonna look for all the ways it’s not autism. I will counteract my bias.
Me [page 20]: This is autism.</description></item><item><title>The Great Gatsby</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-great-gatsby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-great-gatsby/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Word for World is Forest</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-word-for-world-is-forest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-word-for-world-is-forest/</guid><description>This is how I like a thinly-veiled parable to work, especially an anti-colonialism one.
(There’s barely any need for fiction; it’s Vietnam.)</description></item><item><title>Camp Damascus</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/camp-damascus/</guid><description>I had to wait until I was in a good headspace to handle this. Ruth, an autistic devout Christian on the cusp of adulthood, begins to realize everything in her life is not as it seems, not even herself. Cue the horror of religious trauma and conversion therapy camps, right at home with the traditional trappings of the horror genre.</description></item><item><title>The Henchmen of Zenda</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-henchmen-of-zenda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-henchmen-of-zenda/</guid><description>When KJ Charles is on, she’s on. This book is all the things: fun, ridiculous, hilarious, swashbuckling, hot, FUN. The high pulp style suits her so well because she can pack the book full of joy and all the sneering and sniding she likes to write works because it’s comic and joyful.</description></item><item><title>A Governess’s Guide to Passion and Peril</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-governesss-guide-to-passion-and-peril/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-governesss-guide-to-passion-and-peril/</guid><description>The fourth in a series, and I read at least one of the first three during the fugue state years when my dad’s health was failing, so I have only the haziest memory of it. That might mean I’m missing something, as it never felt explained in the text why the other women hadn’t come to Jane’s aid before now, nor why Jane’s feelings for Adrian would evolve beyond a schoolgirl crush.</description></item><item><title>Giovanni’s Room</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/giovannis-room/</guid><description>Not everyone in book club was a fan, but I loved it, but it was brutal, but I’m glad I read it, but I’m glad I won’t be in a rush to read it again.
“Somebody,” said Jacques, “your father or mine, should have told us that not many people have ever died of love.</description></item></channel></rss>