<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cycling on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/cycling/</link><description>Recent content in cycling on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/cycling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Cyclist and His Shadow</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cyclist-and-his-shadow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-cyclist-and-his-shadow/</guid><description>I like how right away, in the forward, Thomazeau François is pitting this book against [[books/the rider|The Rider]] as the seminal classic of cycling literature. I arched a skeptical eyebrow, and… was in total agreement by like, chapter 3.
Brilliant. Insane. Philosophical. Spiritual. Erotic. I read it during the nearly-hallucinatory six hours of Milan—San Remo and feel like bits of it have embedded in my brain like gravel, because I think of it every time I watch a race.</description></item><item><title>Spokes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spokes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/spokes/</guid><description>Nooooo. I thought I had finally found the holy grail, cycling fiction (nay, romance!) that gets the cycling facts correct. The dedication is to Wouter Weylandt(!), there’s a glossary of French terms and race classifications, and four pages in she’s name-dropping Garmin-Sharp and Fausto Coppi. My expectations, below sea level, started to gain elevation.</description></item><item><title>Racing to You</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/racing-to-you/</guid><description>“Has someone written a romance about pro cycling?” was something I wondered last week. And voila, this book.
It actually:
Has some legit knowledge of cycling! Addresses doping as a plot point Addresses the extremely monastic and high-pressure lifestyle Gets the team dynamic! Has real races like Paris-Nice!</description></item><item><title>The Black Jersey</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-black-jersey/</guid><description>It takes until page 280 for the main character to say, “I am an imbecile,” which is the truest thing in the book.
Oh boy. So many feelings. That are conflicted. Is this a book about cycling? Yes. Do I love cycling? Yes. Do I love books about cycling?</description></item><item><title>The Rider</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rider/</guid><description>My dear friend Karen made sure I got this book for an October gift, and since pro cycling is currently trying to do a nine month season in two months, including three grand tours, why not pile on some more and make this my cycling read of the (Covid-shortened) season?</description></item></channel></rss>