<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kinky-books on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/kinky-books/</link><description>Recent content in kinky-books on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/kinky-books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Bang a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-bang-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-bang-a-billionaire/</guid><description>Ugh, billionaires! I love Arden as much as I ugh Caspian. Which I think is the point at this point. Fifty Shades of Gray fanfic at its finest.</description></item><item><title>Iron &amp; Velvet</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/iron-and-velvet/</guid><description>I have now done each of these in print (well, ebook, as print is sadly out of print) and each of these in audio, and all other vampire books can check themselves at the door. All other PI noirs too, for that matter.
“Yes, I was a faery-blooded, thirty-something PI with trust issues and a drinking problem, and she was a bloodthirsty undead nun with a pudding fixation, but I honestly thought we were in with a chance.</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 1</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:40:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-1/</guid><description>Back when I first read this, only the first Seven Seas volume had come out in the US. I thought I could just dip my toe in, get the gist, no harm done. I’d only read [[books/heaven official’s blessing vol 1|one other xianxia]] at that point and it was by the same author, so I’d just read others in the meantime to have more points of comparison by the time I got around to evaluating MDZS as a whole.</description></item><item><title>The Ruin of Gabriel Ashleigh</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ruin-of-gabriel-ashleigh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ruin-of-gabriel-ashleigh/</guid><description>Why yes, I’m re-reading the whole series in order, even the miscellany. Probably my least favorite of the lot, but only due to how much I like the others. I still endorse it completely, because if you’re gonna play cards, play them for keeps.</description></item><item><title>How to Blow It with a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-blow-it-with-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-blow-it-with-a-billionaire/</guid><description>It’s a testament to Hall’s writing that I’m still enjoying a series where my primary thought is: Arden! Ditch Caspian!</description></item><item><title>Shadows &amp; Dreams</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shadows-and-dreams/</guid><description>I’m almost sad I did this in audio because there are SO MANY lines I would have copy-pasted. Except the audio is SO GOOD I am not sad. I will just read it again in words-on-page form to copy-paste lines, and it will be no trial.</description></item><item><title>The Gentle Art of Fortune Hunting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-gentle-art-of-fortune-hunting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-gentle-art-of-fortune-hunting/</guid><description>So sweet! Will read again, because I felt I read it too quickly. (And kind of wanted way more of the roleplay/pretext stuff&amp;hellip;.)</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 2</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Think of England</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</guid><description>This is pulp with all the trappings—daring spies, dastardly villains, plots galore—and yet it’s so grounded in real emotion it hardly feels like pulp at all. Except for the part that’s so entertaining I devoured it in two days.
Great book. Great pairing. KJ Charles does it again.</description></item><item><title>Any Old Diamonds</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/any-old-diamonds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/any-old-diamonds/</guid><description>As KJC says: In which we stick it to a duke.
What [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] was to 2018, Any Old Diamonds is to 2019. It’s SO good. An instant favorite. I might have to re-read both to decide which one I like best, and if it’s too close to call, which only means I should read them a third and fourth time, I won’t mind a bit.</description></item><item><title>A Nobleman’s Guide to Seducing a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>So I somehow didn’t even realize my preorder of the paperback arrived two weeks early (!!!), meaning I’ve already read this twice by the time I got the “book release day!” email this morning.
Oops.
Except not oops, because I needed the last two weeks with this book.</description></item><item><title>How to Belong with a Billionaire</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-belong-with-a-billionaire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:14:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-belong-with-a-billionaire/</guid><description>If there’s an author who could get me to love books with billionaire in the title, it’s Alexis Hall. Just like if there’s an author who could get me to love books with duke in the title, it’s going to be Alexis Hall’s [[books/a lady for a duke|upcoming historical romance]].</description></item><item><title>Fire &amp; Water</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/fire-and-water/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Something Extraordinary</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</guid><description>The high-strung Belle has left behind her heroine era, and the drama-prone Rufus has left behind his Sir Horley Comewithers era. Together they embark on the worst elopement kidnapping elopement in history (per Belle, it’s not vainglorious to claim that when it’s true), and what ensues is a meditation on friendship, love, sexuality, identity, self-discovery, society, and home in a way that only Alexis Hall can do it.</description></item><item><title>The Duke at Hazard</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</guid><description>I have a few auto-buy (auto-preorder) authors, but KJ Charles is the only one where I drop everything to start reading the day a new book comes out. Here, that impatience is rewarded with a tender, slow-blooming romance-on-the-run between Daizell, a disgraced non-scoundrel scoundrel (he’s paying for the sins of his father), and Cassian, aka The Duke, aka Vernon Fortescue Cassian George de Vere Crosse, the fourth Duke of Severn, the Earl of Harmsford, Baron Crosse of Wotton, and Baron Vere, who’s incognito for a month to hunt down a thief and win a wager (he’s burdened with the premature inheritance of his father’s title).</description></item><item><title>A Power Unbound</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 22:28:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-power-unbound/</guid><description>Here is my theory from [[books/a restless truth|book 2]]: the Blyths suit me best in small doses. Robin and Maud, respectively, were the most difficult parts of their own books for me. They’re just so young, energetic, athletic, upstanding, so shiny, so beautiful, so aggressively… “normal,” for lack of a better word, when I prefer crankiness and weariness and a bit of tarnish on the bronze these days.</description></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 3</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Seditious Affair</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</guid><description>This was my first KJ Charles, purchased and read—I just looked it up—March 2017. I then read the whole series (out of order, of course), re-read this one in 2018, again in 2019, and somehow reviewed nary a one before 2020.
I feel so sentimental.</description></item><item><title>For Real</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/for-real/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/for-real/</guid><description>Re-read, for the new annotated print edition. And let me tell you, just when I thought one of my favorite romances could not get better, the annotations add a new layer. Dare I say, much as I enjoyed them, the annotations in [[books/glitterland|Glitterland]] felt… superfluous? In [[books/waiting for the flood|Waiting for the Flood]] and [[books/chasing the light|Chasing the Light]], they were a welcome addition to help stitch the old half of the story with the new.</description></item><item><title>Smoke &amp; Ashes</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/smoke-and-ashes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 4</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-4/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Grandmaster of Demonic Cultivation Vol 5</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/grandmaster-of-demonic-cultivation-vol-5/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Freak Pleasures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/freak-pleasures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/freak-pleasures/</guid><description>Now this is protest art. Specifically, the protest of SESTA/FOSTA and the censorship it entails, not to mention the way it endangers those it purports to protect.
Available here: https://claystorks.itch.io/freak-pleasures</description></item><item><title>Juliette</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/juliette/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/juliette/</guid><description>I rarely do this, but there’s another review that says it so well, I’m going to quote it instead of trying to sum up my own thoughts:
Sade the philosopher is in force, and his treatises — like his other novels delivered by key characters — are interspersed with the sex and violence one expects.</description></item><item><title>Justine, Philosophy in the Bedroom, and Other Writings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/justine-philosophy-in-the-bedroom-and-other-writings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/justine-philosophy-in-the-bedroom-and-other-writings/</guid><description>Thank you, [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]]. I had my suspicions about Sade, that more was going on than just some shock and awe erotica, and in [[books/too like the lightning|Too Like The Lightning]], when he becomes part of the dialogue in a key way, she makes it clear that to read Sade as sadism is too narrow a view.</description></item><item><title>Origin Story</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/origin-story/</guid><description>If I had to comp this title, it’s like when I discovered Matt Dean, a talented writer self-publishing better litfic than 80% of the market, yet in a way that would earn rejections from most if not all of the big 5 and their imprints, as it’s not easily marketable as one thing or another.</description></item><item><title>Kink</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kink/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kink/</guid><description>A letdown. Overall, it’s a bit “disaffected millennials discover kink,” and I enjoy so much more when it’s kink in romance, erotica, or even fanfic, where the outcome is joy and unexpected discoveries and a healthy relationship to yourself and others, not disconnection and ennui.</description></item><item><title>The Dominance Playbook</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dominance-playbook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-dominance-playbook/</guid><description>There’s a wealth of good relationship knowledge hidden in here, apart from any kink or power play stuff, like: [[notes/abuse is best recognized by the effect it has on the abused|Abuse is best recognized by the effect it has on the abused]].
In fact, he has a list of questions to ask yourself when you’re involved in any type of relationship, and I’m gonna recap it here, because it should be mandatory reading, and deserves a much wider audience than people reading kink books:</description></item><item><title>The Good Life</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-good-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:56:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-good-life/</guid><description>Man takes [[books/the great gatsby|The Great Gatsby]] as a how-to manual, right down to the narcissism and body count, just with more explicit gay sex. (As in, Gatsby the way the good lord intended.) It’s unpleasant to read in the way obscene wealth always is, but it’s beautifully structured and compellingly written, an interesting artifact of both the era in which it’s set and when it’s written.</description></item><item><title>Decameron</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/decameron/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:34:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/decameron/</guid><description>Hey, remember way back when there was this pandemic happening? This was good reading during it.</description></item><item><title>Kushiel’s Dart</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kushiels-dart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 23:49:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kushiels-dart/</guid><description>My semi-decennial attempt to finish this book. I made it farther this time, with determination, but despite an attempt every three to five years, I still bounce off it like a rubber ball. Taboo, kink, AND court intrigue in the same book?! This should be exactly my thing!</description></item><item><title>Small Favors</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/small-favors/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:10:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/small-favors/</guid><description>Haaaaa, this was so FUN. And hot. And silly. I loved the manifesto introduction by Kelly Sue Deconnick about the power of play and the radical defiance of silliness, how it’s like lowering a rope in a dark well that saves the people at both ends.</description></item><item><title>Exodus 20</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:55:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/exodus-20/</guid><description>If you’re gonna write monster kink, make it a biblically accurate angel. And throw in some searing social/political/theological commentary. This was excellent.</description></item><item><title>Unreal Sex</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unreal-sex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unreal-sex/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>