<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>middle-east on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/middle-east/</link><description>Recent content in middle-east on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/middle-east/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Adventures of Amina al-Sirafi</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-adventures-of-amina-al-sirafi/</guid><description>A rollicking pirate adventure AND an extensive bibliography for the historical accuracies! Be still my heart! This was brilliant. It would be easier to make a list of the things I didn’t like about it than all the things I loved. The things I didn’t like: zero.</description></item><item><title>Forest of Noise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/forest-of-noise/</guid><description>How do you write the unimaginable? How do you craft art from the horror? How do you count your loved ones, now dead, in lines of poems?
I read this twice, once fast, once slow, and let it break me. 50 years of occupation and apartheid.</description></item><item><title>On Palestine</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-palestine/</guid><description>Many of the world’s problems are so intractable that it’s hard to think of ways even to take steps toward mitigating them.
The Israel-Palestine conflict is not one of these.
I admit I’ve fallen prey to the line, re: the occupation of Palestine, “it’s too complex to understand.</description></item><item><title>Dirty Wars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/dirty-wars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/dirty-wars/</guid><description>[Insert string of obscenities] at the things the United States has done. The best thing this book does is make it perfectly clear there isn’t right-wing or left-wing. It spans two crucial presidencies (Bush II and Obama), and the substantive difference is that the former worried how far they could push things and the latter did not care.</description></item><item><title>Amazing Asia</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/amazing-asia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/amazing-asia/</guid><description>The “explain it like I’m 5” primer that more people beyond the age of 5 could appreciate. It’s more thorough, interesting, and engaging than what got taught in school, that’s for sure.
ARC kindly provided by the publisher via NetGalley in exchange for an honest review.</description></item><item><title>On History</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-history/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/on-history/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Propaganda Blitz</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/propaganda-blitz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:44:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/propaganda-blitz/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lessons from Cruising</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/lessons-from-cruising/</guid><description>Joke’s on me, because I picked up this ARC for the last story, a retelling of Billy Budd from Captain Vere’s point of view. I figured I’d sample the rest; instead I went down the buffet line and inhaled them all. Rarely do I like every story in a short story collection, but that’s what Goodman’s done to me.</description></item><item><title>Shattered Spear</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shattered-spear/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 22:00:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/shattered-spear/</guid><description>Such a powerful example of what comics/graphic novels can do, with images more than words. I loved it. And more fiction of any kind set in the neolithic middle east, please.
Available from the author here, name your own price: https://claystorks.itch.io/shattered-spear</description></item><item><title>The Twice-Drowned Saint</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-twice-drowned-saint/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 15:15:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-twice-drowned-saint/</guid><description>I don’t even know how the hell to describe this, except amazing. Apparently my unintentional theme lately is biblically accurate angels—see [[books/pet|Pet]], see [[books/exodus 20|Freydís Moon]]. Here, Cooney made the mythology its own thing and the worldbuilding is fiendishly clever. A refugee crisis in the midst of a celestial city with bloodthirsty angels who must be overthrown by two secret saints, a newly-sprouted godhead, and a family of filmmakers and waste collectors—that’s the best stab I can take at the plot.</description></item><item><title>I’ll Have What He’s Having</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/ill-have-what-hes-having/</guid><description>I’m glad the term tonic masculinity has been making the rounds, because this feels like tonic masculinity of the highest order. David Curtis, sommelier, mistakes Farzan Alavi for a food critic, and what blooms in the wake of this mixup is a tender, sexy, heartfelt romance between two grown adults who have to deal with the obstacles that a grown-ass relationship entails.</description></item></channel></rss>