<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>taboo on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/taboo/</link><description>Recent content in taboo on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/taboo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gothic Tales</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gothic-tales/</guid><description>Turns out I’ve read most of these stories before, but it makes sense to repackage them here for their gothic themes and add a pleasing cover. My hope springs eternal, with each new edition, that Sade gets placed in his rightful political context, his radical philosophy that’s more dangerous than any pornography.</description></item><item><title>Juliette</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/juliette/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/juliette/</guid><description>I rarely do this, but there’s another review that says it so well, I’m going to quote it instead of trying to sum up my own thoughts:
Sade the philosopher is in force, and his treatises — like his other novels delivered by key characters — are interspersed with the sex and violence one expects.</description></item><item><title>Justine, Philosophy in the Bedroom, and Other Writings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/justine-philosophy-in-the-bedroom-and-other-writings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/justine-philosophy-in-the-bedroom-and-other-writings/</guid><description>Thank you, [[authors/ada palmer|Ada Palmer]]. I had my suspicions about Sade, that more was going on than just some shock and awe erotica, and in [[books/too like the lightning|Too Like The Lightning]], when he becomes part of the dialogue in a key way, she makes it clear that to read Sade as sadism is too narrow a view.</description></item><item><title>Kink</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kink/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kink/</guid><description>A letdown. Overall, it’s a bit “disaffected millennials discover kink,” and I enjoy so much more when it’s kink in romance, erotica, or even fanfic, where the outcome is joy and unexpected discoveries and a healthy relationship to yourself and others, not disconnection and ennui.</description></item><item><title>Perv</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/perv/</guid><description>For the longest time, to be a pervert wasn’t to be a sex deviant; it was to be an atheist Almost overnight, “pervert” goes from “immoral religious heretic” to “immoral sexual deviant” because Havelock Ellis The [[notes/naturalistic fallacy|naturalistic fallacy]] of polyamory, homosexuality, etc. (a rebuttal to [[books/sex at dawn|Sex at Dawn]]) Instead of “natural” or “unnatural”: Is it harmful?</description></item></channel></rss>