<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mental-health on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/mental-health/</link><description>Recent content in mental-health on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rosaline Palmer Takes the Cake</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rosaline-palmer-takes-the-cake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rosaline-palmer-takes-the-cake/</guid><description>I laughed. I cried. I have a therapist now. How many books can do that, AND homage the hell out of the Great British Bake Off?
Rosaline Palmer does take the cake.</description></item><item><title>The Love Remedy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:35:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</guid><description>I noped out hard at the kiss during a panic attack(!!!), and it never won me back. I did skim through the rest to find out whodunnit, which means I was annoyed by whodunnit (it’s just nonsensical based on the characterization within the book!), with bonus annoyance that there’s some minor kinkiness (yay blindfolds!</description></item><item><title>Glitterland</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/glitterland/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:43:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/glitterland/</guid><description>Give me any book where the hero is not conventional hero material, and is devalued by the world, and is the best person in the world anyway, and is unashamed to be themselves, and makes molehills out of mountains because they love freely and completely. I cried through the whole end because I am a marshmallow with a weakness for glitter pirates from Essex.</description></item><item><title>Paris Daillencourt is About to Crumble</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</guid><description>Once again Alexis Hall takes away the book I thought I wanted and replaces it with the book I actually need.
Reading this at the same time as [[books/the body keeps the score|The Body Keeps the Score]], though, just means I’m peeking between the lines of all the parental neglect and trauma and thinking, dearest Paris, get thee to some somatic therapy, medication is just a start.</description></item><item><title>Chinese Medicine for the Mind</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/chinese-medicine-for-the-mind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/chinese-medicine-for-the-mind/</guid><description>Receiving the ARC for this one did its trick—I ordered a copy once it was published. The sections on insomnia, anxiety (shaking exercise!), and trauma are especially helpful. Instead of isolating a few neurochemicals, it approaches the body and mind as a whole.
(Note: the type is quite small in the print edition.</description></item><item><title>Liars</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/liars/</guid><description>Brilliant, merciless, couldn’t put it down. Jane marries John (Bridges, but might as well be Doe, for all the universality implied), and misery ensues as John exploits his masculine privilege and his own insecurities to make Jane’s life hell.
Written as autofiction with a dash of crime fiction, it’s an autopsy of a 21st century marriage between two (eventually wealthy) white straight people, who are best placed to reap the benefits of modern feminism and equality, and instead expose the grotesque flaws and inequalities.</description></item><item><title>Wintering</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</guid><description>DNF due to the health scare(s) both May and her husband experience at the beginning of the book. Even though I knew they were okay, it was too much to relive in the moment, my own recent family health scares too fresh. I skimmed ahead to see if I could just skip that part, but multiple other chapters failed to grab me.</description></item><item><title>Everyone in This Room Will Someday Be Dead</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:21:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead/</guid><description>This is the most strongly coded [[notes/autism|autistic]] protagonist I’ve read. Especially of the female, high-masking, chronic burnout variety, and undiagnosed. (Or rather, insufficiently diagnosed with anxiety and depression.) The unconscious stimming! Chronic sensory overload! The shutdowns! The meltdowns! The masking!
I feel like I am operating my body like it’s a vehicle.</description></item><item><title>Interesting Facts about Space</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/interesting-facts-about-space/</guid><description>Me [page 1]: I’m worried I read too much about [[notes/autism|ASD]] into [[books/everyone in this room will someday be dead|Everyone in This Room Will Someday be Dead]]. This time I’m gonna look for all the ways it’s not autism. I will counteract my bias.
Me [page 20]: This is autism.</description></item><item><title>The Body Keeps the Score</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-body-keeps-the-score/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 12:00:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-body-keeps-the-score/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Consolations</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/consolations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/consolations/</guid><description>Re-read 11/24 – 12/24.
I picked this up last month after [[books/forest of noise|Forest of Noise]], when a full year of ongoing genocide seemed to pass without fanfare. Despair is a necessary and seasonal state of repair, Whyte writes. It takes us in when we have nowhere else to go; when we feel the heart cannot break anymore.</description></item><item><title>Health Communism</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/health-communism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/health-communism/</guid><description/></item><item><title>I’m Sorry for My Loss</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/im-sorry-for-my-loss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/im-sorry-for-my-loss/</guid><description>I know a book is going to be good when it starts off with the way language limits or distorts our understanding of a subject. Recommended to absolutely anyone, with or without a uterus, with or without the intention to procreate. It’s ostensibly about pregnancy loss and miscarriage/stillbirth awareness, but that overlaps with many things—abortion, grief, medical misogyny, racial injustice, human rights.</description></item></channel></rss>