<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>london on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/london/</link><description>Recent content in london on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/london/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Rat-Catcher’s Daughter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</guid><description>Very sweet and dare I say necessary before [[books/gilded cage|Gilded Cage]]. It has some pretty key context. And come on—that title.</description></item><item><title>The Ruin of Gabriel Ashleigh</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ruin-of-gabriel-ashleigh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ruin-of-gabriel-ashleigh/</guid><description>Why yes, I’m re-reading the whole series in order, even the miscellany. Probably my least favorite of the lot, but only due to how much I like the others. I still endorse it completely, because if you’re gonna play cards, play them for keeps.</description></item><item><title>Slippery Creatures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</guid><description>My favorite KJ Charles yet.
I should probably wait till the end of the trilogy to make declarative statements, but there’s WWI spies and bookshops and gentle friendship despite odds and this is as far into my wheelhouse as you can get until, like, sheep herding or Belgium is involved.</description></item><item><title>10 Things That Never Happened</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/10-things-that-never-happened/</guid><description>It’s about grief and melancholy and connection and hope; it hit me so hard in the feels I cried through the last chapters. Outstanding use of the cheesy amnesia trope, a worthy homage to While You Were Sleeping. (Sam is absolutely the British Sandra Bullock.)</description></item><item><title>A Lady’s Guide to Fortune-Hunting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-fortune-hunting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-ladys-guide-to-fortune-hunting/</guid><description>I didn’t love this quite as much as [[books/a lady&amp;rsquo;s guide to scandal|book two]]. (Read them out of order, oops!) Lots of promise, but I think the difference in POV—floating omniscient instead of tight third—didn’t work quite as well for me, possibly because it’s such a high bar of difficulty, possibly because it’s much closer to Jane Austen’s voice, which means the differences in quality are glaring.</description></item><item><title>A Marvellous Light</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-marvellous-light/</guid><description>Fun Edwardian murder mystery. Fun world building. God save Edwin from the idiotic flower of English manhood.</description></item><item><title>Boyfriend Material</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/boyfriend-material/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/boyfriend-material/</guid><description>I’m doing a reading challenge for the local library and need “a book that became a movie” for bingo, and how I wish this book qualified because, if Hollywood knew what they were doing, it should be optioned and filmed before I finish this sentence.</description></item><item><title>Glitterland</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/glitterland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/glitterland/</guid><description>Give me any book where the hero is not conventional hero material, and is devalued by the world, and is the best person in the world anyway, and is unashamed to be themselves, and makes molehills out of mountains because they love freely and completely. I cried through the whole end because I am a marshmallow with a weakness for glitter pirates from Essex.</description></item><item><title>The Love Remedy</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-love-remedy/</guid><description>I noped out hard at the kiss during a panic attack(!!!), and it never won me back. I did skim through the rest to find out whodunnit, which means I was annoyed by whodunnit (it’s just nonsensical based on the characterization within the book!), with bonus annoyance that there’s some minor kinkiness (yay blindfolds!</description></item><item><title>The Sugared Game</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</guid><description>The reason it takes me a week to read a book that I literally can’t put down is because I read it twice.
When I read [[books/slippery creatures|Slippery Creatures]], I wanted to say, this is what it looks like when an author levels up. I refrained, but I’m not going to wait til book three to say it: this is what it looks like when an author levels up.</description></item><item><title>A Fashionable Indulgence</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</guid><description>Ditto [[books/a seditious affair|A Seditious Affair]]: first read this years ago; out of order then in order; its politics are even more relevant now. There is a refreshing lack of drama between Harry and Julius—their conflict is external—and I greatly appreciate a romance with the guts to do that.</description></item><item><title>Husband Material</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/husband-material/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/husband-material/</guid><description>Choosing to interrogate the state of matrimony, I should have expected nothing less from Alexis Hall. I had to read this twice to really like it, because I am so urgggggh about weddings, and I needed the ending spoiled to get fully on board:
%%THEY DITCHED THEIR OWN WEDDING AT THE ALTAR WOOHOOO%%</description></item><item><title>Subtle Blood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</guid><description>I might have accidentally read Subtle Blood again, since I might have accidentally experienced a vivid dream of Will, Kim, Phoebe, and Maisie on a Parisian adventure (cameo by Teddy Molyneaux, of course), and upon waking, might have accidentally been distraught that that book wasn’t going to exist.</description></item><item><title>Gilded Cage</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gilded-cage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gilded-cage/</guid><description>Yes, this is Susan Lazarus from [[series/sins of the cities|Sins of the Cities]]. I love a prickly, ruthless heroine. I love jewel thieves and morality that is questionable at best. I love all that the most. This one didn’t quite click all the way with me despite all of the above, so I will be revisiting to see what I missed.</description></item><item><title>A Seditious Affair</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</guid><description>This was my first KJ Charles, purchased and read—I just looked it up—March 2017. I then read the whole series (out of order, of course), re-read this one in 2018, again in 2019, and somehow reviewed nary a one before 2020.
I feel so sentimental.</description></item><item><title>There Will Be Phlogiston</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/there-will-be-phlogiston/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/there-will-be-phlogiston/</guid><description>Well fuck, now [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] has competition for most wholesome ever. So short, and so tender, so full of power and beauty.</description></item><item><title>A Gentleman’s Position</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-gentlemans-position/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-gentlemans-position/</guid><description>It’s the favorite recurring KJ Charles theme: sometimes you just need a villain instead of a hero. See [[books/wanted a gentleman|Wanted, A Gentleman]] or [[books/the henchmen of zenda|Henchmen of Zenda]], et. al. My love language is elaborate schemes by crafty bastards, so you can guess how happy I was by the end.</description></item><item><title>The Price of Meat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</guid><description>Maybe don’t read this over lunch like I did? By which I mean, it’s fanfic of Sweeney Todd, it’s grisly horror, and it’s very good and effective, because KJ Charles. She can write anything from [[books/band sinister|Georgette Heyer homages]] to penny dreadfuls and it’s worth the ink.</description></item><item><title>Wanted, A Gentleman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</guid><description>She had me at “gothic novelist” and “lonely hearts columnist.” This is wonderful. I love it when Charles just unleashes her id.
Note: I’m including the epilogue Wanted, an Author, in which Corvin from [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] makes a cameo and Theo’s gay gothic erotica novel Jonathan: or The Struggles of Virtue is at the top of my list for books-within-a-book that I most need to read.</description></item><item><title>Unfit to Print</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unfit-to-print/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unfit-to-print/</guid><description>Print shop feels! Plus the Victorian porn trade! And yes to showing this side of British colonialism, even if that could stand to be fleshed out a bit.</description></item><item><title>The Duchess War</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duchess-war/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 22:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duchess-war/</guid><description>Finally I didn’t bounce off a Courtney Milan! Granted, the Norfolk Southern disaster had me in the mood to read about labor organizing, and that part worked for me better than the romance.
(In theory, I liked Minnie and Robert together, but they didn’t make me feel it, you know.</description></item><item><title>A Governess’s Guide to Passion and Peril</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-governesss-guide-to-passion-and-peril/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-governesss-guide-to-passion-and-peril/</guid><description>The fourth in a series, and I read at least one of the first three during the fugue state years when my dad’s health was failing, so I have only the haziest memory of it. That might mean I’m missing something, as it never felt explained in the text why the other women hadn’t come to Jane’s aid before now, nor why Jane’s feelings for Adrian would evolve beyond a schoolgirl crush.</description></item><item><title>How to Fall for a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/how-to-fall-for-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>A thief and a private investigator team up to solve a theft, and the vibes are basically a case-of-the-week tv episode (think Charlie’s Angels, Remington Steele, White Collar, etc) playing historical dress-up. The plot is as straightforward as it gets—they search for a macguffin, they get a clue, they get another clue, they solve the case.</description></item></channel></rss>