<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>complexity on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/complexity/</link><description>Recent content in complexity on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/complexity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thinking about symbiosis is itself a symbiotic phenomenon</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-about-symbiosis-is-itself-a-symbiotic-phenomenon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-about-symbiosis-is-itself-a-symbiotic-phenomenon/</guid><description>Just the complex process of thought—oxygen enters the bloodstream to be metabolized by mitochondria, etc.—means that thinking is itself a symbiotic event. (!!!)
Our brains themselves and the thought required to read this sentence, if my radical symbiogenesis theory is correct, were made possible by the protein microtubules that first evolved in bacteria.</description></item><item><title>Human behavior is too complex to be predictable</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/human-behavior-is-too-complex-to-be-predictable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/human-behavior-is-too-complex-to-be-predictable/</guid><description>Human behavior is too complex to be predictable, especially by ourselves, because we are oblivious to the detailed complexity of what’s happening within us.
When we say that human behavior is unpredictable, we are right, because it is too complex to be predicted, especially by ourselves.</description></item><item><title>Self-organizing systems of vast complexity are the way of the world</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-organizing-systems-of-vast-complexity-are-the-way-of-the-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-organizing-systems-of-vast-complexity-are-the-way-of-the-world/</guid><description>We get in trouble when we try to impose external, hierarchical order on ourselves—much like how monoculture fails to thrive, and instead entangled ecosystems are key.
If something as complex as a human body is a self-organizing system, could you not scale it up and infer that all of humanity is a self-organizing system as much as mycelia are?</description></item><item><title>The indigenous attribution of agency</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-attribution-of-agency/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-attribution-of-agency/</guid><description>In the indigenous worldview, vegetal life is granted agency and even personhood.
Each creature is directly responsible for the well-being of many beings at many times, but not for all beings at all times, and these “overlap[ping] connections” sustain a community united not by its identity to itself, but by its complex, mobile, and interrelated differentiations.</description></item></channel></rss>