<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>complexity on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/complexity/</link><description>Recent content in complexity on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/complexity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Human behavior is too complex to be predictable</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/human-behavior-is-too-complex-to-be-predictable/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/human-behavior-is-too-complex-to-be-predictable/</guid><description>Human behavior is too complex to be predictable, especially by ourselves, because we are oblivious to the detailed complexity of what’s happening within us.
When we say that human behavior is unpredictable, we are right, because it is too complex to be predicted, especially by ourselves.</description></item><item><title>No organization is organic</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/no-organization-is-organic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/no-organization-is-organic/</guid><description>No organization, in the political and commercial sense of the word, is organic. Organizations, in this sense, are based on the following of linear rules and laws imposed from above—that is, of strung-out, serial, one-thing-at-a-time sequences of words and signs which can never grasp the complexity of nature, although nature is only “complex” in relation to the impossible task of translating it into these linear signs.</description></item><item><title>Nothing is all good or all bad, even black and white thinking</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/nothing-is-all-good-or-all-bad-even-black-and-white-thinking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/nothing-is-all-good-or-all-bad-even-black-and-white-thinking/</guid><description>The idea that nothing is all good or all bad is, paradoxically, is also true for “black-and-white” thinking. Sometimes the straightforward, yes-or-no, this-or-that way is beneficial.
I like how [[authors/jessica dore|Jessica Dore]] puts it in [[books/tarot for change|Tarot for Change]], referring to the ace of swords:</description></item><item><title>Self-organizing systems of vast complexity are the way of the world</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-organizing-systems-of-vast-complexity-are-the-way-of-the-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/self-organizing-systems-of-vast-complexity-are-the-way-of-the-world/</guid><description>We get in trouble when we try to impose external, hierarchical order on ourselves—much like how monoculture fails to thrive, and instead entangled ecosystems are key.
If you think chaos is the only result of a non-hierarchal system, your own body disproves it. Try to get your mind to tell your lungs to breathe, your heart to beat, your stomach to digest, your skin to sweat, your colon to poop.</description></item><item><title>“Complexity” is sometimes noise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/complexity-is-sometimes-noise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/complexity-is-sometimes-noise/</guid><description>Note to self: as someone who always strives to grasp complexity and nuance, recognize when that can be used against me, especially when it comes to global politics. Sometimes sorting the signal from the noise really does mean swiftly cutting through the bullshit, not skillfully dissecting an elaborate tangle.</description></item><item><title>Thinking about symbiosis is itself a symbiotic phenomenon</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-about-symbiosis-is-itself-a-symbiotic-phenomenon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:39:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/thinking-about-symbiosis-is-itself-a-symbiotic-phenomenon/</guid><description>Just the complex process of thought—oxygen enters the bloodstream to be metabolized by mitochondria, etc.—means that thinking is itself a symbiotic event. (!!!)
Our brains themselves and the thought required to read this sentence, if my radical symbiogenesis theory is correct, were made possible by the protein microtubules that first evolved in bacteria.</description></item><item><title>The indigenous attribution of agency</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-attribution-of-agency/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-indigenous-attribution-of-agency/</guid><description>In the indigenous worldview, vegetal life is granted agency and even personhood.
Each creature is directly responsible for the well-being of many beings at many times, but not for all beings at all times, and these “overlap[ping] connections” sustain a community united not by its identity to itself, but by its complex, mobile, and interrelated differentiations.</description></item></channel></rss>