<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>narrative on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/narrative/</link><description>Recent content in narrative on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/narrative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anatomy of a propaganda blitz</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</guid><description>Copying this straight from [[books/propaganda blitz|Propaganda Blitz]] ([[authors/david edwards|David Edwards]] and [[authors/david cromwell|David Cromwell]]) because it’s immensely helpful to reference.
Propaganda blitzes are fast-moving attacks intended to inflict maximum damage in minimum time. They are:
based on allegations of dramatic new evidence communicated with high emotional intensity and moral outrage apparently supported by an informed corporate media/academic/expert consensus reinforced by damning condemnation of anyone daring even to question the apparent consensus often generated with fortuitous timing characterised by tragicomic moral dissonance Every one of these things, much less the concatenation of all of them, signals red flag, red flag, red flag.</description></item><item><title>Ideology cloaks power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ideology-cloaks-power/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ideology-cloaks-power/</guid><description>Superficially, the means by which power conceals itself is through stories. Its needs narratives — mainly about those who appear powerful — to create political and social dramas that distract us from thinking about deep power. But more fundamentally still, power depends on ideology. Ideology cloaks power – in a real sense, it is power — because it is the source of power’s invisibility.</description></item><item><title>Power exists only so long as we consent</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-exists-only-so-long-as-we-consent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:48:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-exists-only-so-long-as-we-consent/</guid><description>Power is the structure of the thoughts we think we control, a framework for the ideologies we think we voted for, the values we think we choose to treasure, the horizon of imaginations we think we created. Power exists only so long as we consent to it through our blind obedience.</description></item><item><title>Any human power can be changed by human beings</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/any-human-power-can-be-changed-by-human-beings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/any-human-power-can-be-changed-by-human-beings/</guid><description> We live in capitalism. Its power seems inescapable. So did the divine right of kings.
Any human power can be resisted and changed by human beings. —[[authors/ursula k le guin|Ursula K. Le Guin]], National Book Awards Speech
see also: [[notes/the only thing keeping a crown on a king’s head is narrative|the only thing keeping a crown on a king’s head is narrative]], and [[notes/since it’s all narrative, anything is possible|since it’s all narrative, anything is possible]] see also: [[notes/we are making ourselves up as we go|we are making ourselves up as we go]] future: link to how we stay blind to the story of power</description></item><item><title>Mute the narrative soundtrack for global politics</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mute-the-narrative-soundtrack-for-global-politics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:24:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mute-the-narrative-soundtrack-for-global-politics/</guid><description>Much like mindfulness helps cut through the internal noise, muting the narrative helps cut through the external noise.
Learn the art of perceiving life without the perceptual filter of narrative. Mentally “mute” the narrative soundtrack and watch where all the resources are going, where the weapons are moving to and coming from, who’s being killed and imprisoned etc, to get a clear picture of what’s going on in the world.</description></item><item><title>“Complexity” is sometimes noise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/complexity-is-sometimes-noise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/complexity-is-sometimes-noise/</guid><description>Note to self: as someone who always strives to grasp complexity and nuance, recognize when that can be used against me, especially when it comes to global politics. Sometimes sorting the signal from the noise really does mean swiftly cutting through the bullshit, not skillfully dissecting an elaborate tangle.</description></item><item><title>We are making ourselves up as we go</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-making-ourselves-up-as-we-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:01:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-making-ourselves-up-as-we-go/</guid><description>The current cultural orthodoxy, often formulated or short-handed as “stay in your lane,” postulates that a writer ought to remain centered in their own community, to write from their own and their community’s experience: to stay home. But Ursula argued that those places, those points of origin, home and community, are themselves acts of the creative imagination.</description></item><item><title>Everything is fiction</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/everything-is-fiction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/everything-is-fiction/</guid><description>Lest we get so attached to our stories we can’t surrender them, remember: what we experience and the way we describe it is fiction. We are constantly editing, tweaking, cutting, rewriting our vast, chaotic narrative.
And I mean that—everything is fiction. When you tell yourself the story of your life, the story of your day, you edit and rewrite and weave a narrative out of a collection of random experiences and events.</description></item><item><title>Healthy stories are fluid, not fixed</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/healthy-stories-are-fluid-not-fixed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/healthy-stories-are-fluid-not-fixed/</guid><description>We often forget that our storytelling is rooted in millennia of oral tradition. Collaborative, mutable, fluid, living narratives that changed to suit different ecosystems and social scenarios.
Written tales are more “permanent,” but they have a harder time evolving. So we’ve traded (a false sense of) permanence for the complex and evolving (and communal) narrative lifeforms.</description></item><item><title>AI exposes the hierarchy of intelligence</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ai-exposes-the-hierarchy-of-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ai-exposes-the-hierarchy-of-intelligence/</guid><description>These were back to back in my feed: Mandy Brown on the smokescreen of AI and our narratives (it’s masking the real story; we need to re-think our hierarchy of intelligence), then Austin Kleon on AI as intern (appeasing our need to be the superior intelligence?</description></item><item><title>Power doesn’t need facts or evidence, just narrative and ideology</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-doesnt-need-facts-or-evidence-just-narrative-and-ideology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/power-doesnt-need-facts-or-evidence-just-narrative-and-ideology/</guid><description>Power doesn’t need facts or evidence, even when its claims are self-evidently disruptive to the democratic process. It exists chiefly in the realm of narrative and ideology. This is a story, just like Corbyn’s “antisemitism crisis”, that is made true simply through repetition.
Because power is power, its narratives can defy the most elementary rules of logic.</description></item><item><title>Since it’s all narrative, anything is possible</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/since-its-all-narrative-anything-is-possible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/since-its-all-narrative-anything-is-possible/</guid><description>Because here’s the thing: since it’s all narrative, anything is possible. Those who see this have the ability to plunge toward health and human thriving without any regard for the made-up reasons why such a thing is impossible, and plant seeds of light which sprout in unprecedented directions that never could have been predicted by someone plugged into to establishment how-it-is stories.</description></item><item><title>The only thing keeping a crown on a king’s head is narrative</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-only-thing-keeping-a-crown-on-a-kings-head-is-narrative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-only-thing-keeping-a-crown-on-a-kings-head-is-narrative/</guid><description>This is why there have been book burnings, heretic burnings, and executions for mocking the emperor throughout history: ==ideas which differ from the dominant narratives about what power is, how money works, who should be in charge and so on are threatening to a ruler’s power in the exact same way that an assassin’s dagger is.</description></item></channel></rss>