<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>narrative on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/narrative/</link><description>Recent content in narrative on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/narrative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anatomy of a propaganda blitz</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/anatomy-of-a-propaganda-blitz/</guid><description>Copying this straight from [[books/propaganda blitz|Propaganda Blitz]] ([[authors/david edwards|David Edwards]] and [[authors/david cromwell|David Cromwell]]) because it’s immensely helpful to reference.
Propaganda blitzes are fast-moving attacks intended to inflict maximum damage in minimum time. They are:
based on allegations of dramatic new evidence communicated with high emotional intensity and moral outrage apparently supported by an informed corporate media/academic/expert consensus reinforced by damning condemnation of anyone daring even to question the apparent consensus often generated with fortuitous timing characterised by tragicomic moral dissonance Every one of these things, much less the concatenation of all of them, signals red flag, red flag, red flag.</description></item><item><title>Mute the narrative soundtrack for global politics</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mute-the-narrative-soundtrack-for-global-politics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/mute-the-narrative-soundtrack-for-global-politics/</guid><description>Much like mindfulness helps cut through the internal noise, muting the narrative helps cut through the external noise.
Learn the art of perceiving life without the perceptual filter of narrative. Mentally “mute” the narrative soundtrack and watch where all the resources are going, where the weapons are moving to and coming from, who’s being killed and imprisoned etc, to get a clear picture of what’s going on in the world.</description></item><item><title>“Complexity” is sometimes noise</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/complexity-is-sometimes-noise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/complexity-is-sometimes-noise/</guid><description>Note to self: as someone who always strives to grasp complexity and nuance, recognize when that can be used against me, especially when it comes to global politics. Sometimes sorting the signal from the noise really does mean swiftly cutting through the bullshit, not skillfully dissecting an elaborate tangle.</description></item><item><title>We are making ourselves up as we go</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-making-ourselves-up-as-we-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:01:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/we-are-making-ourselves-up-as-we-go/</guid><description>The current cultural orthodoxy, often formulated or short-handed as “stay in your lane,” postulates that a writer ought to remain centered in their own community, to write from their own and their community’s experience: to stay home. But Ursula argued that those places, those points of origin, home and community, are themselves acts of the creative imagination.</description></item><item><title>Everything is fiction</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/everything-is-fiction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/everything-is-fiction/</guid><description>Lest we get so attached to our stories we can’t surrender them, remember: what we experience and the way we describe it is fiction. We are constantly editing, tweaking, cutting, rewriting our vast, chaotic narrative.
And I mean that—everything is fiction. When you tell yourself the story of your life, the story of your day, you edit and rewrite and weave a narrative out of a collection of random experiences and events.</description></item><item><title>Healthy stories are fluid, not fixed</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/healthy-stories-are-fluid-not-fixed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/healthy-stories-are-fluid-not-fixed/</guid><description>We often forget that our storytelling is rooted in millennia of oral tradition. Collaborative, mutable, fluid, living narratives that changed to suit different ecosystems and social scenarios.
Written tales are more “permanent,” but they have a harder time evolving. So we’ve traded (a false sense of) permanence for the complex and evolving (and communal) narrative lifeforms.</description></item><item><title>AI exposes the hierarchy of intelligence</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ai-exposes-the-hierarchy-of-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/ai-exposes-the-hierarchy-of-intelligence/</guid><description>These were back to back in my feed: Mandy Brown on the smokescreen of AI and our narratives (it’s masking the real story; we need to re-think our hierarchy of intelligence), then Austin Kleon on AI as intern (appeasing our need to be the superior intelligence?</description></item></channel></rss>