<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ace-spectrum on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/ace-spectrum/</link><description>Recent content in ace-spectrum on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/ace-spectrum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Rat-Catcher’s Daughter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</guid><description>Very sweet and dare I say necessary before [[books/gilded cage|Gilded Cage]]. It has some pretty key context. And come on—that title.</description></item><item><title>Something Fabulous</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-fabulous/</guid><description>So far the theme of the year is romances that I read and then re-read right away and install on my best-of-year list (best-of-ever list too, in the case of Something Fabulous, which more than lives up to its name).
A few notes:
We’re starting to see the books written during the pandemic where authors are writing what they WANT, not what they SHOULD.</description></item><item><title>Something Spectacular</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-spectacular/</guid><description>You couldn’t write your own story in the margins of someone else’s.
I want to write something long and complex about the concept of family in this book (the Tarletons enfolding Valentine and Sir Horley and Periwinkle and practically every other stray into their own little world; the stitched-together warmth of the Delanceys’ parenting, wrapped around Peggy like a quilt; that spectacular ending of creating a new family when convention says it’s impossible).</description></item><item><title>Something Extraordinary</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/something-extraordinary/</guid><description>The high-strung Belle has left behind her heroine era, and the drama-prone Rufus has left behind his Sir Horley Comewithers era. Together they embark on the worst elopement kidnapping elopement in history (per Belle, it’s not vainglorious to claim that when it’s true), and what ensues is a meditation on friendship, love, sexuality, identity, self-discovery, society, and home in a way that only Alexis Hall can do it.</description></item><item><title>Kiss Her Once for Me</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/kiss-her-once-for-me/</guid><description>Tried this one again, hoping I had one more festive read in me for the year, but there are just sooo many things that bug me right away. It’s gonna be one of those books where shitty systemic poverty gets magically fixed for one [pretty young white] woman by the power of romance with a [manipulative gaslighting] millionaire, isn’t it?</description></item></channel></rss>