<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>therapy on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/therapy/</link><description>Recent content in therapy on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/tags/therapy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Abuse is best recognized by the effect it has on the abused</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-is-best-recognized-by-the-effect-it-has-on-the-abused/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/abuse-is-best-recognized-by-the-effect-it-has-on-the-abused/</guid><description>I’m just going to paraphrase and quote this whole bit from [[books/the dominance playbook|The Dominance Playbook]] by [[authors/anton fulmen|Anton Fulmen]], because HOW this this not foundational knowledge:
While there are people out there with malicious intentions, abuse can often happen when there’s no intent to harm.</description></item><item><title>All relationships involve power</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-relationships-involve-power/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/all-relationships-involve-power/</guid><description>Every relationship involves a power exchange, and learning the dynamics of power exchanges can be key to navigating relationships in general—and I’d argue life in general. It gets a hell of a lot easier to spot abuse and control.
Just as all power relationships are relationships, all relationships also involve power.</description></item><item><title>Could kinesiology explain the phenomenon of faith healing?</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/could-kinesiology-explain-the-phenomenon-of-faith-healing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:29:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/could-kinesiology-explain-the-phenomenon-of-faith-healing/</guid><description>Can kinesiology—specifically the therapeutic practices of body talk, acupressure, emotional stress release, etc.—explain what’s occurring in many instances of faith healing?
In the Pentecostal tradition that I grew up in (and escaped from), faith healing often happens in a highly charged environment, with lots of prayer (meditation), and emotional catharsis.</description></item><item><title>The trust checklist</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-trust-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/the-trust-checklist/</guid><description>Trust is more of a cognitive assessment than an emotion. Distrust is when you feel “what is important to me is not safe with this person.” That lack of safety makes authenticity and vulnerability difficult for fear of betrayal (rightly so!).
In [[books/atlas of the heart|Atlas of the Heart]], [[authors/brené brown|Brené Brown]] lists seven specific trustworthy behaviors:</description></item><item><title>Emotional identification</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotional-identification/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/notes/emotional-identification/</guid><description>Broadly speaking, we experience three different kinds of emotions in our brains: reactive, routine, and reflective emotions.
Reactive emotions are primitive, hardwired, and innate emotions, such as fear and defensive rage, produced in response to a perceived threat. They energize us for fight-and-flight and live in our limbic system.</description></item></channel></rss>