<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KJ Charles on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/authors/kj-charles/</link><description>Recent content in KJ Charles on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/authors/kj-charles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Thief in the Night</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-thief-in-the-night/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-thief-in-the-night/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Proper English</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 22:43:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/proper-english/</guid><description>It’s the House Party from Hell, and the first time I read it, I was like this is exhausting, it’s claustrophobic, not sure I can vibe with it—but then I read it again in 2020 and YES. It is a MOOD.</description></item><item><title>The Secret Lives of Country Gentlemen</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-secret-lives-of-country-gentlemen/</guid><description>Update: Yep. [[books/a noblemans guide to seducing a scoundrel|Second book]] delivers the very necessary half of the whole. I adored it, and now I adore this one on re-read. Everything that just felt a slight step off pace the first time was solved with a deeper, closer read, and the addition of Luke’s story.</description></item><item><title>The Rat-Catcher’s Daughter</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-rat-catchers-daughter/</guid><description>Very sweet and dare I say necessary before [[books/gilded cage|Gilded Cage]]. It has some pretty key context. And come on—that title.</description></item><item><title>The Ruin of Gabriel Ashleigh</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ruin-of-gabriel-ashleigh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-ruin-of-gabriel-ashleigh/</guid><description>Why yes, I’m re-reading the whole series in order, even the miscellany. Probably my least favorite of the lot, but only due to how much I like the others. I still endorse it completely, because if you’re gonna play cards, play them for keeps.</description></item><item><title>Slippery Creatures</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/slippery-creatures/</guid><description>After the recent spate of lackluster histroms that were trying to do various spy and mystery related things, I was pining for Will Darling. Enter Chirp audiobooks with a well-timed deal on the series bundle, and before you could say Lord Arthur Aloysius Kimberly de Brabazon Secretan, I had the dulcet tones of Cornell Collins narrating my favorite KJ Charles competence porn.</description></item><item><title>The Gentle Art of Fortune Hunting</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-gentle-art-of-fortune-hunting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 22:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-gentle-art-of-fortune-hunting/</guid><description>So sweet! Will read again, because I felt I read it too quickly. (And kind of wanted way more of the roleplay/pretext stuff&amp;hellip;.)</description></item><item><title>Think of England</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/think-of-england/</guid><description>This is pulp with all the trappings—daring spies, dastardly villains, plots galore—and yet it’s so grounded in real emotion it hardly feels like pulp at all. Except for the part that’s so entertaining I devoured it in two days.
Great book. Great pairing. KJ Charles does it again.</description></item><item><title>Any Old Diamonds</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/any-old-diamonds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/any-old-diamonds/</guid><description>As KJC says: In which we stick it to a duke.
What [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] was to 2018, Any Old Diamonds is to 2019. It’s SO good. An instant favorite. I might have to re-read both to decide which one I like best, and if it’s too close to call, which only means I should read them a third and fourth time, I won’t mind a bit.</description></item><item><title>The Sugared Game</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/sugared-game/</guid><description>The reason it takes me a week to read a book that I literally can’t put down is because I read it twice.
When I read [[books/slippery creatures|Slippery Creatures]], I wanted to say, this is what it looks like when an author levels up. I refrained, but I’m not going to wait til book three to say it: this is what it looks like when an author levels up.</description></item><item><title>A Nobleman’s Guide to Seducing a Scoundrel</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-noblemans-guide-to-seducing-a-scoundrel/</guid><description>So I somehow didn’t even realize my preorder of the paperback arrived two weeks early (!!!), meaning I’ve already read this twice by the time I got the “book release day!” email this morning.
Oops.
Except not oops, because I needed the last two weeks with this book.</description></item><item><title>A Fashionable Indulgence</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-fashionable-indulgence/</guid><description>Ditto [[books/a seditious affair|A Seditious Affair]]: first read this years ago; out of order then in order; its politics are even more relevant now. There is a refreshing lack of drama between Harry and Julius—their conflict is external—and I greatly appreciate a romance with the guts to do that.</description></item><item><title>The Duke at Hazard</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-duke-at-hazard/</guid><description>I have a few auto-buy (auto-preorder) authors, but KJ Charles is the only one where I drop everything to start reading the day a new book comes out. Here, that impatience is rewarded with a tender, slow-blooming romance-on-the-run between Daizell, a disgraced non-scoundrel scoundrel (he’s paying for the sins of his father), and Cassian, aka The Duke, aka Vernon Fortescue Cassian George de Vere Crosse, the fourth Duke of Severn, the Earl of Harmsford, Baron Crosse of Wotton, and Baron Vere, who’s incognito for a month to hunt down a thief and win a wager (he’s burdened with the premature inheritance of his father’s title).</description></item><item><title>Subtle Blood</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/subtle-blood/</guid><description>I might have accidentally read Subtle Blood again, since I might have accidentally experienced a vivid dream of Will, Kim, Phoebe, and Maisie on a Parisian adventure (cameo by Teddy Molyneaux, of course), and upon waking, might have accidentally been distraught that that book wasn’t going to exist.</description></item><item><title>Gilded Cage</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gilded-cage/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/gilded-cage/</guid><description>Yes, this is Susan Lazarus from [[series/sins of the cities|Sins of the Cities]]. I love a prickly, ruthless heroine. I love jewel thieves and morality that is questionable at best. I love all that the most. This one didn’t quite click all the way with me despite all of the above, so I will be revisiting to see what I missed.</description></item><item><title>A Seditious Affair</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-seditious-affair/</guid><description>This was my first KJ Charles, purchased and read—I just looked it up—March 2017. I then read the whole series (out of order, of course), re-read this one in 2018, again in 2019, and somehow reviewed nary a one before 2020.
I feel so sentimental.</description></item><item><title>A Gentleman’s Position</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-gentlemans-position/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/a-gentlemans-position/</guid><description>It’s the favorite recurring KJ Charles theme: sometimes you just need a villain instead of a hero. See [[books/wanted a gentleman|Wanted, A Gentleman]] or [[books/the henchmen of zenda|Henchmen of Zenda]], et. al. My love language is elaborate schemes by crafty bastards, so you can guess how happy I was by the end.</description></item><item><title>The Henchmen of Zenda</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-henchmen-of-zenda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-henchmen-of-zenda/</guid><description>When KJ Charles is on, she’s on. This book is all the things: fun, ridiculous, hilarious, swashbuckling, hot, FUN. The high pulp style suits her so well because she can pack the book full of joy and all the sneering and sniding she likes to write works because it’s comic and joyful.</description></item><item><title>The Price of Meat</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/the-price-of-meat/</guid><description>Maybe don’t read this over lunch like I did? By which I mean, it’s fanfic of Sweeney Todd, it’s grisly horror, and it’s very good and effective, because KJ Charles. She can write anything from [[books/band sinister|Georgette Heyer homages]] to penny dreadfuls and it’s worth the ink.</description></item><item><title>Wanted, A Gentleman</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wanted-a-gentleman/</guid><description>She had me at “gothic novelist” and “lonely hearts columnist.” This is wonderful. I love it when Charles just unleashes her id.
Note: I’m including the epilogue Wanted, an Author, in which Corvin from [[books/band sinister|Band Sinister]] makes a cameo and Theo’s gay gothic erotica novel Jonathan: or The Struggles of Virtue is at the top of my list for books-within-a-book that I most need to read.</description></item><item><title>Band Sinister</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/band-sinister/</guid><description>If this isn’t everything that’s wholesome and good in the world, I don’t know what is. A tribute to Heyer indeed; it just includes those who paint with oils outside conventional lines. It cranked my heart open without being saccharine or heavy. One of those books where I have to be careful what I read next because it might not measure up.</description></item><item><title>Unfit to Print</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unfit-to-print/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 15:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/unfit-to-print/</guid><description>Print shop feels! Plus the Victorian porn trade! And yes to showing this side of British colonialism, even if that could stand to be fleshed out a bit.</description></item></channel></rss>