<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>therapeutic on</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/therapeutic/</link><description>Recent content in therapeutic on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notebook.jamieharris.co/shelves/therapeutic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rosaline Palmer Takes the Cake</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rosaline-palmer-takes-the-cake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/rosaline-palmer-takes-the-cake/</guid><description>I laughed. I cried. I have a therapist now. How many books can do that, AND homage the hell out of the Great British Bake Off?
Rosaline Palmer does take the cake.</description></item><item><title>Paris Daillencourt is About to Crumble</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 21:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/paris-daillencourt-is-about-to-crumble/</guid><description>Once again Alexis Hall takes away the book I thought I wanted and replaces it with the book I actually need.
Reading this at the same time as [[books/the body keeps the score|The Body Keeps the Score]], though, just means I’m peeking between the lines of all the parental neglect and trauma and thinking, dearest Paris, get thee to some somatic therapy, medication is just a start.</description></item><item><title>Tarot for Change</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tarot-for-change/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 22:26:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/tarot-for-change/</guid><description>I’d prefer a bit less Joseph Campbell and Cognitive Behavioral Therapy,1 but overall, the best book on tarot I’ve encountered so far. Or, rather than a definitive superlative, it’s the book that most resonates with me so far. It’s how I engage with tarot, not for divination, but therapeutically, creatively, narratively, for introspection and storytelling.</description></item><item><title>Come Out, Come Out</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:35:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/come-out-come-out/</guid><description>In the same niche as [[books/camp damascus|Camp Damascus]], the conversion-therapy-as-horror genre. Similarities abound, even down to the senior class quarry jumps, which doesn’t indicate any co-opting of plot points but simply how ubiquitous this experience is, the same script across rural America, where any deviation from the script means there will be Consequences.</description></item><item><title>Untypical</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/untypical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/untypical/</guid><description>Part memoir of a late-diagnosed autistic person (straight white British male version); part comprehensive outline of accommodations that would make the world a safer, more autistic-friendly place. Some are so laughably trivial that it’s shameful they even have to be requested in the first place—but alas, that’s the world we live in.</description></item><item><title>Wintering</title><link>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 13:53:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://notebook.jamieharris.co/books/wintering/</guid><description>DNF due to the health scare(s) both May and her husband experience at the beginning of the book. Even though I knew they were okay, it was too much to relive in the moment, my own recent family health scares too fresh. I skimmed ahead to see if I could just skip that part, but multiple other chapters failed to grab me.</description></item></channel></rss>